<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A fashion, culture, art and music publication, written by students about students.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 18:43:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/cropped-12773305_10206631248554054_481252708_o.jpg?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107671177</site>	<item>
		<title>SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part IV</title>
		<link>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv</link>
					<comments>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 17:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Farewell Issue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Posts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rebecca, Founder, Creative Director and our Queen The day has finally come, SUBCULTURED is coming to an end. Whether it’s a temporary hiatus or something permanent (only time will tell), I felt like it was time to move on. With everything that has happened this year, I could not foresee us trying to recruit a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part IV</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Rebecca, Founder, Creative Director and our Queen</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4354" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-1/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4354" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>The day has finally come, SUBCULTURED is coming to an end. Whether it’s a temporary hiatus or something permanent (only time will tell), I felt like it was time to move on. With everything that has happened this year, I could not foresee us trying to recruit a new team of staff amidst COVID-19, to replace those who have graduated. But it has been an incredible journey.</p>



<p>It all started in 2015 with a strong, gut feeling that wouldn’t go away, causing me to send an email to the student body about this idea that would quite frankly, change my life! Hundreds of responses to my email and subsequently calls, meetings and discussions led to our website launch and first issue in Semester 2 of 2016. Little did I know when I sent that email how much SUBCULTURED would impact my life and all those involved. It was a key factor in obtaining my placement year, the subject of university assignments, a source of like-minded people and so much more! To this day, I have still referenced it in post-grad interviews and it has been a vessel to get me where I am today. And it has done the same for many others as well. I have also learnt sooo much about entrepreneurship, work-life balance, people management, and pretty much every single creative skill going <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f602.png" alt="😂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I’m not going to lie though, there were both ups and downs (as is everything in life) to running the magazine, but it has made me who I am today and I wouldn’t change it for the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I cannot reference just one specific memory, but between the years of 2015 and 2018, where I was most involved, was a key time in the magazine, which included our website launch and party in 2016, the University of Surrey hoodies shoot (one of my favourite photo-shoots to date), doing our first print issue in 2018 and the Black Students of British Institutions feature.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to give a huge shout out to the rest of the team, as without them none of this would have been possible. Thank you to Alice, who has supported myself and the magazine from the very start, partner in crime and a true OG. Thank you to Juliey, for being the force behind our digital presence, thank you to Natalie for coordinating our lit photo-shoots, thank you to Alim for standing in as President of the society after I graduated, thank you to Roshni for shooting some sick street style, thank you to Eve for commissioning articles and putting together a lit final issue and thank you to Daisy for coordinating our last round of content. And thank you to the rest of the current team &#8211; Niki, Amy and Clarise. Some other staff that have since left the magazine but were heavily involved in the launch are Katherine, Zehra, Setareh, Dagmar and Elpida &#8211; thank you! And most of all, thank you to our readers and contributors.</p>



<p>I started off as Editor-in-Chief and Creative Director, being involved in all areas of the magazine, but more recently specialised in the Creative Direction side, leading me to work as a Graphic Designer after graduating. Much self-discovery then led me to Front-End Development within the fashion, media and lifestyle space and I will be starting a new role as a Junior Front-End Developer this month. I am so excited to move on to the next phase of my life but I will miss running this wonderful enterprise.</p>



<p><strong>To conclude, I have created and designed a brand new website for The Farewell Issue, which summarises our best content from the last few years. Check it out at: </strong><a href="http://www.farewell.subculturedmag.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">http://www.farewell.subculturedmag.com/</span></strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>



<p>Follow Rebecca: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/beccacofie/?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">@beccacofie</span></a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/rebeccacofiedesign/?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">@rebeccacofiedesign</span></a></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part IV</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4406</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part III</title>
		<link>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii</link>
					<comments>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 17:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Farewell Issue]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Alice, Managing Director and OG SUBCULTURED Member It wouldn’t be an exaggeration to say that my uni life really started when I got into SUBCULTURED. I loved doing things alongside my degree and I loved meeting like-minded people. Just knowing that there was a creative outlet for me helped me through stressful times and offered [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part III</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Alice, Managing Director and OG SUBCULTURED Member</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4359" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-9/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-9" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4359" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>It wouldn’t be an exaggeration to say that my uni life really started when I got into SUBCULTURED. I loved doing things alongside my degree and I loved meeting like-minded people. Just knowing that there was a creative outlet for me helped me through stressful times and offered me a chance to keep being creative.</p>



<p>When I got Rebecca’s email about the magazine she wanted to start and went to the first session she organised, I was amazed by the energy in the room and all the incredible people I talked to. But it wasn’t until later that I actually got to know Rebecca – it was while she was preparing to make a speech in front of a packed AGM to convince them to grant us society status. Our connection was instant. After spending a few hours with her, I was energised and ready to help with anything.</p>



<p>That was exactly what I did – and it turned out a lot of help was needed, because the task before us was overwhelming and there was no manual for all the unexpected issues that came up. Assembling the team, designing the logo and the website, commissioning content, working for our website to go live… There were so many meetings in the Surrey library with all of us involved, trying hard to work things out as we went along! So so SO many messages and calls between Rebecca and me. Eventually I became Managing Director, which meant I continued to be heavily involved with running the magazine, managing the team, supervising content, recruiting amazing new people, and making sure the projects we had planned came to fruition. I have shared many incredible moments with our talented team and our contributors and have had such an amazing relationship with Rebecca, who has been to me not only a partner in creativity, but also a friend. We have been there for each other and for the team during the ups and downs of the magazine, of university life, of life after graduation, of life during corona.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, even though the time is right for Rebecca and me to move on with our professional lives, I am going to miss the buzz of getting ready for another round of content, of setting up exciting projects. I certainly will miss the team and the creators that have supported us for these past five years. I have been lucky to be part of a truly diverse team, committed to promoting our mission; we wanted to create content that showcased the student community in all its diversity, to champion sustainability, to talk about youth culture and explore fashion through the lens of self-love. So that is one of the main things I am taking away from SUBCULTURED, which was a working environment that allowed me to thrive: I want to be surrounded by unique, different people all the time, especially at work! SUBCULTURED has set the bar high for any professional environment I find myself working in.</p>



<p>Lastly, a huge thank you to our audience and the Surrey community. I have loved being a member of it and I can only hope that we made university life for you even a bit fun – hopefully as fun as it was for us behind the scenes!</p>



<p><strong>Stay tuned for Part IV (Final Part)!</strong><em><br><strong>From SUBCULTURED Team</strong></em></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part III</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4401</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part II</title>
		<link>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii</link>
					<comments>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 17:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Farewell Issue]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Roshni, Street Style Director and Professional Fashionista Hi, I’m Roshni and I was the Street Style Director for SUBCULTURED. I joined last year, around this time. From the beginning of uni, I had a deep desire to be part of a community interested in fashion and youth culture, which is why I joined the magazine. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part II</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Roshni, Street Style Director and Professional Fashionista</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4355" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4355" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>Hi, I’m Roshni and I was the Street Style Director for SUBCULTURED. I joined last year, around this time.</p>



<p>From the beginning of uni, I had a deep desire to be part of a community interested in fashion and youth culture, which is why I joined the magazine. Prior to the pandemic, I was photographing street style around campus, jotting down outfit details and doing post-production on photos before sending them off to be published. I had a little dabble in some social media stuff as well, which I loved!</p>



<p>I was sadly not a part of the SUBCULTURED team for long and so my favourite memory sounds quite mundane I suppose. Despite my social anxiety, I loved communicating and being surrounded (whether that was physically or digitally) by a cohort of people working together for a common interest and passion. What I definitely gained out of the whole experience was being able to be part of a community that I had been seeking for so long!</p>



<p>I just graduated from Surrey and I will now be doing my MA in Strategic Fashion Marketing at London College of Fashion at UAL in October! As I am currently involved in a fashion mentoring programme, I am reading a lot of fashion books and watching a ton of fashion documentaries!</p>



<p>What we are going through is certainly unprecedented, but the youth of today are part of a revolutionary time. Lockdown became a time in which all of us were forced to confront issues of race and power. I would like to use my final words in this space to say a little something, because SUBCULTURED was created by the youth of today for the youth of today:&nbsp; we must all do the best we can to educate ourselves, to fight for a fair and just future, not just for ourselves but for all.</p>



<p>Finally, I cannot thank Rebecca enough for creating and maintaining this amazing community within UoS. SUBCULTURED gave the students of Surrey a forum in which to express their creative self. It brought a whole array of people together, allowing us to be a part of something meaningful, memorable and personal.</p>



<p><strong>Daisy, Editorial Director and Outstanding Staff Writer</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4357" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-6/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-6" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4357" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>I have only been involved with SUBCULTURED for the past year, but its value to me has been immeasurable. As a keen writer, SUBCULTURED gave me the creative outlet I had been seeking, serving as a platform for my thoughts and feelings. More importantly, it gave me a community of creatives I didn’t know I was looking for, people who worked tirelessly and selflessly to keep the magazine running despite their own individual commitments. The amazing team generously trusted me with content and editorial responsibilities which have given me insight into a world that I hope to be part of one day as a professional. SUBCULTURED is more than a magazine, it’s a passion project; it’s Rebecca’s baby and I want to personally thank her for lovingly creating it and sharing it with us. Saying goodbye to this experience is really hard, which is why I am hoping this is not goodbye forever, just for now.</p>



<p>For the time being, I will keep writing and creating, finding my way through this strange time governed by face masks and hand sanitizer. Keep safe everyone!</p>



<p><strong>Stay tuned for Part III!</strong><em><br><strong>From SUBCULTURED Team</strong></em></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part II</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4399</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SUBCULTURED Editors’ Letters: Part I</title>
		<link>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-i/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=subcultured-editors-letters-part-i</link>
					<comments>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-i/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 17:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Farewell Issue]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Juliéy, Digital Director, Social Media Maverick, and Incredible Content Creator Hey there, I’m Juliéy, Social Media &#38; Digital Director at SUBCULTURED. I manage all digital marketing activities in the magazine, on the website and on social media. It’s been a wild ride with SUBCULTURED! I started out doing marketing for the magazine when it was [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-i/">SUBCULTURED Editors’ Letters: Part I</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Juliéy, Digital Director, Social Media Maverick, and Incredible Content Creator</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4356" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-3/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4356" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>Hey there, I’m Juliéy, Social Media &amp; Digital Director at SUBCULTURED. I manage all digital marketing activities in the magazine, on the website and on social media.</p>



<p>It’s been a wild ride with SUBCULTURED! I started out doing marketing for the magazine when it was founded in Surrey 5 years ago, and just worked my way up to be a Director (sort of proud to say that Rebecca, Alice and I are the only 3 members who were there from the very beginning and are still here today).</p>



<p>One of my best memories at SUBCULTURED is definitely when we released our first print publication, ‘THE STUDENT ISSUE’. I remember vividly that moment when we were waiting in the Union House for the magazine delivery and got way too excited and screamed at the top of our lungs when the print copies finally arrived. For us, as creators, to be able to physically witness our hard work after all those months, and to see that it was so highly anticipated and that it was received so well by Surrey students was the best feeling ever.</p>



<p>I’m now working full-time as a digital marketer and have been working from home since lockdown. Lockdown was daunting at first, but I’ve really enjoyed being in my own vibe and hanging out with my housemates. I think the key to staying sane during this pandemic is to really focus on yourself, by self-pampering, eating healthy and exercising. Also stay positive- nothing can help you get through tough times more than a positive attitude. And, in case you miss us, always feel free to check us out on the SUBCULTURED website, where you can also find links to our online issues!</p>



<p>For more by Juliéy: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/julieythe1st/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">@julieythe1st</span></a> on Facebook and Instagram</p>



<p><strong>Natalie, Photography Director and Blogger Extraordinaire</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4351" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-8/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-8" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4351" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>I joined SUBCULTURED as a Creative Assistant back in 2017 when I was in my second year of Uni. I helped plan, style and direct photoshoots, which led to me becoming Photography Director and undertaking the creative direction of photoshoots.</p>



<p>I love how our shoots brought different people together and I had so much fun meeting everyone. I also wrote some articles for the SUBCULTURED website and got to explore some really interesting topics, such as unrealistic beauty standards. It was great to have people edit my work and help me improve. SUBCULTURED was a brilliant creative outlet for myself and many others and it gave me so many skills both personally and professionally; it gave me experience of managing a team and helped me gain confidence through interacting with new people and speaking at AGMs. Ultimately,<em> </em>SUBCULTURED allowed me to feel part of something which helped me during times when I felt isolated at uni. Being part of<em> </em>SUBCULTURED was one of the highlights of being at Surrey for me, and I will cherish the memories for the rest of my life. Thank you, Rebecca, and thank you to the rest of the SUBCULTURED team.</p>



<p>For more by Natalie:&nbsp; <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.ncarterofficial.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.ncarterofficial.com/</a></span> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/nat_carts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">@nat_carts</span></a>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Eve, Former Editorial Director and Content Queen</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4372" data-permalink="/?attachment_id=4372" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-10" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4372" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>I joined SUBCULTURED in my first year, writing articles whenever I could. I loved being part of such a cool and talented team and in my final year I had the opportunity to become Editorial Director for the magazine. In this role, I had the responsibility of commissioning content and learned about maximising the magazine’s reach through tailored, relevant content. The Valentine’s Week feature and our latest issue are some of my favourite pieces. I have so much respect and love for Rebecca and Alice who have made SUBCULTURED what it is and it will be sorely missed!</p>



<p><strong>STAY TUNED FOR PART II!<br><em>From SUBCULTURED Team</em></strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-i/">SUBCULTURED Editors’ Letters: Part I</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-i/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4382</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Social Dilemma Review &#8211; “The Greatest Existential Threat Of Our Time?”</title>
		<link>/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time</link>
					<comments>/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 17:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Social media &#8211; the biggest existential threat that we&#8217;ve ever faced? SUBCULTURED takes a look at the latest Netflix film kicking up some dirt on Silicon Valley&#8217;s biggest tech companies. The Social Dilemma, which arrived on Netflix earlier this month, is an exposing docu-drama from Jeff Orlowski, with help from a vast club of co-founders [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/">The Social Dilemma Review &#8211; “The Greatest Existential Threat Of Our Time?”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Social media &#8211; the biggest existential threat that we&#8217;ve ever faced? SUBCULTURED takes a look at the latest Netflix film kicking up some dirt on Silicon Valley&#8217;s biggest tech companies.</strong></p>



<p><em>The Social Dilemma</em>, which arrived on Netflix earlier this month, is an exposing docu-drama from Jeff Orlowski, with help from a vast club of co-founders and designers who have now left some of the most influential social media companies in the world. The title nods to the popular 2010 film &#8216;<em>The Social Network</em>&#8216;, attempting to unpick the platform and other social media sites, while unearthing the dark truths behind these companies.</p>



<p>The film opens with slick camera shots against modernistic backgrounds, as various tech experts disclose their ex-Silicon Valley employers before their interviews begin. It is apparent that they are about to expose some of what goes on behind our screens; they seem nervous, as if unsure how their revelations will be received. One former Google employee awkwardly reveals that he &#8220;spent eight months talking back and forth with lawyers&#8221; about this interview, before others express their concern for the ethics of the companies they worked for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the next scene, we are presented with a dystopian-style barrage of social media-related American news reports on teenagers’ mental health, extremist groups, mass violence and Coronavirus misinformation. The essence of the problem, as explained by main contributor Tristan Harris and his industry friends, is this: the biggest tech companies are no longer the ones who simply create a product and sell it to their users. Instead, they are the ones whose customers are advertisers who pay to show their ads; and the product is you.</p>



<p>Their goal, then, becomes &#8220;how can we capture as much of their attention as possible?”, to hook us on the app, resulting in more ad exposure. These apps are therefore designed to be as addictive as possible, exploiting psychological vulnerabilities; meanwhile, the algorithms determine what to show us that will best engage us based on the data they have. These algorithms, however, are blind to false information and tend to bias extreme content and ideas, polarising nations and encouraging conspiracy theories and extremist groups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Not only does social media create its own problems of addiction, depression and anxiety; it also divides and misinforms, preventing people from focusing on solutions to the bigger issues at hand. Combined, these implications mean social media is fast being considered an existential threat to our humanity.</p>



<p>The film is interlaced with emotive dramatizations portraying the extreme capabilities of the technology we interact with on a level nothing short of a typical Black Mirror episode &#8211; also equipped with all of the eerie nostalgia and unsettling intensity courtesy of the background music.</p>



<p>However, the enactments create the challenge of distinguishing frenzied exaggeration from true portrayal; it&#8217;s hard to tell what data your devices are collecting from you, or to what extent different apps can use this data; do they really wait for gaps in your calendar app to ping an enticing notification your way? Do they really queue posts in your news feed from a person who is near to your location, and if so, is it really as stark as its Hollywood portrayal? It’s unclear which of the capabilities of these apps is the hard, cold truth, and how much is pure hyperbole designed &#8211; quite ironically &#8211; to get our attention?</p>



<p>Confusingly, the film seems to peddle the idea that social media companies are using manipulative, persuasive features to addict their users to the apps, while the co-founder and ex-designer interviewees seem reluctant to admit that there was anything inherently misguided about the way that they designed these apps. “nobody, I believe, ever intended any of these consequences”, reports former Twitter Executive Jeff Seibert. Some level of unfiltered honesty is displayed, but not a full admission of guilt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sure, the kind of gratification you get from receiving an email or notification is fairly unavoidable, but the hijacking of these addictive pathways is clearly deliberate. but there are blatant and intentional ways that the addictive pathways are being designed, too. Sean Parker, former president of Facebook, says of this manipulation, &#8220;[We all] understood this. But we did it anyway.&#8221; Surely, they couldn’t pretend to be ‘victims of a dangerous business model’. Perhaps this reveals the dark side of what went on &#8211; and is still going on &#8211; within these companies.</p>



<p>Ultimately, the “attention extraction” model that these companies have adopted, which views human beings as a resource to profit from, isn’t much less of a definition of exploitation than slavery or human trafficking. It&#8217;s just that this new kind of abuse and manipulation is far subtler, embedded in hidden webs of human psychology and algorithmic complexity; and therefore, all the more dangerous.</p>



<p>After taking on a rather solemn tone towards the end, with talk of the inevitable entrapment that the advertising business model and shareholder pressure bring, the film ends with a more optimistic, spirited call to remember what technology was created to be — something that helped us and connected us. This kind of technology can be designed humanely by returning to our original goal: “How do we make the world a better place, for everyone?” It’s what we all want, and it’s what social media companies promised; but it&#8217;s not delivering.</p>



<p>At least these ex-employees of the big tech companies have moved on, and begun to expose and discuss the secrets from within the industry. Have they helped to create these problems? Yes. Should you trust them? Probably. Having left the companies, contributed to this film, and some even helped to found an institute pursuing a humane technology agenda, you&#8217;d better believe them. In fact, our future may depend on it.</p>



<p><em>The Social Dilemma is available now on Netflix. To find out more about the project behind the film and continue the conversation, go to <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.thesocialdilemma.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">www.thesocialdilemma.com</a></span>.</em></p>



<p><strong>Text by Barney Venable<br>Featured image via <em>Forbes</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/">The Social Dilemma Review &#8211; “The Greatest Existential Threat Of Our Time?”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4343</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Room Of One’s Own: Some Thoughts On Isolation</title>
		<link>/a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation</link>
					<comments>/a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 17:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is certainly not what Virginia Woolf had in mind. For the majority of us, who live our lives by making plans, laying down brick by brick the path to our best future, this lockdown was not what we had in mind either. The rug was pulled out from under our feet. We tripped and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation/">A Room Of One’s Own: Some Thoughts On Isolation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>This is certainly not what Virginia Woolf had in mind.</p>



<p>For the majority of us, who live our lives by making plans, laying down brick by brick the path to our best future, this lockdown was not what we had in mind either. The rug was pulled out from under our feet. We tripped and when we came back up, the world had turned upside down. With the restrictions lifting, most of us still are encouraged to stay indoors, which means we are still contemplating how we can exist in a universe where time is standing still.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It feels like we (let me indulge and speak for those in early adulthood) are sidestepping minefields constantly. From Brexit to the constant threat of climate change to Trump to a pandemic, our futures never look that certain and taking those first steps into adulthood is becoming harder and harder when the world around us seems to be fighting for breath day after day. I suppose one of the side-effects of the world stopping on its axis is anxiety about the future and a certain hopelessness. I actively try to fight against the idea that our future is bleak. Because that’s all I am getting at the moment; be it through anxious conversations with my parents, or Doomsday reports about a global recession, or because I am unable to offer some true comfort to friends who are losing jobs, money, or their sanity.</p>



<p>I am thankfully safe and happy in my own home, but this forced moving-back-in certainly makes me feel unfree. It’s a particular feeling that only comes when you realise that you can’t live your life on your own terms; there is no concrete end date to how long you are meant to stand there and watch life pass you by. Even in the happiest of families, the home is no longer just a place that can bring people who love each other together; it is somewhere you must stay. I feel powerless, like a child, but I can’t expect the adults to figure this one out. And neither can I fully step in, be the adult, tell my parents: don’t worry, we’ll figure it all out.&nbsp; Because I don’t really believe that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Things would be easier if we could pick up where we left off, but the endless sea of uncertainty that is the future – emerging from lockdown, recovering from the financial dip, eventually dealing with Brexit – takes away that comfort. So it’s not so much that we are enjoying quality time with our loved ones, as that we are rooted to the spot, looking at things unfurling with terror. I feel ill-equipped to face the difficulties of the future. How am I going to face the ‘new normal’? For how long will we live our lives tiptoeing around, fearing infection? What jobs will be there for us to hustle for? As a generation already prone to anxiety and other mental health issues, can we even deal with more anxiety and uncertainty? Can we rebuild? Only to have things knocked down again when Brexit is added to the mix and whatever else comes next?</p>



<p>These are the depressing thoughts that pass through my mind. Spiralling has probably become a trend for anyone just starting out in their adult life, past the green grass (hm, actually, it wasn’t that green) of the early university years. I don’t really know what dreams to hold on to, because dreaming right now feels pointless.&nbsp; I have this constant urge to get out there and make things happen, but then I remember.</p>



<p>I am rooted to the spot.</p>



<p>But I am safe. I am healthy. As an international community, we are committed to preserving health for as many people as possible. We are staying in, we are wearing masks, we are doing all these things to save lives, to build a safer future if not the best future imaginable. Seldom have personal liberties been sacrificed for a better cause. Even through our screens, we have come together in great solidarity, fighting united against this pandemic, and I have hope that this solidarity will continue as we attempt to rebuild. These past few months have been a turning point: we learnt to act to protect others, we had a moment to reflect on our impact on the environment, we had a reckoning on racial injustice, and we gained clarity on the failures and successes of politicians around the world. We now clearly know what we are asking for: we are asking governments to protect us and support public health, we are asking for a society that truly cares about diversity and equality, we are asking for a greener future. No, we are not asking, we are demanding, because we can’t turn a blind eye anymore. Within ourselves, we have also redefined what success means to us, what we are hustling for and what we want in life. We have come to appreciate our health and be more grateful about the things we have and are truly worth fighting for: our loved ones, our community, the world’s future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Things will not be the same for a long time, but we have to hold on tight to the fact that we <em>can</em> make them better. If we can’t get back to normal, we might as well start thinking about what we want to replace that normal with.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Text by Alice Papadopoulou</strong><br><strong>Featured image via Tumblr.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation/">A Room Of One’s Own: Some Thoughts On Isolation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4286</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Netflix’s Indian Matchmaking: A Step Forwards Or Backwards For South Asian Culture?</title>
		<link>/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture</link>
					<comments>/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 18:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While mainstream TV shows and films helmed by South Asians were once few and far between, the increasing diversification of media indicates that one-note depictions of South Asians might soon become a thing of the past. But, at present, with so few cultural touchpoints when it comes to representations of South Asians, the stakes are [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/">Netflix’s Indian Matchmaking: A Step Forwards Or Backwards For South Asian Culture?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>While mainstream TV shows and films helmed by South Asians were once few and far between, the increasing diversification of media indicates that one-note depictions of South Asians might soon become a thing of the past. But, at present, with so few cultural touchpoints when it comes to representations of South Asians, the stakes are higher. In this light, it’s easy to understand why South Asians are divided over Netflix’s latest runaway hit <em>Indian Matchmaking</em>, which explores the contentious practice of arranged marriage. Some have argued that the show is a step backwards, <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/scaachikoul/indian-matchmaking-criticism-family-karma" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">presenting “South Asian identity” as “uniquely fraught,”</span></a> while others argue the show is just <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/07/indian-matchmaking-dating-reality-tv-colorism.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“telling it like it is.”</a>&nbsp;</span></p>



<p>Showrunner Smriti Mundhra was as frustrated as some of her critics with shows that were only <a href="https://medium.com/the-international-wave/interview-with-smriti-mundhra-storytelling-without-a-script-9edb2b7848ae" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">“about the trauma and the stereotypes that our communities are known for,”</span></a> seeking to present a fluffier alternative. <a href="https://medium.com/the-international-wave/interview-with-smriti-mundhra-storytelling-without-a-script-9edb2b7848ae" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">In an interview preceding its release on Netflix</span></a>, she stated that she “packaged” <em>Indian Matchmaking, </em>which<em> </em>documents matchmaker Sima Taparia as she journeys between India and America to find her clients a suitable spouse, as “a fun dating show” in the hopes that it would “be more accessible to a wider range of people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Inevitably, the South Asian community formed the show’s largest and most vocal viewership. The show is wryly funny, lightly ribbing some of the ridiculous views that are often espoused by South Asians, its editing poking fun at the absurd criteria that Taparia’s clients insist on and interspersing her meme-able observations in between scenes depicting her clients on their quest for love. Multiple episodes of the show open with <em>When Harry Met Sally</em>-esque interviews featuring bickering couples who had an arranged marriage, adding to its sentimental feel. At first glance, its cast seems to be formed of caricatures of South Asians we know and may or may not love – the highly-strung overachiever, the regressive aunty, the overbearing mother and the coddled mummy’s boy. However, the show does not solely relegate its cast to sources of comedy. In part, it endeavours to demonstrate a fuller picture of who Taparia’s clients are and why they ended up in front of her, such as fan favourite Nadia, who seeks to find a partner who is accepting of both her Indian and Guyanese heritage and Ankita, a self-assured businesswoman who is ready to move onto the next stage of her life, but only on her own terms.</p>



<p>As much as the <em>Indian Matchmaking</em> audience’s familiarity with the communities and cultures heightens its relatability and humour, it also renders its lurid veneer transparent. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2020/08/netflix-indian-matchmaking-and-the-shadow-of-caste/614863/?utm_source=feed" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">As Yashica Dutt writes</a></span>, the show’s “coding” of caste through seemingly benign phrases like “shared communities” or “respectable families” serves to disfigure the reality of the caste system and the discrimination and violence it creates. Many have criticised the show for being uncritical of the misogyny upheld by matchmakers and clients alike, who idealise fair skin and prize compliance to men, insisting that potential brides be “flexible,” while women who are unwavering in their standards are labelled “not stable.” It has not gone unnoticed that the burdens of belonging to such a family-orientated and image-based culture and the resulting pressure to conform, as well as the consequences of not conforming,&nbsp; are a frequent theme in the storylines of nearly all of Taparia’s clients.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mundhra is well aware of the arguments surrounding her subject, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.thecut.com/2020/07/indian-matchmaking-review.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">having faced pressure to have an arranged marriage herself</a></span>, as well as having directed the slightly more critical documentary<em> A Suitable Girl </em>in 2017. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.glamour.com/story/netflix-indian-matchmaking" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Her own view of arranged marriage</a></span> is that “it was designed to preserve caste and class and to subjugate women,” but that it has since “evolved from that.” She appears to argue that arranged marriage is a choice, that, as <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-53499195" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Anna MM Vetticad states</span></a>, it is merely “a practical Indian version of the dating game in the West,” whereby the only difference is that your potential matches are presented to you by your parents and matchmaker rather than Tinder. It’s an argument that may ring familiar to many South Asians for whom this half-truth is a balm to their affection for their culture against Western paternalism and condescension. Yet, in spite of the optimistic perspective that informs it, <em>Indian Matchmaking’s</em> light-hearted approach jars with the tensions implicit in the situations we witness, almost satirical in its absurdity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In&nbsp; acknowledgement of the criticism of<em> Indian Matchmaking</em>,&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.glamour.com/story/netflix-indian-matchmaking" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mundhra has stated that</a></span> “It’s not possible to show the entire perspective, of course, and the show leaves a lot on the table,” inviting others to hold her “accountable.” By relying on its audience to complete the unfinished picture that <em>Indian Matchmaking</em> presents of arranged marriage, particularly those most negatively affected by the prejudicial practices it upholds, the show admits its failure to prove its thesis. As it turns out, <a href="https://www.womenshealthmag.com/relationships/a33368001/indian-matchmaking-netflix-couples-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">none of Taparia’s clients that featured on the show found a match through her</span></a>. Sometimes, reality cannot be easily repackaged as a romcom. Nor should the unique struggles faced by South Asians living in the West, often tied to their cultures and traditions, be obscured, to prevent others viewing South Asian identity as “uniquely fraught.” As much as South Asians are tired of being represented as repressed objects of ridicule, it’s apparent that the solution is to treat these issues with nuance, not to sandpaper over the breadth of our experiences with generalised positivity.</p>



<p><strong>Text by Madhu Manivannan<br>Featured image via Vanity Fair.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/">Netflix’s Indian Matchmaking: A Step Forwards Or Backwards For South Asian Culture?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4282</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Film Fanatic&#8217;s Guide To Staycation</title>
		<link>/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation</link>
					<comments>/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 11:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown American chef Anthony Bourdain cited his experience filming an episode of his show Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations in Lebanon in the midst of the 2006 Israel-Lebanon War as having significantly reshaped his attitude towards his work. He remarked that “I just saw that there were realities beyond what was on my [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/">A Film Fanatic&#8217;s Guide To Staycation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong><em>Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown</em></strong></p>



<p>American chef Anthony Bourdain cited his experience filming an episode of his show <em>Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations</em> in Lebanon in the midst of the 2006 Israel-Lebanon War as having significantly reshaped his attitude towards his work. <a href="https://explorepartsunknown.com/beirut/field-notes-from-beirut/">He remarked that</a> “I just saw that there were realities beyond what was on my plate, and those realities almost inevitably informed what was—or was not—for dinner. To ignore them had come to seem monstrous.” <em>Anthony Bourdain:</em> <em>Parts Unknown</em> is a reflection of these realities, following Bourdain as he journeys around the world, sampling native delicacies from the Chickenjoy bucket at Jollibee to fish and chips in a greasy spoon. <em>Parts Unknown </em>is a celebration of food and its multifaceted significance, whether it serves a communal purpose or constitutes an expression of love, or it is rooted in historical significance and acts as an expression of identity and culture.</p>



<p><em>Seasons 1 to 12 available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>The Imagineering Story</em></strong></p>



<p>Over the past few months, many of us have realised that the American Dream is just that, a dream. One of the most tangible manifestations of this dream is Main Street, U.S.A., a themed area of Disneyland parks across the world, the first of which was inspired by Walt Disney’s childhood memories of growing up in Missouri. In many ways, the story told in <em>The Imagineering Story</em>, the story of the original Disneyland and its expansion across the world, is a story about America, as well as a tribute to the creative endeavors of the “Imagineers” who made the ornate attractions of Disneyland possible, albeit a whitewashed one. Among the companies admitting their past wrongdoings and vowing to do better in the wake of the Black Lives Matter protests was Disney, who finally decided to overhaul the last conspicuous acknowledgement of their racist 1946 film, <em>Song of the South</em>. The ride Splash Mountain will now be <a href="https://twitter.com/DisneyParks/status/1276187686672437249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1276187686672437249%7Ctwgr%5E&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.smithsonianmag.com%2Fsmart-news%2Fdisney-will-completely-reimagine-controversial-splash-mountain-ride-180975198%2F" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“<em>reimagined with a new story</em>”</a> inspired by <em>The Princess and the Frog</em>, the 2009 film that introduced Disney’s first Black princess, Tiana. As illustrated by <em>The Imagineering Story</em>, Disneyland continues to evolve alongside America, an amalgamation of its hopes and desires, both past and present. </p>



<p><em>Episodes 1 to 6 available on Disney+.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Elite</em></strong></p>



<p>Catch up on the frothy teen drama before the release of its fourth season, for which Netflix Spain recently revealed the four new additions to its cast. <em>Elite</em>’s first season revolves around three working class students who win a scholarship to study at an exclusive private school as they navigate high society alongside typical adolescent struggles. While it’s a hard sell on intellectual merit alone, the heightened melodrama and extravagance of <em>Elite</em> makes for pure mindless fun.</p>



<p><em>Seasons 1 to 3 available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Time to Hunt (2020)</em></strong></p>



<p>This South Korean thriller is set within a dystopia, where a financial crisis has devastated the South Korean economy. <em>Time to Hunt</em> follows a group of three small time criminals, one of whom is played by Choi Wooshik, who you may recognize as Kiwoo from Parasite. As they embark on one last heist to escape their miserable situation by leaving for Taiwan, things go awry as they are hunted down by a mysterious assassin. Although the ominous nature of the film’s setting may leave you with questions by the time the credits roll, it also serves to heighten the atmospheric and thrilling journey of the three protagonists while alluding to themes of class and brotherhood.</p>



<p><em>Available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>A Suitable Girl (2017)</em></strong></p>



<p>Netflix’s <em>Indian Matchmaking</em>, a reality TV show documenting matchmaker Sima Taparia from Mumbai as she attempts to find her clients a spouse, has set the South Asian diaspora ablaze. Discussion about the show is equally as abundant with memes as with disapproval for its uncritical depiction of arranged marriage, touching on but ultimately glossing over a host of issues such as colourism and misogyny. Taparia is presumably no stranger to such criticisms, having previously starred in <em>A Suitable Girl</em>, a documentary following three women in India, including Taparia’s daughter Ritu, as they search for a spouse and adjust to married life. <em>A Suitable Girl</em> focuses not on delightfully extravagant personalities like Pradhyuman and Aparna, but the experiences of ordinary women as they reflect on how notions of marriage and gender have shaped their lives. Unassuming yet powerful, <em>A Suitable Girl</em> is an insight into the quotidian cultural and familial pressures faced by Indian women.</p>



<p><em>Available on Netflix.&nbsp;&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><strong><em>The Half of It (2020)</em></strong></p>



<p><em>The Half of It</em> revolves around shy recluse Ellie Chu, a Chinese-American teenager on the cusp of adulthood who is stuck in the small town of Squahamish for the foreseeable future. Strapped for cash, she agrees to mediate on the behalf of inarticulate jock Paul Munsky who pays her to write love letters to his crush, the popular daughter of a conservative pastor, Aster Flores. However, Paul and Ellie learn that you can’t plan love, as the three teenagers’ feelings act independently of their preordained destinations, growing unexpectedly deeper and more complicated. Alice Wu’s first film since 2005’s <em>Saving Face</em> is a refreshing, funny and heartwarming take on the “teen movie”, investigating the interlinking themes of adolescent identity, friendship and love.</p>



<p><em>Available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong>Text by Madhu Manivannan<br>Featured image via <em>reddit.com</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/">A Film Fanatic&#8217;s Guide To Staycation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4267</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Stay Motivated For Online Courses</title>
		<link>/tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses</link>
					<comments>/tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 17:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s all extended-holidays and sleep-ins until we&#8217;re back to home lectures and compulsory studying, right guys? The real question is: how do I stay motivated when doing online courses? It&#8217;s definitely not easy, whether it be younger siblings who just love being in your space, or that you’re home alone and can’t help feeling distracted. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses/">How To Stay Motivated For Online Courses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>It’s all extended-holidays and sleep-ins until we&#8217;re back to home lectures and compulsory studying, right guys? The real question is: how do I stay motivated when doing online courses? It&#8217;s definitely not easy, whether it be younger siblings who just love being in your space, or that you’re home alone and can’t help feeling distracted. Both are unbearable for trying to get work done depending on your study habits, so here are our top tips for staying focused at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>First things first: establishing a clear workspace</strong>.</p>



<p>Whether it be in your room, the living room or even the dining room, it is important that you don’t attempt to work from your bed. While it may be the most comfortable spot in the house, it’s also the biggest temptress for sleeping. Speaking for the majority, it’s the first mistake you can make when trying to work from home. To avoid this, try and find a place in your house that will allow you to maintain a separate workspace; where you can physically and mentally disconnect yourself from distractions and other such things that are not a part of working hours, and means you can leave study-mode when it’s time to relax.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Remember to take time for yourself every day.</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;Apart from attending your compulsory online lectures, studying itself shouldn’t be a complete chore. While you have many things to do such as writing and typing out your notes, reading chapters or planning out reports, it is important that you spread out your tasks throughout the day and week, and not try and complete them in one sitting for the sake of “getting them out of the way”. This way of working gives you a little permission to still be human and decompress between workloads during the day, instead of building up stress and then becoming unmotivated. Prioritising allows you to get the pain-staking tasks out of the way; so that you can work more leisurely in completing your less-demanding tasks throughout the week.</p>



<p>Although it’s important to spread out your work through the day, we all operate differently; what works for one person may not necessarily work for the next. To organise yourself in a way that suits your style, try out different plans of action to discover what studying plan is performance-effective for you. It could be that you feel more stimulated to do work in the evenings, or that you might have more energy after your morning workout.</p>



<p><strong>Finally, re-establish that motivation and asking yourself “why am I doing this?”</strong></p>



<p>Being work-focused in your home is never going to be the same as in the lecture theatre &#8211; surrounded by other students eager to learn. Let’s be honest, it&#8217;s those sitting through the 2-hour 9.00am lectures that are the serious candidates. That said, if you know you&#8217;re not that type of person, it is important you become that person. Remind yourself why you need to work harder than if you were on campus&#8230; in other words, to secure the bag and get that degree.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Tobi Ogunjemilua<br>Featured image via<a href="https://www.freepik.com/free-photo/flat-lay-laptop-mockup-with-notepad_4181729.htm"> </a><em>freepik.com</em></strong>.</p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses/">How To Stay Motivated For Online Courses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4264</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Terrace House: Yet Another Reality TV Show Which Hasn’t Learnt Its Lesson</title>
		<link>/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson</link>
					<comments>/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 20:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Japanese show, Terrance House, has attracted a devoted international audience who herald it as a softer alternative to traditionally abrasive, overtly manufactured reality shows like Big Brother and Love Island. Terrace House is Not Like Other Reality TV Shows, at least that’s the implicit promise that lies behind its minimalistic premise of following a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/">Terrace House: Yet Another Reality TV Show Which Hasn’t Learnt Its Lesson</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>The Japanese show, Terrance House, has attracted a devoted international audience who herald it as a softer alternative to traditionally abrasive, overtly manufactured reality shows like Big Brother and Love Island.</p>



<p>Terrace House is <em>Not Like Other Reality TV Shows,</em> at least that’s the implicit promise that lies behind its minimalistic premise of following a rotating cast of six, (mostly) ordinary strangers, as they go about their daily lives and learn to live together in a lavishly decorated house. They are free to end their arc at any time by leaving the house. After each scene, the show cuts to a celebrity panel, who watch and react alongside you. Each member of the panel assumes an archetype, allowing their acute dissection to play out like a skit, while also acting as a surrogate viewer voice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Terrace House’s so-called utopia has been called into question following the death of Hana Kimura, a pro wrestler, as well as a cast member on its most recent season, Terrace House: Tokyo 2019-2020. Shortly before her death last month, Hana tweeted “Every day, I receive nearly 100 honest opinions and I cannot deny that I get hurt,” as <a href="https://www.japantimes.co.jp/culture/2020/05/26/entertainment-news/suicide-note-written-pro-wrestler-terrace-house-star-hana-kimura-discovered/#.Xs_XAy3Mzs0" target="_blank" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">translated by Japan Times</span></a>. These hateful tweets had apparently escalated following the airing of an episode in Japan in which she had a heated argument with another cast member.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Defined by its obsession with the interpersonal conflicts that inevitably arise between housemates, Terrace House feeds of as what Troy Patterson described in the New Yorker as the “honest friction of minor personality flaws and conflicting personal needs”.&nbsp; Yet, the last three complete seasons just happen to be punctuated by the dramatization of a major argument between multiple cast members. Although these arguments do, to an extent, appear to be driven by “honest friction,” it is also apparent that the spectre of the camera looms behind them.</p>



<p>Another facet to the lens through which Terrace House is dramatized is the culture of prurience that underlies the show, which, admittedly, is not atypical within the reality TV genre. Much of the critical discussion about misogyny in Terrace House revolves around its portrayal and discussion of consent, particularly with regards to the relationships between Seina and Shohei in Opening New Doors and Boss and Yume in Tokyo 2019-2020. The voyeuristic nature of the show facilitates its panel in scrutinising and shaming its female cast members for how they express their sexuality.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery aligncenter columns-1 is-cropped"><ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson\/"}' class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="4235" data-permalink="/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/image-12/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?fit=750%2C422&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="750,422" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?fit=750%2C422&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="750" height="422" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?resize=750%2C422" alt="" data-id="4235" data-full-url="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?resize=750%2C422" data-link="/?attachment_id=4235" class="wp-image-4235" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?w=750&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></li></ul><figcaption class="blocks-gallery-caption"><em>via Time Out</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The show’s regressive attitudes towards women have never been so blatantly mean spirited as in the panel’s treatment of 22 year old student Emika In Tokyo 2019-2020, a storyline involved both Emika and Hana, who eventually became friends within the house, competing for the attention of basketball player Ryo. Emika was framed as the manipulative seductress in opposition to Hana’s innocent naïf through the editing of the show and the panel’s vulgar commentary. Another unique aspect of Terrace House’s format is that episodes may air in a matter of weeks after they were filmed, so housemates sitting in the “playroom” to watch and reflect on the episodes they star in together is a frequent fixture of the show. In Emika’s penultimate episode, she watches an episode in the playroom which casts her in an unflattering light. After hearing the unsympathetic words of the panel, she leaves the room. She breaks down crying, finding online hate comments and the panel’s unrelenting scrutiny to be “excruciating,” and ultimately decides to leave the house. The episode then cuts to the panel, who stand by their criticism and refuse to show any empathy for Emika or to reflect on the veracity and tone of their criticisms. In Emika’s final episode, the guest panellist, Mei Nagano, states “I believe we received the correct impression from her actions,” which the rest of the panel concur with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Terrace House’s panellists appear not only to function as a form of comedic relief, but also as moral arbiters, their observations acting as trials through which Terrace House cast members undergo self-realisation and improvement. Despite, only watching carefully curated scenes edited and chopped to intentionally depict a heightened version of real life, the panelists ignore this superficial construction of reality. As a consequence, they allow wry commentary based on the events of the show to quickly descend into vindictive insults mired in prejudice that blur the lines between the cast members as real people and characters.</p>



<p>In the wake of Hana’s death, Japanese government officials have called for tougher action to be taken on cyberbullying and Terrace House’s Tokyo 2019-2020 season was <a href="https://www.japantimes.co.jp/culture/2020/05/27/entertainment-news/terrace-house-canceled-hana-kimura-suicide/#.XuOFNy3Mzs3">announced to be cancelled</a> on May 27<sup>th</sup>, although the future of the show itself is unclear. What is clear is that the show is untenable in its current format. Its deceptively simple premise belies the fact that living in Terrace House could turn into a pressure cooker of expectations imposed by its panellists, production team, audience and the cast members themselves. But if Terrace House were to be cancelled, its problems might continue to exist. Reality TV shows may continue to mischaracterise their participants through editing and broadcast their lowest moments with little regard as to how this could affect them. Audiences may still take what they see at face value, flattening real people into caricatures that can neatly be placed into the category of “hero” or “villain,” while cast members are left to fend for themselves as social media platforms are used to weaponize these assumptions against them.</p>



<p>Terrace House turned out not to be an idyllic utopia but a microcosm, shining a light on our shortcomings as a society and as digital citizens. Although it is defined by its Japanese cultural context, we are familiar with some of the reality TV tropes and regressive attitudes it employed in the west, reflecting a world where we are quick to make condemnatory judgements and reserve our harshest criticism for women who act outside of their prescribed societal role, rather than men who forcibly kiss their romantic interests and ogle over their female housemates’ “assets.” But while it could stoke our worst impulses, Terrace House was also capable of celebrating understanding and compassion. Despite its problems, the wide majority of fans tuned in for scenes of housemates diligently plating party snacks and arranging balloons for surprise birthday dinners, of couples navigating the first stages of their relationships, of friendships evolving from nervous introductions to tearful hugs goodbye. In its best moments, Terrace House was an ode to human connection, finding the beauty in its most joyful as well as its most painful moments. In the wake of tragedy, this aspect of the show has taken on a poignant relevancy.</p>



<p><strong>Text by Madhu Manivannan<br>Featured image via <em>Eater</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/">Terrace House: Yet Another Reality TV Show Which Hasn’t Learnt Its Lesson</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4234</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
