<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Music Review &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/music/music-review/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A fashion, culture, art and music publication, written by students about students.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 18:49:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/cropped-12773305_10206631248554054_481252708_o.jpg?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Music Review &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107671177</site>	<item>
		<title>GT Live Sessions: A Review</title>
		<link>/gt-live-sessions-a-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=gt-live-sessions-a-review</link>
					<comments>/gt-live-sessions-a-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 16:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Returning from a stay in Liverpool had me itching to check out Guildford’s music scene, and so I headed to watch the latest episode of GT Live Sessions. Hosted at the Britannia, this weekly event is a showcase of local talent organised by guitarist and songwriter Gavin Thomas. First on the bill were Lauren and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/gt-live-sessions-a-review/">GT Live Sessions: A Review</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>Returning from a stay in Liverpool had me itching to check
out Guildford’s music scene, and so I headed to watch the latest episode of GT
Live Sessions. Hosted at the
Britannia, this weekly event is a showcase of local talent organised by
guitarist and songwriter Gavin Thomas.</p>



<p>First on the bill
were Lauren and Hardy, an acoustic guitar and vocal duo whose seamless on-stage
chemistry made for some incredibly exciting playing. Intoxicating steel-stringed
melodies wove together, providing an ideal base for impressive vocal play
between Mason’s airy soprano and Hardy’s gritty bass. The singing was as well
matched as the guitars, and tight harmonies demonstrated the unmistakeable
togetherness that comes from hours of practise and performance. Their groovy,
triplet-feel cover of Survivior was undoubtedly the highlight; my head was
bobbing throughout, and a quick scan of the audience behind me confirmed that I
was not alone.</p>



<p>Next up was Vicky
Sayers, a singer-songwriter who took to the stage armed with acoustic guitar,
microphone, bundles of energy and infectious charm. A driving, strummed
accompaniment and some tidy work on the equaliser from Thomas allowed plenty of
space for Sayers to display her vocal agility. Long, airy verse lines meshed well
with weightier, more soulful choruses to frame a performance driven by raw
songwriting talent; “Human Nature” instantly brought to mind the
powerful-yet-catchy performances of a young KT Tunstall, while “Rolling Stone” would
look right at home in the upper reaches of the UK Top 40.</p>



<p>A short intermission saw the arrival of a kit and Launchpad on stage, much to my excitement. My instincts were right, as what followed was undoubtedly my favourite act of the evening. Solent-born <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="BRUCH (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.instagram.com/BruchMusic/" target="_blank"><strong>BRUCH</strong></a>, a student at the Academy of Contemporary Music (ACM), presented a set genuinely unlike anything I have heard before. With reverb cranked to 11 and phasers set to stun, BRUCH opened with a masterclass in vocal control supported by a dreamy, tumbling backing track. Her performance had the air of a 2009 Florence Welch submerged in a vat of purple synthesiser juice, such was the degree of vocal versatility and width of stereo on display. Suspended, crystalline melodies were interspersed with yelps of joy from the young artist, whose captivating on-stage presence silenced all conversation in the bar. The addition of Ryan Bartlett on drums for “Crown” betrayed a sudden sense of urgency and what was a dreamy, ethereal set instantly became driving, energetic and brimming with anger. Bartlett’s restrained use of floor tom and snare struck an unmistakably war-like tone (think Florence’s “Leave My Body” from Ceremonials, but faster, darker and much, much more pissed off!). </p>



<p>BRUCH considers
nature as one of her main influences and this is plain to see; where the
earlier numbers represented something akin to delicate vines growing around a
great tree trunk, these later numbers brought images of an Atlantic storm
battering the Hampshire coast. This anger is no metaphor, however; I caught up
with BRUCH before the show where she expressed how her frustration and rage at
the mistreatment of the planet is a definite driving force behind her writing.
A truly exciting talent, this is definitely not an act to miss, and with more
releases scheduled for later in the year we can expect big things to come.</p>



<p>From the
awe-inspiring to the delightful, next up was Polly Gone Wrong, a female
voice-only trio who could not hide their wonderful on-stage chemistry; an
infectious, swaggering confidence full of giggly, cheeky energy. At its heart,
creativity is about reaching a playful state of mind and Polly Gone Wrong
embody this perfectly, riffing off each other both in performance and between
songs. A deeply charming stage presence did not go for want of talent, however,
as the trio navigated effortlessly between chromatic close harmonies and
parallel thirds, fifths and octaves, sometimes from bar to bar, interspersed
with occasional beatboxing. Melding top singing talent with thoroughly likeable
personas, Polly Gone Wrong could make even Pachabell’s Canon interesting.</p>



<p>Next on the bill was
Beamis, a two-man guitar and voice lineup from Portsmouth. It is hard to beat
the appeal of two old boys rocking out, and the combination of driving, clean
rhythm and peachy lead sounded like something straight from an Eagles concert.
Accomplished strumming, supplied by some of the more tidy wristwork I’ve seen
recently, knitted seamlessly with the vocals to produce an appealing, enjoyable
sound. Beamis’ frothy, joyful opener reminiscent of the Bellamy Brothers’ glory
days kept smiles on faces, while the darker, more urgent tracks would not have
been out of place in a smoky Nashville dive bar. Overall, a solid set executed
with precision, dexterity and, most importantly, a genuine joie-de-vivre.</p>



<p>The final set saw
local singer-songwriter Tom Copson take the stage. Copson’s appealing brand of
clean acoustic guitar and treacly, glinting baritone are the perfect tools to
showcase an exciting song writing talent. Unfortunately, train timetables
forced me to bid an early and reluctant goodbye to the Britannia, and so I
missed the rest of the set. However, readers can listen to all of Tom’s
releases on Bandcamp, YouTube and Soundcloud.</p>



<p>Each of the acts expressed themselves and their work with skill and confidence. The artists here have exiting futures in store, with both the talent and potential to achieve notoriety. Music is happening in Guildford, and it is happening right now – you won’t want to miss it!</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Sam Clarke<br>Picture research by Anna Irina; featured image from Pinterest.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/gt-live-sessions-a-review/">GT Live Sessions: A Review</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/gt-live-sessions-a-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3663</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BBC Music Introducing LIVE 2018: A Review</title>
		<link>/bbc-music-introducing-live-2018-a-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bbc-music-introducing-live-2018-a-review</link>
					<comments>/bbc-music-introducing-live-2018-a-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 18:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Music is an outlet for expression. That was most definitely seen at BBC Music Introducing LIVE last week. So much culture and colour in one setting, designed to inspire all those who attended. Musicians and instrumentalists alike, the atmosphere was buzzing with people of all ages making connections and gaining inside knowledge on the music [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/bbc-music-introducing-live-2018-a-review/">BBC Music Introducing LIVE 2018: A Review</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody"></p>
<p class="normal">Music is an outlet for expression. That was most definitely seen at BBC Music Introducing LIVE last week. So much culture and colour in one setting, designed to inspire all those who attended. Musicians and instrumentalists alike, the atmosphere was buzzing with people of all ages making connections and gaining inside knowledge on the music industry. As R&amp;B artist Call Me Unique was performing her charismatic set on the North Bandstand, James McVinnie and Belle Chen were sharing their creative insights on how classical music can have influence on the contemporary pop sound we hear on our radio stations every day.</p>
<p class="normal">Elizabeth Alker of BBC 6Music and BBC Radio 3 opened the discussion up in ‘Unclassified… Taking Influence From Classical &amp; Pop’ of how to introduce audiences to new music. Breakfast radio show ‘Unclassified’ has had a good response with audiences, reflecting influences from pop, rock, jazz and electronic music genres. Unique, albeit eclectic, artists such as Thomas Bartlett &amp; Nico Muhly, as well as Bryce Dessner and Aphex Twin, were all played to showcase the growing movement of different genres across a broad range of artists. Australian pianist Belle Chen trained at the Royal Academy and has a new album ‘Departure’ out now. Her third full-length album draws inspiration from traditional sounds from all around the world. Over the course of the talk, she voiced her passion for wanting to tell her own story and this is what drove her to start creating her own sound. A lot of her inspiration comes from experimenting with acoustic instruments in order to make music that draws from the world around her.</p>
<p>English organist James McVinnie’s innovated new angles on pipe organs and how they can be assimilated to early synthesisers when describing his new album ‘The Grid’. Initially, McVinnie expressed how traditional instruments such as the pipe organ can have a lot of preconceived ideas attached to them, but when remodelled and brought to life in a different way, can be uniquely received by an audience. Genre-hopping has been around for as long as music has, and every artist has to start somewhere with the type of music they draw upon in order to create their own musical identity. This is key to understanding the stance that both Chen and McVinnie take in their music, starting a dialogue that begs the question: should the term “unclassified” be a genre in itself?</p>
<p><div id="attachment_3269" style="width: 6010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3269" data-attachment-id="3269" data-permalink="/bbc-music-introducing-live-2018-a-review/img_1670/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1670.jpg?fit=6000%2C4000&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6000,4000" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_1670" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1670.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1670.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-3269 size-full" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1670.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1670.jpg?w=6000&amp;ssl=1 6000w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1670.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1670.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1670.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1670.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1670.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-3269" class="wp-caption-text">© Hadiya Haseeb</p></div></p>
<p><div id="attachment_3268" style="width: 6010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3268" data-attachment-id="3268" data-permalink="/bbc-music-introducing-live-2018-a-review/img_1669/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1669.jpg?fit=6000%2C4000&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6000,4000" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_1669" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1669.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1669.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-3268 size-full" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1669.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1669.jpg?w=6000&amp;ssl=1 6000w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1669.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1669.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1669.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1669.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_1669.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-3268" class="wp-caption-text">© Hadiya Haseeb</p></div></p>
<p class="normal">On the other side of the Tobacco Docks, Clean Bandit’s Jack Patterson broke down his song ‘Solo’ in a masterclass open to all that were interested in the technical mixing process. He too, spoke of his classical roots. After all, Grace Chatto and himself started off by recording Chatto’s string quartet performances in Cambridge before Luke Patterson joined the band. In experimenting with different sound samples, they very quickly attracted attention and haven’t turned back since. As a band, they pride themselves in using original samples and mixing their songs independently, but Patterson was open in admitting that sometimes the biggest challenge in song-writing is to know when to let go of a demo and let it develop further before it can be heard by the public. Towards the end of the masterclass, he revealed his intent for the future sound of Clean Bandit, wanting to get back to their classical roots even though that can sometimes bring more musical challenges. With his jazz background, he expressed a love for mixing classical and electronic sounds, which ultimately creates Clean Bandit’s signature sound.</p>
<p class="normal"><a name="_gjdgxs"></a>Looking ahead to the future of the industry, BBC Music Introducing LIVE perfectly showed how music genres have evolved over time. Even today, electronic, dance and house artists are still looking back to previous models of music, proving its true immortality. SUBCULTURED left Tobacco Docks feeling inspired and excited for up and coming music artists who established more of a name for themselves. A hub for dynamic and bright individuals, music has lived on in society for generations with its unparalleled nature to connect individuals from all walks of life. We wonder, what will we hear on the radio next?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="normal"><strong>Text by Annabella Costantino</strong></p>
<p><strong>Photos by Hadiya Haseeb.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/bbc-music-introducing-live-2018-a-review/">BBC Music Introducing LIVE 2018: A Review</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/bbc-music-introducing-live-2018-a-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3267</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Good Enough That It Can Be Great: SHADED&#8217;s ‘A Familiar Love’ EP</title>
		<link>/good-enough-that-it-can-be-great-shadeds-a-familiar-love-ep/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=good-enough-that-it-can-be-great-shadeds-a-familiar-love-ep</link>
					<comments>/good-enough-that-it-can-be-great-shadeds-a-familiar-love-ep/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 18:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I started playing SHADED’s “Dream Girl” at full volume in an isolated study space tucked away in my departmental building one night, just to hear it, and – after quickly hitting pause and turning down the volume upon the initial eardrum quake – thought ‘man, I really like this’. Then I thought that the vocals [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/good-enough-that-it-can-be-great-shadeds-a-familiar-love-ep/">Good Enough That It Can Be Great: SHADED&#8217;s ‘A Familiar Love’ EP</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">I started playing SHADED’s “Dream Girl” at full volume in an isolated study space tucked away in my departmental building one night, just to hear it, and – after quickly hitting pause and turning down the volume upon the initial eardrum quake – thought ‘man, I really like this’. Then I thought that the vocals needed better equalisation, which for the average listener just means that despite being pretty loud you might feel like you’re straining to hear the voice over the music. Thankfully, this doesn’t persist through the whole track, and is a non-starter in the rest of the songs.</p>
<p>And when you can hear the vocals, you pick out something not often seen in this soft-punk-pop since Avril skated away: the singer really cares about vocal quality and technique, and isn’t afraid to show off in ways your average neon pink emo ‘00s tween would think were just not <em>cool </em>compared to the generic shout-singing that made us all think we could start a band. I had to hit pause again at the first “but you’re not the one that I need girl”, as clichéd as the lyric is, to just appreciate this. Because if 2018 can’t bring about a real embracing of musical skill no matter the fragile semantics of genre, what can?</p>
<p>The vocal excellence shatters a bit when it veers into common practice (with a bit of a country tone? Though you can’t go wrong with mid-transition Taylor Swift as inspiration) and then into repetition. We can’t condemn songs for repeating lyrics in the appropriate places, but vocal variety is something you have to afford if you don’t want me to feel like only one take was good enough and you Ctrl+P’d it for every chorus. Saying this, the bridge smashes vocal complexity, so the three lines of slipping into boring territory can be ploughed through.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_3127" style="width: 5556px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3127" data-attachment-id="3127" data-permalink="/an-interview-with-shaded/lead-press-shot-2/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/LEAD-PRESS-SHOT-2.jpg?fit=5546%2C3693&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="5546,3693" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.4&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1532096576&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;35&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.000125&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="LEAD PRESS SHOT 2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/LEAD-PRESS-SHOT-2.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/LEAD-PRESS-SHOT-2.jpg?fit=1024%2C682&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-3127 size-full" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/LEAD-PRESS-SHOT-2.jpg?resize=1200%2C799" alt="" width="1200" height="799" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/LEAD-PRESS-SHOT-2.jpg?w=5546&amp;ssl=1 5546w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/LEAD-PRESS-SHOT-2.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/LEAD-PRESS-SHOT-2.jpg?resize=1024%2C682&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/LEAD-PRESS-SHOT-2.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/LEAD-PRESS-SHOT-2.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/LEAD-PRESS-SHOT-2.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-3127" class="wp-caption-text">@ George Girvan Photography</p></div></p>
<p>“Dream Girl”? I’d listen to that at the gym, on a walk, studying. It’s good, and it works, and you can forgive it those minor grievances because it’s an unguilty pleasure.</p>
<p>The title track (“A Familiar Love”) suffers a bit more: a long intro shortly followed by an early bridge is confusing, and the music definitely rules in this particular song – which would be fine if not for the fact that it is, for the most part, barely distinguishable from the previous song (“Dream Girl”). Back-to-back, this creates a postmodern listening experience where there’s a slight mood shift but it feels like an extension of the same song, or a deliberate interval between tracks. It doesn’t get to two minutes before it feels like the song should have ended, and it might not be enticing enough to keep people listening past this point when it plays on shuffle, which is a little bit tragic because after this is when the variety and technical ability (shout out to the guitarist) finally shifts into fifth gear. It’s worth listening to, because it’s not missing anything it needs, though it feels a bit wobbly, so I wouldn’t isolate it as individually powerful. And why is the fade out so long?</p>
<p>Contrastingly, the final track “You” is a firecracker of a song that sounds like it was written for a film soundtrack. Possibly for the ending credits, but also potentially during some dramatic rom-com airport chase scene. Now, again, let’s not overly-concern ourselves with the words, instead focusing our attentions on the nice scaling of the musical scale done for some of these notes. I don’t think you need more of me saying that it’s musically good, but you need to know that the progression is very well done – songwriting is more than just music, and they’ve mastered the structure here, too.</p>
<p>As a short slide away from compliments, I have to tell you that my first impression of “Tell Me” is that it, without lyrics, is perfect as an alternative music track for “Party in the USA” until 35 seconds, and then for Miley’s <em>actual </em>pop-punk dabble of “7 Things” after that and, seriously, why make me think about Hannah Montana releasing an emo EP? But you know what, I’ll go back and restart it once I’ve cleansed that from my mind.</p>
<p>Hey, this is a really good song. It doesn’t hit stride till around the minute mark, but if you listen to the voice as well then it segues from Miley into something that I can’t think of a suitable comparison for. <em>Let’s call it SHADED.</em>Their sound is well-defined in this track, and I will now, for you, define that sound as a wonderful complement between the singer’s vocal abilities – constantly at a soft shout and having the occasional quarrel with the confines of range, to his advantage – and the tuneful bashing by crowbars of every instrument they could find in his garage that constitutes the music. That guitarist also comes out to shine again, so the next song best have a solo in it <em>à la </em>Queen. Ironically, “tell me I’m fine for the hundredth time” is also the thing I say most often in relationships.</p>
<p>That’s a lie, I just can’t date. Which gives me the time to have enough of a musical variety stored in my noggin to know that the intro and opening chords of “Dead Feelings” were both sampled, I just can’t remember what songs from. The whole song, following suit, feels like the bastard child of songs from different branches of the genre of rock. It’s like an All-American Rejects angry ‘I got just dumped’ song and a Say Anything sad ‘I just got dumped’ song were shoved into a blender and the result was discarded on the countertop – which, in genuine retrospect, is a process that would make me feel angry, sad, and dumped, so I guess that works.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_3124" style="width: 5770px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3124" data-attachment-id="3124" data-permalink="/an-interview-with-shaded/3a2a5065-1/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3A2A5065-1.jpg?fit=5760%2C3840&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="5760,3840" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="3A2A5065-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3A2A5065-1.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3A2A5065-1.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-3124 size-full" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3A2A5065-1.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3A2A5065-1.jpg?w=5760&amp;ssl=1 5760w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3A2A5065-1.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3A2A5065-1.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3A2A5065-1.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3A2A5065-1.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/3A2A5065-1.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-3124" class="wp-caption-text">@ George Girvan Photography</p></div></p>
<p>Realistically, the EP is a pretty basic dive from the springboard of pop-punk, and its cheesy uninspired lyrics aren’t much to get excited about, but even from half a song you can tell that SHADED has talent. It’s like no band has really had the courage to tiptoe towards the pool since about 2011, and these guys have not only tried, they’ve definitely succeeded. It was simple, but they didn’t splash everyone, and after years of nothing I’m personally into this approach to a revival. So they’re not hitting Blink or Paramore’s records, but with execution marks like that, a bit more experience will see them onto the scoreboard. They’re musically gifted instrumentally and vocally, and not so punk that they’re going to scare away your little sister; I really hope for more music from SHADED. And this EP? Send it to the ex you’re pissed off at.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Hannah Mickleburgh</strong></p>
<p><strong>Photography by George Girvan (Instagram: <em><a href="https://www.instagram.com/georgegphoto/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@georgegphoto</a>; </em>Facebook: <em><a href="https://www.facebook.com/georgegirvanphotography" target="_blank" rel="noopener">George Girvan Photography</a></em>).</strong></p>
<div class="sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled"></div>
<p></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/good-enough-that-it-can-be-great-shadeds-a-familiar-love-ep/">Good Enough That It Can Be Great: SHADED&#8217;s ‘A Familiar Love’ EP</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/good-enough-that-it-can-be-great-shadeds-a-familiar-love-ep/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3225</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Concert: Paramore And Supporting Act mewithoutYou</title>
		<link>/concert-paramore-supporting-act-mewithoutyou/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=concert-paramore-supporting-act-mewithoutyou</link>
					<comments>/concert-paramore-supporting-act-mewithoutyou/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 18:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tennessee rock band Paramore has been on our playlists for as long as we can remember. Whether it’s bops such as ‘Misery Business’ that are buried deep on your ‘Old Bangers’ playlist, or new and fun material like ‘Hard Times’ from their 4th studio album After Laughter. Paramore certainly has been around for a while, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/concert-paramore-supporting-act-mewithoutyou/">In Concert: Paramore And Supporting Act mewithoutYou</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">Tennessee rock band <em>Paramore</em> has been on our playlists for as long as we can remember. Whether it’s bops such as ‘Misery Business’ that are buried deep on your ‘Old Bangers’ playlist, or new and fun material like ‘Hard Times’ from their 4<sup>th</sup> studio album <em>After Laughter</em>. <em>Paramore</em> certainly has been around for a while, but this hasn’t stopped them from putting on a show to remember.</p>
<p>On January 12, 2018, the three-piece band arrived at London’s O2 Arena with a bang. Crowds queued as early as the night before to secure a top spot at the front barriers inside the concert hall. The masses religiously donned <em>Paramore</em> merch ranging from canary yellow <em>Fake Happy</em> beanies to the trusted band shirt (I copped one myself). Looking at the types of folk around, one thing was evident: we all had a love for <em>Paramore</em> that was not only blazing with passion, it was a love and loyalty which had and could support the band through thick and thin.</p>
<p>The gig started with US band and supporting act <em>mewithoutYou</em>. It was obvious that not many had heard of them before- the concert hall was not yet at full capacity evidenced by a sea of empty seats in the upper galleries, a sign that fans were biding their time in order to arrive for <em>Paramore</em> and <em>Paramore</em> only. A handful of fans were rocking out and singing along to <em>mewithoutYou</em>, and rightly so. It was apparent why <em>Paramore</em> had chosen this band as their European support act, as they mirrored <em>Paramore</em> with their sombre lyrics and ecclesiastical themes throughout. The 45-minute set took us through a journey of powerful vocals, spoken word and some inventive (and interesting) singing and dancing styles by frontman Aaron Weiss. All in all, an interesting experience that left many of us with a newfound appreciation for <em>mewithoutYou</em>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2642" style="width: 918px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2642" data-attachment-id="2642" data-permalink="/concert-paramore-supporting-act-mewithoutyou/unnamed-1/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/unnamed-1.jpg?fit=908%2C513&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="908,513" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="unnamed (1)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/unnamed-1.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/unnamed-1.jpg?fit=908%2C513&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2642 size-full" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/unnamed-1.jpg?resize=908%2C513" alt="" width="908" height="513" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/unnamed-1.jpg?w=908&amp;ssl=1 908w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/unnamed-1.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 908px) 100vw, 908px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2642" class="wp-caption-text">mewithoutYou in O2 London &#8211; 12/01/2018 (via rocksound.tv)</p></div></p>
<p><em>Paramore </em>made their entry the only way <em>Paramore</em> knew how: with energy. The band kicked us off with <em>Ignorance</em> and ignited lonely hearts with <em>Still Into You</em>. <em>Forgiveness</em> struck a chord with many of us as it did on stage with <em>Paramore</em>. The story behind this melancholy number is one of heartache, disappointment and near-closure. <em>‘And you, you want forgiveness/but I, I just can’t do it yet/there’s still a thread that runs from your body to mine’</em> sings Williams. The lyrics are indicative of a tumultuous time during the band’s life as it neared a break up. Members were walking in and out, each time shaking the foundations of the band a little bit more. Williams addressed this halfway through the set, noting that without the fans’ unwavering support, they would not have managed to get through this journey of ups and downs, and ultimately growth. The band delighted us with <em>Fake Happy,</em> <em>That’s What You Get, Rose-Coloured Boy, Pool,</em> <em>Caught in the Middle</em> and <em>I Hate to See Your Heart Break</em>. <em>mewithoutYou’s</em> frontman Aaron Weiss made another appearance for <em>No Friend</em>, too. The stage theatricals and layout didn’t disappoint either. It was colourful when we had to put on our dancing shoes, and appropriately mellow when the song called for it.</p>
<p>Overall, <em>Paramore</em> delivered a show that so many of us had gingerly awaited whether it was our seventh or first time seeing them live. <em>After Laughter</em> is out now and can be streamed on all music platforms.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Naomy Kuma</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Donna Darafshian; featured image from <em>paramorenews.com</em>.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/concert-paramore-supporting-act-mewithoutyou/">In Concert: Paramore And Supporting Act mewithoutYou</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/concert-paramore-supporting-act-mewithoutyou/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2636</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Royal Blood Concert Review</title>
		<link>/royal-blood-concert-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=royal-blood-concert-review</link>
					<comments>/royal-blood-concert-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 17:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Missing Royal Blood’s concert in the U.K (due to exams) was a big deal for me- I was so excited to hear the two-member band live. When I moved to Barcelona for my year long placement I had no hope that I would see them play anytime soon, so you can imagine how enthusiastic I [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/royal-blood-concert-review/">Royal Blood Concert Review</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">Missing Royal Blood’s concert in the U.K (due to exams) was a big deal for me- I was so excited to hear the two-member band live. When I moved to Barcelona for my year long placement I had no hope that I would see them play anytime soon, so you can imagine how enthusiastic I felt when I heard they were coming to Barcelona in October.</p>
<p>It felt nerve-wracking during the actual live event, waiting for them to come on stage. However, Black Honey did a great job at leading up to the much-awaited moment. Black Honey revolve around a more indie/alternative style, accompanied by powerful female vocals. They still have strong rock notes lingering in their music and it all comes to blend beautifully together, with lead singer Izzy Baxter’s theatric stage presence, as well as her passionate and sultry vocals. The crowd seemed to enjoy their performance, but they were not as pumped, let’s say, as someone would expect them to be.</p>
<p>And then it was time for Royal Blood came on stage: You could tell from the excitement in the crowd, the shouting and screaming, that everyone was anticipating this moment (the atmosphere felt so much different compared to when Black Honey was playing).</p>
<p>The duo started off the night by playing ‘’How did we get so dark.” It is worth mentioning again that the band only consists of two people: Mike Kerr as a vocalist and bass player and Ben Thatcher playing the drums. The live performance had additional backing vocals, present in ‘’How Did We Get So Dark’’, in order to be able to translate the exact same sound as the pre-recorded audio.</p>
<p>All instrumentation was perfectly delivered on stage by the two-member band: a bass, drums, guitar, bass amps and a multi-effect pedal. One might wonder how so much energy can be translated to the crowd by only two people. That was certainly attained by Kerr’s way of approaching the crowd in the midst of song (even offering alcohol), as well as Thatcher’s drum solo in their well-loved &#8220;Little Monster&#8221; track.</p>
<p>There is something so simplistic about the type of music Royal Blood makes, as they prefer to stick to a similar sound throughout their albums, but this means that their sound and their lyrics, as well as Kerr’s way of singing, makes them who they are. It is refreshing to see such garage rock bands coming into the spotlight lately, to enhance the music scene.</p>
<p>Moreover, the duo did a great job at emitting the tension and complex feelings expressed in their songs and drag the audience into the different emotions sang by Kerr. Old favorites like ‘’Ten Tonne Skeleton’’, ‘’Out of the Black’’, as well as newest additions such as ‘’She’s Creeping’’ and ‘’Lights Out’’ saw the crowd signing along and enjoying the moment.</p>
<p>Repeated mixtures of bass and guitar, like sounds all attained by Kerr’s bass, the strong drum presence and an underlying pessimism and uncertainty present in their lyrics, describe the duo’s style. The performance ended by the band playing ‘’Out of the Black’’. Even though the song was played for a second time the crowd did not seem to mind that fact and gave their best sing-along energy for the last few minutes of the performance.</p>
<p>After watching them live, the only question for me remains to see what else they’re going to bring in the game: Is their style going to develop and change? Will they create a completely different sound? Will they stick to the music style we are used to and add more to it? All that remains is for us to wait and see. I certainly think this was a worthwhile experience, and I would definitely do it again &#8211; even though I had to wake up early for work the next day (a concert on Monday? Seriously my only complaint.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Elpida Komianou</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Juliey Pham; featured image from <em>song-bar.com</em>.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/royal-blood-concert-review/">Royal Blood Concert Review</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/royal-blood-concert-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2479</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Never Too Late to Remember: Nirvana’s MTV Unplugged in New York (1993)*</title>
		<link>/never-late-remember-nirvanas-mtv-unplugged-new-york-1993/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=never-late-remember-nirvanas-mtv-unplugged-new-york-1993</link>
					<comments>/never-late-remember-nirvanas-mtv-unplugged-new-york-1993/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 03:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>‘Fuck you all, this is the last song of the evening’… …and with this caustic phrase, Kurt Cobain introduces Nirvana’s cover of Lead Belly’s ‘Where Did You Sleep Last Night’. The audience laughs but remains fascinated. To some of us, watching these moments on YouTube is both distressing and bittersweet, since we know that the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/never-late-remember-nirvanas-mtv-unplugged-new-york-1993/">Never Too Late to Remember: Nirvana’s MTV Unplugged in New York (1993)*</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">‘Fuck you all, this is the last song of the evening’…</p>
<p>…and with this caustic phrase, Kurt Cobain introduces Nirvana’s cover of Lead Belly’s ‘Where Did You Sleep Last Night’. The audience laughs but remains fascinated. To some of us, watching these moments on YouTube is both distressing and bittersweet, since we know that the intense blue of Kurt’s eyes is now lost to eternity.</p>
<p>I believe that certain topics in music history are very difficult to examine, particularly when the legend overshadows the facts, or clichés threaten to completely engulf reality. The trajectory of Nirvana from the murky depths of grunge to rock stars is one such subject. It’s made even more problematic by the fact that, at a personal level, Cobain’s music had a powerful impact on my vision of the world and on how I relate to people. In a very strange way, his tormented life is on my mind again; a life that is emblematic of the artist as an uncompromising and frequently misunderstood individual. Cobain was, if anything, an absorbing paradox: simultaneously courting and rejecting stardom; tentatively welcoming his status as a spokesman for a whole generation of frustrated youngsters, but consciously attempting to shed his casual fans after <em>Nevermind </em>made Nirvana an unexpected success story of the alternative scene; a gifted songwriter whose personal issues eventually got the best of him; and last but not least, a figure fighting for indie credentials who was also in love with pop music.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Talking about <em>MTV Unplugged in New York</em> in 2017 is a challenging task, largely because of the almost automatic association with Cobain’s death in the spring of 1994. The bleak setting of this now-famous <em>Unplugged </em>session certainly didn’t make things any easier for those who attended it or watched it in their homes: the use of candles, red curtains and flowers had all the poignancy of a mock funeral, convincing people of the reality of Kurt’s mental instability and his depression; yet how many could have predicted that he would take his own life only a few months later? Perhaps it is the wrong question to ask. What is more important to me is to focus not on his passing, but on the beauty of his short existence as a guiding light which shone all too briefly, however painful that may seem in retrospect. The echoes of his suicide can still be heard, but I must press on.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If we stop and think about <em>MTV Unplugged in New York </em>simply as another step for Nirvana, it becomes quite clear that Kurt intended it as a concert which was meant to showcase his talents and his maturity in an unadulterated fashion, away from the distortion and noise of <em>In Utero</em> or the punky catchiness of <em>Nevermind</em>. The arrangements are stripped down, and the acoustic versions of compositions like ‘About a Girl’, ‘Come as You Are’ or ‘On a Plain’ are typically much more haunting than anything on the original records because the textures do a wonderful job of emphasizing Cobain’s sombre lyrics and hopelessness. Between songs, Kurt jokes around and taunts the audience, although a pervasive feeling of sadness can be extracted from the tone of his voice. Scruffily dressed, he maintains a high degree of sobriety and witty cynicism, but occasionally he appears to be lost in deep thought, as if nothing could contain his anguish.</p>
<p>Against all expectations, the core of <em>MTV Unplugged in New York </em>is represented by the six covers that Nirvana selected to play, as well as a conspicuous lack of major hits. The covers say more about Kurt and his passions than his own creative output, as the choices forcefully reflect his appreciation for numerous other artists which were mentioned many times in interviews. The renditions of Meat Puppets’ ‘Plateau’, ‘Oh, Me’, and ‘Lake of Fire’, guest starring band members Curt and Cris Kirkwood, are nothing short of bewitching; the pensive lament of ‘The Man Who Sold the World’, originally a David Bowie track, is so consuming and heart-wrenching that it’s hard not to get teary-eyed; on The Vaselines’ ‘Jesus Doesn’t Want Me for a Sunbeam’, the spectres of self-loathing and religious scepticism hang above every chord; lastly, ‘Where Did You Sleep Last Night’ is possibly Nirvana’s most memorable live performance, with Cobain’s tortured vocals and eerie stare enduring to this very day.</p>
<p>To quote music critic Robert Christgau, ‘Not only did Kurt Cobain transcend alt-rock by rocking so hard, he transcended alt-rock by feeling so deep’ [1]. If <em>Bleach</em>, <em>Nevermind</em>, and <em>In Utero</em> are mostly about rocking, then this album is all about Kurt Cobain’s honesty, vulnerability, and sensitive spirit. <em>MTV Unplugged in New York</em> is an inadvertent self-epitaph to a beautiful soul who was, in many ways, too real for this world and too troubled to overcome his suffering, and nowhere else is he as brutally genuine and as exposed as he is here. Only one other <em>Unplugged </em>session manages to connect with me so intimately, and that is Alice in Chains’ concert of 1996. The fact that Kurt is no longer with us, of course, makes the record unbearably hard to listen to, these lines hard to write, and my evaluation nearly impossible to dissociate from his harrowing absence – after all, we are only human and we tend to get carried away by emotions and irrationality. Maybe his death is all the more reason to remember Nirvana and to quietly celebrate Kurt’s amazing life and the purifying nature of his music.</p>
<p>‘We passed upon the stair’…</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>10/10</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*Note: <em>MTV Unplugged in New York</em> was recorded and aired on cable television in late 1993. After Cobain’s death, it was released as an album in November 1994.</p>
<p>References:</p>
<p>[1] <a href="https://www.robertchristgau.com/get_album.php?id=2588">https://www.robertchristgau.com/get_album.php?id=2588</a>, accessed 5 May 2017.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Track Listing:</p>
<ol>
<li>About a Girl</li>
<li>Come as You Are</li>
<li>Jesus Doesn’t Want Me for a Sunbeam</li>
<li>The Man Who Sold the World</li>
<li>Pennyroyal Tea</li>
<li>Dumb</li>
<li>Polly</li>
<li>On a Plain</li>
<li>Something in the Way</li>
<li>Plateau</li>
<li>Oh, Me</li>
<li>Lake of Fire</li>
<li>All Apologies</li>
<li>Where Did You Sleep Last Night</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Vlad Nicu</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Juliey Pham; featured image from <em>jackseattle.cbslocal.com</em>.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/never-late-remember-nirvanas-mtv-unplugged-new-york-1993/">Never Too Late to Remember: Nirvana’s MTV Unplugged in New York (1993)*</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/never-late-remember-nirvanas-mtv-unplugged-new-york-1993/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2231</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Community Festival</title>
		<link>/community-festival/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=community-festival</link>
					<comments>/community-festival/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 16:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There’s something about festival’s which really encompasses that warm summer feeling. Maybe it’s the music or the pitcher of pims or, just maybe, it’s the perfect combination of music, booze and sunshine. Even though it was the last weekend of summer I had before starting a 12 month work placement, Community Festival really felt like [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/community-festival/">Community Festival</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">There’s something about festival’s which really encompasses that warm summer feeling. Maybe it’s the music or the pitcher of pims or, just maybe, it’s the perfect combination of music, booze and sunshine. Even though it was the last weekend of summer I had before starting a 12 month work placement, Community Festival really felt like the start of summer.</p>
<p>For those of you who don’t know, Community Fest is a one-day festival that takes place in Finsbury Park. This year <em>Catfish &amp; The Bottlemen</em>, <em>The Wombats</em>, <em>Slaves and Nothing But Thieves</em> performed on main stage, alongside a second, smaller stage.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2208" data-permalink="/20616057_1656305087736896_13176853_o/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20616057_1656305087736896_13176853_o.jpg?fit=2048%2C1536&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2048,1536" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="20616057_1656305087736896_13176853_o" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20616057_1656305087736896_13176853_o.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20616057_1656305087736896_13176853_o.jpg?fit=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2208" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20616057_1656305087736896_13176853_o.jpg?resize=1200%2C900" alt="20616057_1656305087736896_13176853_o" width="1200" height="900" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20616057_1656305087736896_13176853_o.jpg?w=2048&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20616057_1656305087736896_13176853_o.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20616057_1656305087736896_13176853_o.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>We arrived in true festival gear with blue eyeliner, crop tops, ‘John Lennon’ sunglasses, and a bumbag to the sound of <em>The Hunna</em>. The first thing I felt was surprise, I was impressed by how much bigger the festival was than I thought it would be. There were people everywhere and so many bars and food carts; it was literally as if you stepped into a festival that had been in full swing for a couple of days. However, as I think about it now, I can understand why it was so popular, the lineup was incredible and tickets were only £35. Although, it was obvious that Community would make a huge profit from their bar from the prices of their pints, I’ll tell you that much.</p>
<p><em>Nothing But Thieves</em> was the first full act we saw and it was a great way to set the atmosphere. The crowd were friendly, everyone was having a great time singing along to their biggest tunes with either a beer or cider in hand. With their guitar-based indie rock, it created the perfect vibe for a musice festival, <em>Nothing But Thieves</em> are a band for the grown-up emo kids out there and everyone was loving it.</p>
<p>However, when <em>Slaves </em>took the stage one questionably eloquent description of the set could be that they sounded like glorified pub singers. I remember seeing them at Reading Festival in 2015, and I thought at the time they were really great. However, after seeing that most recent performance? I’m questioning my logic as to why I thought that originally, maybe it was the negative influence of alcohol at the time. Either way, I wasn’t overly impressed by their set – I’m sure this would be very popular for many, but not for me. I, on the otherhand couldn’t wait for <em>The Wombats</em> to come on stage.</p>
<p><em>The Wombats</em> are a band that I’ve loved for a long time, they&#8217;re a great throwback band; there’s so many people that have loved them, drifted away, and come back again when they’ve heard they’re playing a festival. I’ve seen them once before, but I must admit it wasn’t the best from where I was standing previously, we were at the very back at one of the smallest tents there (the Festival Republic tent for those of you who are familiar). Having seen them live again, I have very mixed feelings. Their choice of hits to perform were incredible, but the crowd was incredibly wild for next to no reason. It still remains a mystery to me as to why the crowd were so adamant on moshing to the <em>The Wombats</em>. Aside from that however, they are a great band to see live; they really know how to put on a performance and keep their crowd happy.</p>
<p>Moving on to the final band of the night, <em>Catfish and The Bottlemen</em>, it’s very tricky to describe exactly just how happy I felt seeing them live once again. I’ve seen them once before, again at Reading festival, but I feel they have really matured and come into their own since I last saw them. The music was phenomenal and the atmosphere was amazing. Everyone had relaxed and chilled a lot more since <em>The Wombats</em> gig, maybe it was the joint opinion that everyone in the crowd had sucked previously, or maybe it was the fact that the band are incredible to see live. They played the perfect mixture of songs from ‘The Balcony’ and ‘The Ride’, making it the perfect set as the sun went down on the festival.<img data-attachment-id="2209" data-permalink="/20622803_1656305024403569_1616587972_o/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20622803_1656305024403569_1616587972_o.jpg?fit=2048%2C1536&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2048,1536" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="20622803_1656305024403569_1616587972_o" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20622803_1656305024403569_1616587972_o.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20622803_1656305024403569_1616587972_o.jpg?fit=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2209" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20622803_1656305024403569_1616587972_o.jpg?resize=1200%2C900" alt="20622803_1656305024403569_1616587972_o" width="1200" height="900" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20622803_1656305024403569_1616587972_o.jpg?w=2048&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20622803_1656305024403569_1616587972_o.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20622803_1656305024403569_1616587972_o.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>We left the day with the true feeling of a festival; a bit drunk, tired from running away from mosh pits (sometimes unsuccessfully), and feeling a bit grimey from the amount of others people&#8217;s’ sweat you just <em>knew </em>you had on your clothes, not to mention the spilt beer. But this is a festival that I will keep my eye out for again; it really captures that festival experience, simply without the element where you haven’t showered in 4 days.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2207" data-permalink="/20629264_1656305091070229_173342696_o/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20629264_1656305091070229_173342696_o.jpg?fit=2048%2C1536&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2048,1536" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="20629264_1656305091070229_173342696_o" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20629264_1656305091070229_173342696_o.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20629264_1656305091070229_173342696_o.jpg?fit=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2207" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20629264_1656305091070229_173342696_o.jpg?resize=1200%2C900" alt="20629264_1656305091070229_173342696_o" width="1200" height="900" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20629264_1656305091070229_173342696_o.jpg?w=2048&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20629264_1656305091070229_173342696_o.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/20629264_1656305091070229_173342696_o.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text and photography by Olivia Mitchell.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/community-festival/">Community Festival</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/community-festival/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2214</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mos Def &#038; Talib Kweli Are Black Star: Why It Still Matters</title>
		<link>/mos-def-talib-kweli-black-star-still-matters/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=mos-def-talib-kweli-black-star-still-matters</link>
					<comments>/mos-def-talib-kweli-black-star-still-matters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 17:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>My narrative rose to explain this existence Amidst the harbor lights which remain in the distance Mos Def &#160; Through a historical perspective on black culture we can interpret rap music as the culmination of a century-long attempt to define, articulate, and express the consciousness of the Afro-diasporic community in the United States. On the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/mos-def-talib-kweli-black-star-still-matters/">Mos Def &#038; Talib Kweli Are Black Star: Why It Still Matters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody"><em>My narrative rose to explain this existence</em></p>
<p><em>Amidst the harbor lights which remain in the distance</em></p>
<p>Mos Def</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Through a historical perspective on black culture we can interpret rap music as the culmination of a century-long attempt to define, articulate, and express the consciousness of the Afro-diasporic community in the United States. On the long continuum which began with the blues in the rural South and expanded to urban America with jazz, R&amp;B, rock ‘n’ roll, soul, and funk, rap is the most recent cultural destination of a politically and socially active ethnic community, ‘a direct extension of African-American oral, poetic and protest traditions’ [1]. In a space characterized, both in the past and in the present, by racism, institutional discrimination, structural inequality, chronic poverty, police brutality, and ghettoization, rap artists urge us to listen and think about many things at once; why these things happen, how we can address them, how we can overcome the suffering they cause, and what is to be done in order to turn that suffering into something positive and inspiring.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The 1998 release of <em>Mos Def &amp; Talib Kweli Are Black Star</em> concurred with a period, which revealed the senselessness and ugliness of violence in inner city America like never before. The deaths of Tupac and Biggie in 1996 and 1997 showed how the escalation of gang conflicts and rivalries could affect even the biggest and most beloved of artists. The stigma, which followed the killings, intensified the portrayal of young black men as threats to the social order. Unable to fight against the system on an equal footing, African-Americans turned to the weapon which Pac and Biggie believed in: music.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Along with The Roots’ <em>Things Fall Apart</em>, this record is the underground sound of a culture turning the spotlight on itself, critically re-evaluating its origins and its position in the wider world with a quiet, contemplative, almost grassroots spirituality. The two talented MCs, both at the beginning of their careers, are infused with a restrained but ultimately invigorating anger that condemns the hypocrisy, prejudices and injustices of white society, but also projects positivity, hope, and a desire for freedom. The duo’s name, Black Star, is a clever triple entendre: firstly, it relates to the shipping line of the same name created by Pan-Africanist Marcus Garvey at the beginning of the 20<sup>th</sup> century; secondly, it makes reference to the emcees themselves as ‘stars’, as public figures who create counter-hegemonic discourses and empower their own people; lastly, the ‘black star’ is a beautiful metaphor for the whole community, an organic social body that shines and redeems itself with the help of its leading voices. All of these things add up to the image of African-Americans as strong, resilient and motivated to continue fighting for their rights in the name of a higher principle.</p>
<p>Against a backdrop of superb jazzy beats that subtly indicate the continuity between distinct aspects of black culture, Mos Def and Talib Kweli’s verbal technique and intellectual flair resulted in some of the finest rhymes ever committed to tape. On ‘Definition’, they fondly remember the slain rappers mentioned above, grimly reflecting on a cultural space stained by violence:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>One, two, three                                                                                </em></p>
<p><em>Mos Def and Talib Kweli</em></p>
<p><em>We came to rock it on to the tip-top</em></p>
<p><em>Best alliance in hip-hop, Y-O</em></p>
<p><em>I said one, two, three</em></p>
<p><em>It&#8217;s kind of dangerous to be an MC</em></p>
<p><em>They shot 2Pac and Biggie</em></p>
<p><em>Too much violence in hip-hop, Y-O</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>On ‘Respiration’, the tainted urban landscape of New York appears ruthless, immoral. Despite the lie of the American dream, people somehow manage to survive:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>[<em>Mos Def]:</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Thirsty criminals take pockets</em></p>
<p><em>Hard knuckles on the second hands of working class watches</em></p>
<p><em>Skyscrapers is colossus, the cost of living is preposterous</em></p>
<p><em>Stay alive, you play or die, no options, no Batman and Robin</em></p>
<p><em>Can&#8217;t tell between the cops and the robbers, they both partners, they all heartless</em></p>
<p><em>With no conscience, back streets stay darkened</em></p>
<p><em>Where unbeliever hearts stay hardened</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em>[Talib Kweli]:</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em>Breathin’ in deep city breaths, sittin’ on shitty steps</em></p>
<p><em>We stoop to new lows, hell froze the night the city slept</em></p>
<p><em>[…]</em></p>
<p><em>Look in the skies for God, what you see besides the smog</em></p>
<p><em>Is broken dreams flying away on the wings of the obscene</em></p>
<p><em>Thoughts that people put in the air</em></p>
<p><em>Places where you could get murdered over a glare </em></p>
<p><em>But everything is fair</em></p>
<p><em>It&#8217;s a paradox we call reality</em></p>
<p><em>So keepin’ it real will make you a casualty of abnormal normality</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>At the same time, the album is about reclaiming the lost heritage of a community which is historically united by hardship and misery, but politically neutered and divided in a contemporary context by the structural constraints imposed by whites. This idea is exposed in ‘Thieves in the Night’:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>[Mos Def]:</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em>Not strong, only aggressive cause the power ain&#8217;t directed</em></p>
<p><em>That&#8217;s why we are subjected to the will of the oppressive</em></p>
<p><em>Not free, we only licensed, not live, we just exciting</em></p>
<p><em>Cause the captors own the masters to what we writing</em></p>
<p><em>Not compassionate, only polite, we well trained</em></p>
<p><em>Our sincerity&#8217;s rehearsed in stage, it&#8217;s just a game</em></p>
<p><em>Not good, but well behaved cause the camera survey</em></p>
<p><em>Most of the things that we think, do or say</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The complex history of racial oppression in the United States is ironically nearly always marked by the pervasive interest of whites in the aggressive insubordination of black culture, beginning with the appropriation of blues and rock and ending with the intense marketization and re-packaging of rap. In view of extensive corporate control over the content and distribution of music in the 21<sup>st</sup> century, it is increasingly difficult to find good rap music that continues to be critical of the sad realities of Western societies; yet now, more than ever, the disenfranchised and the desperate need voices that talk about the struggle against an overbearing establishment.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Throughout its long journey, rap has surmounted its local, ethnically-centred appeal, becoming a ubiquitous rallying call in favour of resistance against domination. As ‘The Man’ becomes more powerful, our will and ability to speak against him must grow accordingly. This 19-year-old gem, a work of authentic and impassioned street poetry, reminds us that the battle is not over; on the contrary, we should vigorously renew our commitment to equality, justice, human dignity, and a better future for everyone.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Ten Black Stars.</p>
<p>[1] Tricia Rose, Black noise: Rap music and black culture in contemporary America, p.25.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Vlad Nicu</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Donna Darafshian; featured image taken from <em>hiphopdx.com</em>.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/mos-def-talib-kweli-black-star-still-matters/">Mos Def &#038; Talib Kweli Are Black Star: Why It Still Matters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/mos-def-talib-kweli-black-star-still-matters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shiny Boots of Leather: The Velvet Underground &#038; Nico 50 Years Later</title>
		<link>/shiny-boots-leather-velvet-underground-nico-50-years-later/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=shiny-boots-leather-velvet-underground-nico-50-years-later</link>
					<comments>/shiny-boots-leather-velvet-underground-nico-50-years-later/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 17:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As I finish writing this piece, The Velvet Underground &#38; Nico is turning 50, a respectable age for a rock record by any standard. Of course, it’s crucial to remember that 1967 wasn’t just any year – it represented the apex of a decade which transformed political, social, and cultural issues into a unifying whole, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/shiny-boots-leather-velvet-underground-nico-50-years-later/">Shiny Boots of Leather: The Velvet Underground &#038; Nico 50 Years Later</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">As I finish writing this piece, <em>The Velvet Underground &amp; Nico</em> is turning 50, a respectable age for a rock record by any standard. Of course, it’s crucial to remember that 1967 wasn’t just any year – it represented the apex of a decade which transformed political, social, and cultural issues into a unifying whole, conjuring up images of the hippie movement, the Summer of Love, and of unbound hope for the future of humanity.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Among the great albums of the era, <em>The Velvet Underground &amp; Nico </em>is sometimes given only a brief mention; either because of the insane creative explosion which defined 1967 (<em>Sgt. Pepper</em>, <em>The Doors</em>, <em>Are You Experienced?</em>,<em> The Piper at the Gates of Dawn</em>), or due to the fundamentally alien nature of The Velvet Underground’s music in that particular context. Going against the general optimism of the Summer of Love, this debut seemed painfully unusual: abrasive, noisy, nihilistic, guided by avant-garde, dealing with subjects which were considered taboo at that time: drug consumption, sexual deviance, prostitution, death, dark fantasies, and the degeneration of urban life. If anything, it’s closer in spirit to the ‘accursed poets’ of nineteenth century France: Baudelaire, Rimbaud, Verlaine, or Mallarmé. The world of Lou Reed and John Cale’s songs is populated by the ‘scum of the earth’, the undesirables, people who live at the fringes of society, struggling with marginalization, addiction, or social stigma.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Reed’s gritty urban realism, combined with a celebratory, bohemian stance on decadence and hedonism, is as fresh and as enlightening as it was five decades ago. In the garage stomp of ‘I’m Waiting for the Man’, we have the story of a New York heroin user trying to find his dealer for a hit, sung by Reed in a dispassionate voice, as if it was the most normal thing one could do or see inside a large city. On the epic ‘Heroin’, speaking to us once again from a first-person perspective, he decides not to take any sides, leaving it up to us to judge the moral implications of consuming hard drugs. Perhaps the addict is, after all, as guilty as anyone else; a reflection of the faults and sins of normative society. He is aware of his problems but is unwilling or unable to give them much thought…</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Heroin, be the death of me</em></p>
<p><em>Heroin, it&#8217;s my wife and it&#8217;s my life</em></p>
<p><em> […]</em></p>
<p><em>&#8216;Cause when the smack begins to flow</em></p>
<p><em>And I really don&#8217;t care anymore</em></p>
<p><em>[…]</em></p>
<p><em>And I guess I just don&#8217;t know</em></p>
<p><em>Oh, and I guess I just don&#8217;t know</em></p>
<p><em>            </em></p>
<p><em> </em>‘Venus in Furs’, a delightfully perverse tale of sadomasochism based on the eponymous novella, is a singular experience, the first instance of a song explicitly about BDSM, and one of the band’s defining moments. Structured around a relentless tribal rhythm and Cale’s Eastern-tinged, droning viola, it describes an affair between a weak-willed man named Severin and a domineering female, identified only by the metaphor of Venus as the incarnation of physical pleasure and seduction. Of rare poetic quality, the lyrics depict reversed power relationships, emasculation, and debauchery with impressive vitality:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Shiny, shiny, shiny boots of leather</em></p>
<p><em>Whiplash girl child in the dark</em></p>
<p><em>Comes in bells, your servant, don&#8217;t forsake him</em></p>
<p><em>Strike, dear mistress, and cure his heart!</em></p>
<p><em>[…]</em></p>
<p><em>Severin, Severin, speak so slightly</em></p>
<p><em>Severin, down on your bended knee</em></p>
<p><em>Taste the whip, in love not given lightly</em></p>
<p><em>Taste the whip, now bleed for me!</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Velvets never managed to have a major commercial breakthrough – in fact, this record is their highest charting studio release, and it barely cracked the Billboard 200. Arguably, the wider public was simply not ready for these audacious explorations into the human psyche, or the chaos that they unleashed. However, their immense influence cannot be measured by sales, but by their uncompromising attitude, their artistic integrity, the literary character of their compositions and their perfect blend of emotion and intellectual refinement. Today, it is difficult to imagine what rock would have sounded like without them, and their innovations are watersheds for every radical branch of the genre that followed, from left-wing punk to extreme forms of experimental rock. At the risk of repeating what has been said so many times, it’s necessary to emphasize their position with the following aphorism: of the few people who originally bought <em>The Velvet Underground &amp; Nico</em>, every one of them started a band of their own. Over the years, their cult grew, slowly but surely, and they became more of a myth than an actual musical entity.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Without the patronage and assistance of Andy Warhol, it’s likely that the Velvets would have remained a footnote in rock history, relegated to playing in bars in front of extremely small audiences. Yet Warhol discovered them and had complete faith in their abilities as musicians and songwriters, financing the production of <em>The Velvet Underground &amp; Nico </em>and even designing the now-famous banana cover. With the addition of German chanteuse Nico as a guest member, the band complemented its fiery examinations into forbidden pleasures with an icy, nearly frigid detachment (‘Femme Fatale’, ‘All Tomorrow’s Parties’, ‘I’ll Be Your Mirror’). After falling out with both Warhol and Nico, The Velvet Underground carved out a brilliant and diverse career, from noise freak-outs and spoken word (<em>White Light/White Heat</em>) to more conventional folk rock and garage rock (<em>The Velvet Underground, Loaded</em>). Each one of those records is a fantastic addition to any collection, but they never again reached the same dizzying heights as they did here – it is <em>the</em> starting point for any understanding of rock as an exceptionally confrontational mode of expression.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Naturally, times have changed. In a society in which discussions about sexuality and drugs are no longer as controversial, some would cast doubt on the current relevance of this record. <em>The Velvet Underground &amp; Nico</em>, for all its excesses, is actually quite approachable; but like fine wine, it only gets better with age, thanks to the universality of its topics and the dramatic performances. By treating important and difficult issues without providing definitive answers, the Velvets placed themselves ahead of their time, crushing the flowers of the hippie revolution and offering a glimpse into the darkness of the soul, into a profane and deeply disturbing universe. Their music endures unaffected, bursting with cerebral energy and emotional intensity in equal measure. The recent, unfortunate passing of Lou Reed coincides with a period of renewed and well-deserved attention given to their discography, and this LP certainly is the jewel in the crown. File under ‘essential listening’ and don’t forget to ‘Peel Slowly and See’.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>10/10</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Track Listing:</p>
<ol>
<li>Sunday Morning</li>
<li>I’m Waiting for the Man</li>
<li>Femme Fatale</li>
<li>Venus in Furs</li>
<li>Run Run Run</li>
<li>All Tomorrow’s Parties</li>
<li>Heroin</li>
<li>There She Goes Again</li>
<li>I’ll Be Your Mirror</li>
<li>The Black Angel’s Death Song</li>
<li>European Son</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Vlad Nicu</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Donna Darafshian; featured image taken from <em>fatbeats.com</em>.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/shiny-boots-leather-velvet-underground-nico-50-years-later/">Shiny Boots of Leather: The Velvet Underground &#038; Nico 50 Years Later</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/shiny-boots-leather-velvet-underground-nico-50-years-later/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Romantic Ideal Revisited: My Bloody Valentine&#8217;s Loveless</title>
		<link>/romantic-ideal-revisited-bloody-valentines-loveless/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=romantic-ideal-revisited-bloody-valentines-loveless</link>
					<comments>/romantic-ideal-revisited-bloody-valentines-loveless/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 17:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Turn Your head Come back again To here knows when… &#160; In his analysis of the great artistic movements, literary critic Anatoly Liberman writes: ‘Romanticism in its philosophical aspect is a victory of beauty and grandeur over ugliness and filth. It is a longing for the ideal and a superhuman attempt to find it’ [1]. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/romantic-ideal-revisited-bloody-valentines-loveless/">The Romantic Ideal Revisited: My Bloody Valentine&#8217;s Loveless</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Turn</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Your head</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Come back again</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>To here knows when… </em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In his analysis of the great artistic movements, literary critic Anatoly Liberman writes: ‘Romanticism in its philosophical aspect is a victory of beauty and grandeur over ugliness and filth. It is a longing for the ideal and a superhuman attempt to find it’ [1].</p>
<p>From this perspective, it is perhaps surprising to judge My Bloody Valentine’s <em>Loveless</em> as a musical work about the romantic ideal. Released in 1991 at the critical and commercial peak of the shoegaze scene, <em>Loveless</em> owes its uniqueness to the far-reaching vision of frontman and eccentric genius Kevin Shields. Aside from pioneering techniques such as glide guitar or expanding rock’s sonic palette through the extensive use of alternate tunings and feedback, on <em>Loveless</em>, Shields perfected what he began with <em>Isn’t Anything </em>in 1988: the articulation of a new concept of love that discards notions like conventional gender roles, simple romantic attachment, happiness, or heartbreak. His is a psychoanalytic interpretation of love as pure desire and as burgeoning, occasionally frightening, sexuality. Between its incorporation of noise as a source of aesthetic pleasure in the style of Sonic Youth and the subtle display of human frailty borrowed from the dream pop of Cocteau Twins, the record is an archetype of the postmodern collage: songs flow into one another, drowned in distorted guitar riffs, seemingly having no beginning and no end; the lyrical voice, straddling the masculinity-femininity border, tries to reach out for something which is only hinted at, but never grasped. Referring to the album’s closing track, ‘Soon’, ambient musician Brian Eno remarked with admiration: ‘It set a new standard for pop. It&#8217;s the vaguest music ever to have been a hit’ [2].</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Without falling into the predictable pattern of weaving straightforward stories about a boy and a girl, the songwriting presents disembodied, quasi-androgynous subjects that would rather fantasize about a distant, secret lover than search for fulfilment in reality. In ‘Blown a Wish’, mystique and illusion have indisputable appeal, as Shields’ fellow guitarist and one-time partner Bilinda Butcher whispers: ‘Midnight wish/Blow me a kiss/I&#8217;ll blow one to you/Make like this/Try to pretend it&#8217;s true’. In some cases, the reality/fantasy separation appears as a blur; on ‘When You Sleep’, Shields and Butcher sing in a barely comprehensible manner: ‘When I look at you/Oh, I don’t know what’s real’. As the buried vocals and cryptic lyrics turn into layers of a neo-psychedelic soundscape, <em>Loveless</em> begins to address our innermost cravings in ambiguous ways, and it is here that the connection with psychoanalysis is made clear. By way of Lacanian theory, the person worthy of our attention perpetually remains outside of our reach; yet paradoxically, the impossibility of possessing the loved one fuels the sexual fascination to new heights – desire becomes a purpose in itself. Driven by an oceanic three-chord progression, the opener ‘Only Shallow’ is a perfect example of this approach; at first, Butcher playfully encourages the listener to touch some unnamed female subject ‘there’ (never specifying where ‘there’ might actually be), later confronting us with emptiness, futility, and loneliness (‘Look/In the mirror/She’s not there’) before the aurally blissful instrumental coda finally announces the triumph of the mirage.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The power and visceral impact of the music are found not in the climax of feeling complete by achieving romantic goals, but in the phantasm of the Other, in the self-sustaining cycle of lust, imagination, and obsession. This means that any previous understanding of the ideal is shattered, as there is no place for classical beauty and grandeur in Shields’ world, just like there is no ugliness or filth. <em>Loveless</em> deconstructs the romanticism of old and reconstructs it into a dreamlike dimension beyond time and space where passion and sensuality reign supreme; where direct sensory experiences like seeing, hearing and touching are suspended in the realm of fantasy; where noble and selfless love gives way to infatuation or even narcissism; where the greatest transgressions are indifference and cold rationality. For such a dynamic album, though, the lost souls of Shields’ songs are exceptionally static, caught in a trance or in a state of endless waiting, as if they could drift through life while things are happening around them. On ‘Sometimes’, for instance, Shields’ vocals barely break through the lush arrangements, inviting the mysterious object of his adoration to connect with him, but being aware of the inevitable failure in establishing meaningful contact: ‘Close my eyes/Feel me now/I don&#8217;t know, maybe you could not hurt me now/Here alone, when I feel down too/Over there, when I await true love for you’.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Loveless</em> is a masterpiece of affective catharsis, a slice of self-indulgent experimental music which pushes the limits of implicit eroticism without ever slipping into vulgarity. It conveys joy, ecstasy, and liberation through what is hidden and what is repressed in the unconscious mind, transcending the confines of aesthetic tradition and asserting itself as a radical artistic statement. If the ‘superhuman attempt’ of nineteenth century romanticism requires exceptional individuals, then My Bloody Valentine argue for the reverse: it is within anyone’s reach to create beauty by appealing to two very basic elements of human nature – imagination and sexual drive. In retrospect, we have to wonder why a record characterized by intimacy and sensibility was called <em>Loveless </em>in the first place. One explanation is that it is a description of the emotional distance between Shields and Butcher during the recording sessions, when their stormy relationship was falling apart; another alludes to the lack of resolution and reciprocity in the narratives, as the protagonists give but do not receive; fantasize, but are not fantasized about, therefore remaining ‘loveless’.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Whichever answer seems more appropriate, one thing is certain: the sonic and conceptual innovations of <em>Loveless </em>must be heard to be believed, as words can only go so far in explaining what it’s all about. After an initial shock, it gently draws you in and refuses to let go. Despite the loud guitars and persistent use of reverb, the album is frequently evocative, ethereal, immersive and warm, due in no small part to Shields’ strong sense of melody and the hypnotic harmonies. It’s an excellent introduction to the discography of one of the most unique bands in the history of rock, and one of the few great records of the genre whose intricacies truly reveal something new with every listen. Considering its thematic richness and its emphasis on ambiguity, it demands patience and open-mindedness in order to be fully appreciated; but what it offers in return is worth the price of admission: an insightful and profoundly different way of looking at love.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Track Listing:</p>
<ol>
<li>Only Shallow</li>
<li>Loomer</li>
<li>Touched</li>
<li>To Here Knows When</li>
<li>When You Sleep</li>
<li>I Only Said</li>
<li>Come In Alone</li>
<li>Sometimes</li>
<li>Blown a Wish</li>
<li>What You Want</li>
<li>Soon</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">References</span></p>
<p>[1] Anatoly Liberman (ed.), <em>Mikhail Lermontov: Major Poetical Works</em>, p. 20.</p>
<p>[2] <a href="http://www.tohereknowswhen.org/">http://www.tohereknowswhen.org/</a>, accessed 5 March 2017.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Vlad Nicu</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Juliey Pham; featured image taken from <em>genius.com.</em></strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/romantic-ideal-revisited-bloody-valentines-loveless/">The Romantic Ideal Revisited: My Bloody Valentine&#8217;s Loveless</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/romantic-ideal-revisited-bloody-valentines-loveless/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2067</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
