<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Beauty &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/beauty/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A fashion, culture, art and music publication, written by students about students.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 18:49:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/cropped-12773305_10206631248554054_481252708_o.jpg?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Beauty &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107671177</site>	<item>
		<title>The Four Make-Up Tips and Tricks that Make-Up Artists Aren’t Telling You About</title>
		<link>/the-four-make-up-tips-and-tricks-that-make-up-artists-arent-telling-you-about/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-four-make-up-tips-and-tricks-that-make-up-artists-arent-telling-you-about</link>
					<comments>/the-four-make-up-tips-and-tricks-that-make-up-artists-arent-telling-you-about/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 17:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Beauty is having a moment. Yes, beauty and make-up have always been a hot topic but with the rising boom of social media, we have more resources and information on how to do our own make-up than ever before. Instagram and YouTube are filled to the brim with tutorials on the wackiest, outlandish eye-shadow looks, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-four-make-up-tips-and-tricks-that-make-up-artists-arent-telling-you-about/">The Four Make-Up Tips and Tricks that Make-Up Artists Aren’t Telling You About</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>Beauty is having a moment. Yes, beauty and make-up have
always been a hot topic but with the rising boom of social media, we have more
resources and information on how to do our own make-up than ever before.
Instagram and YouTube are filled to the brim with tutorials on the wackiest,
outlandish eye-shadow looks, the most airbrushed base make-up and everything in
between. So, that begs the question: what tips and tricks <em>don’t</em> we know about? What techniques are make-up artists keeping
secret?</p>



<p><strong>Sharpening Up </strong></p>



<p>Despite having an odd-sounding name, <em>tightlining</em> is a technique that can really enhance your eye
make-up.&nbsp; The waterline is the technical
name for the rim of skin between your eyelashes and your eyeball.&nbsp; <em>Tightlining</em>
involves taking an eye pencil and smoking out that border on your eyelid; just
underneath the upper lash-line.&nbsp; This can
make your lashes appear thicker and fuller, as well as defining the shape of
your eye just that little bit more. </p>



<p><strong>The Colour Wheel</strong></p>



<p>Using colours to your advantage when it comes to make-up is
useful in so many ways.&nbsp; The rule of
thumb is that opposites attract.&nbsp; When it
comes to eyeshadow, if you have blue eyes, gold and orange shades and shimmers
are the way to go.&nbsp; Green eyes will pop
with burgundies and deep berry shades, whilst brown-eyed guys and girls are
lucky; pretty much any colour will look flattering on you!</p>



<p><strong>Blot It Out </strong></p>



<p>Ever applied your lipstick perfectly to find that mid-way
through the day, it has smudged to the point of looking like you only have
lip-liner on? There’s a trick for that. Apply one layer of lipstick and then
blot it on a piece of tissue. Then, with a fluffy brush, apply one layer of
powder, reapply another layer of lipstick and blot again. This technique will
not only make your lipstick last a lot longer, but will actually make it look a
lot more pigmented and vibrant. </p>



<p><strong>A Hairy Affair </strong></p>



<p>Hair-lining involves taking your contour right up into your
hairline on either side of your face.&nbsp;
It’s tricky to clean off at the end of the day. Sure. But taking your
brush and sweeping the product into the hairline itself under your cheekbone
will enhance your facial structure much more. This works for both powder and
cream contours and helps them look more seamlessly blended in with the natural
bone structure of your face.&nbsp; </p>



<p>So, there you have it, the four tips that make-up artists have not been telling you about. Let it be known that using these tips will sky rocket your make up skills straight to a professional level. Whether it be uploads for the gram, a job interview or date night, keep these tips in mind to achieve a flawless look.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Nathalie Egerton Gable<br>Featured image from <em>shopify.com</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-four-make-up-tips-and-tricks-that-make-up-artists-arent-telling-you-about/">The Four Make-Up Tips and Tricks that Make-Up Artists Aren’t Telling You About</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-four-make-up-tips-and-tricks-that-make-up-artists-arent-telling-you-about/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3947</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What You Really Need To Know About Makeup Expiration Dates</title>
		<link>/what-you-really-need-to-know-about-makeup-expiration-dates/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=what-you-really-need-to-know-about-makeup-expiration-dates</link>
					<comments>/what-you-really-need-to-know-about-makeup-expiration-dates/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 23:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We can all be guilty of keeping products a little too long in our makeup bags… But how bad can it be? Often, most of us have no clue how long we should be holding on to our cosmetics and what consequences using a product past it’s sell-by-date can have. Newsflash…makeup can expire! And as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/what-you-really-need-to-know-about-makeup-expiration-dates/">What You Really Need To Know About Makeup Expiration Dates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>We can all be guilty of keeping
products a little too long in our makeup bags… But how bad can it be? </p>



<p>Often, most of us have no
clue how long we should be holding on to our cosmetics and what consequences
using a product past it’s sell-by-date can have.</p>



<p>Newsflash…makeup can
expire! And as much as it might pain you to throw away your favourite lipstick
or concealer, expiration dates are extremely important. Why? After a product is
past its shelf-life, it becomes the perfect breeding ground for all types of
bacteria. &nbsp;Once transferred to the skin,
lips and lashes it can cause dreaded breakouts, skin irritation, and occasionally
worse, such as nasty bacterial infections like conjunctivitis. </p>



<p>The difficult thing about
expiration dates with cosmetics is that, unlike the contents of your fridge,
the date we are given is from when we <em>open</em> them, rather than when we <em>buy</em>
them. This can then cause some confusion if you’re an obsessive makeup
purchaser or get roped into <em>buy two get one free</em> deals. In addition, the
way we store our cosmetics and the type of packaging they are kept in, can be
major factors. <em>*Hint hint* try not to leave the cap off.</em> </p>



<p><strong>How do you find
out the expiration date of cosmetic products? </strong></p>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/what-you-really-need-to-know-about-makeup-expiration-dates\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-1 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3669" data-permalink="/what-you-really-need-to-know-about-makeup-expiration-dates/untitled-16/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Untitled.png?fit=454%2C302&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="454,302" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Untitled" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Untitled.png?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Untitled.png?fit=454%2C302&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="454" height="302" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Untitled.png?resize=454%2C302" alt="" data-id="3669" class="wp-image-3669" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Untitled.png?w=454&amp;ssl=1 454w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Untitled.png?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Untitled.png?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w" sizes="(max-width: 454px) 100vw, 454px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>via Vogue UK</figcaption></figure></li></ul>



<p>This image is known as a
Period After Opening (PAO) which appears on almost all cosmetic products and
acts as a guideline for how long to keep them after opening. This symbol
consists of a number followed by the letter ‘M’ which indicates the number of
months you should use this product for. Occasionally, some
products won’t show the PAO on its package so&#8230; </p>



<p><strong>What are the
tell-tale signs to throw out your favourite beauty-aid? </strong></p>



<p>Firstly, starting with
skin care, trust your eyes and nose. If products such as cleanser, toner or
moisturiser start to change colour, odour or thickness …throw them out!
Continued use of these products could cause the complete opposite effect of <em>skin
care </em>by irritating your skin.</p>



<p>For liquids like
concealer, foundation, highlighter or mascara, the initial warning signs will
be when they start to dry out, change in texture, become cakey or start to
smell different. If you notice any of these, toss them in the bin immediately. </p>



<p>Products with a powdery
consistency such as your setting powder, blush and bronzer, will need chucking
if you see any discolouration, waxy build up or a change in smell.</p>



<p><strong>A guide to the
sell-by-date of your makeup bag</strong></p>



<table class="wp-block-table"><tbody><tr><td>4-6 months</td><td>6 months &#8211; 1 year</td><td>1 year</td><td>2 years</td><td>8 &#8211; 10 years</td></tr><tr><td>Mascara</td><td>Liquid eyeliner</td><td>Cleanser</td><td>Powder<br>eyeshadow/blush  </td><td>Fragrances</td></tr><tr><td>Micellar water</td><td>Toner</td><td>Moisturiser</td><td>Setting powder</td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Cream eyeshadow/blush</td><td>Concealer</td><td>Pencil eyeliner</td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Cream foundation</td><td>Liquid foundation</td><td>Brow pencil</td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td>Lip liner</td><td>Nail polish</td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td>Lip balm/gloss</td><td>Lipstick</td><td></td></tr></tbody></table>



<p><strong>Top tips </strong></p>



<ol><li>Anything water-based such as micellar water will be one of the first products in the bin if you don&#8217;t use it quickly. Water encourages bacteria growth, which explains the shelf-life of six months max.</li><li>Powders can last up to two years, as the dry texture doesn&#8217;t allow bacteria to grow as easily. So if you know you won’t use up a cream or liquid product quick enough, opt for the powder version. </li><li>Washing your makeup brushes regularly and your hands before every skin care or makeup application use will increase the product’s shelf-life.</li><li>Sharpen any pencil in your makeup bag, whether that a lipliner or brow pencil, as this will remove any bacterial growth on the top layer from contact with the air and your skin.</li><li>Stop pumping air into your mascara! This air forced into the tube will dry out your precious product and encourage bacterial contamination.</li></ol>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Ella Gannon<br>Picture research by Anna Irina; featured image from </strong><em><strong>chealth.canoe.com</strong></em><strong>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/what-you-really-need-to-know-about-makeup-expiration-dates/">What You Really Need To Know About Makeup Expiration Dates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/what-you-really-need-to-know-about-makeup-expiration-dates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3667</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SUBCULTURED’s Sustainable Beauty Brand Of The Month</title>
		<link>/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month</link>
					<comments>/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 21:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Get yourself acquainted with the rebellious beauty brand that makes a big impact: Manic Panic. “Going Vegan” is something that an increasing number of brands are beginning to adopt. In the past vegan and cruelty free products were a bit niche, rejecting animal testing and foregoing animal products is moving further and further into the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month/">SUBCULTURED’s Sustainable Beauty Brand Of The Month</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p class="has-medium-font-size">Get yourself acquainted with the rebellious beauty brand that makes a big impact: <em>Manic Panic</em>.</p>



<p>“Going Vegan” is something that an increasing number of brands are beginning to adopt. In the past vegan and cruelty free products were a bit niche, rejecting animal testing and foregoing animal products is moving further and further into the norm, which is an amazing step towards a kinder and more sustainable makeup industry. However, there is one brand that has been leading the vegan beauty revolution for a whopping 40 years and, since their foundation in 1977, has <em>always </em>been both vegan and cruelty free. Say hello to our Subcultured Sustainable Beauty Brand of the Month – Manic Panic! </p>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-1 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3633" data-permalink="/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month/untitled-15/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled.png?fit=838%2C356&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="838,356" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Untitled" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled.png?fit=300%2C127&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled.png?fit=838%2C356&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="838" height="356" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled.png?resize=838%2C356" alt="" data-id="3633" data-link="/?attachment_id=3633" class="wp-image-3633" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled.png?w=838&amp;ssl=1 838w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled.png?resize=300%2C127&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 838px) 100vw, 838px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></li></ul>



<p><strong>The </strong><em><strong>Hair-Story </strong></em><strong>of Manic Panic</strong></p>



<p>Manic Panic is traditionally a hair dye brand that has recently expanded into the cosmetics industry, sporting an iconic, punk-inspired branding and philosophy that seeps its way into everything they do. </p>



<p>The company’s founders, sisters Tish and Snooky, have worked hard to embody this philosophy. Starting out as backing singers in the original “Blondie” line-up in the mid-70s, they went on to open America’s “first punk boutique” in 1977. It was here, in NYC’s little slice of alternative paradise that <em>Manic Panic</em> was born. Since then, they have stuck to their punk rock roots and continue to perform regularly, having collaborated with a star-studded collection of artists over the years. It is clear that <em>Manic Panic </em>is more than just a brand to them &#8211; it’s a lifestyle. Tish and Snooky say it best in their <em>Manic Panic</em> motto: “We don’t just sell it … We live it!”</p>



<div data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month\/"}' class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img data-attachment-id="3647" data-permalink="/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month/untitled1-1/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled1-1.png?fit=490%2C334&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="490,334" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Untitled1-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled1-1.png?fit=300%2C204&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled1-1.png?fit=490%2C334&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled1-1.png?resize=490%2C334" alt="" class="wp-image-3647" width="490" height="334" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled1-1.png?w=490&amp;ssl=1 490w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled1-1.png?resize=300%2C204&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 490px) 100vw, 490px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p style="text-align:center" class="has-small-font-size"><em>Tish and Snooky with Debbie Harry, lead singers of Blondie, in 1975 </em></p>



<p><strong>So, what do they have to offer?</strong></p>



<p>Manic Panichas an impressive line of products to its name, but is best known for the <em>High Voltage </em>hair colour range, which comes in over 40 tones. From adorable pastels to standout pigments that glow under black light, <em>High Voltage </em>has it all (and at the reasonable price of £11.99 a tub).</p>



<div data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month\/"}' class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="3644" data-permalink="/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month/untitled3-1/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled3-1.png?fit=638%2C359&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="638,359" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Untitled3-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled3-1.png?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled3-1.png?fit=638%2C359&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="638" height="359" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled3-1.png?resize=638%2C359" alt="" class="wp-image-3644" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled3-1.png?w=638&amp;ssl=1 638w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled3-1.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 638px) 100vw, 638px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p style="text-align:center" class="has-small-font-size"><em>Me wearing Manic Panic’s High Voltage semi-permanent dye</em><br><em>in “Electric Tiger Lily”</em></p>



<p>My personal favourite range, Amplified<em>, </em>is known for its strong, long-lasting formula and comes in 22 eye-watering colours. Sporting the tagline “<em>Wear it Loud” </em>it certainly does not disappoint.</p>



<div data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month\/"}' class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="3643" data-permalink="/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month/untitled4-1/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled4-1.png?fit=437%2C437&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="437,437" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Untitled4-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled4-1.png?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled4-1.png?fit=437%2C437&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="437" height="437" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled4-1.png?resize=437%2C437" alt="" class="wp-image-3643" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled4-1.png?w=437&amp;ssl=1 437w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled4-1.png?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled4-1.png?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled4-1.png?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 437px) 100vw, 437px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p style="text-align:center" class="has-small-font-size"><em>Me, 2017, wearing Manic Panic’s Amplified semi-permanent dye</em><br><em>in “Purple Haze”</em></p>



<p> One of the best things about Manic Panic dyes is that they are easy-to-use and versatile. On their website, Manic Panic preaches the fact that their dyes are “non-damaging” and contain “restorative properties.” This has led to a trend of parents using the Manic Panic dye range on their children, as a fun but safe way to temporarily change up their little ones’ looks (see the mini models <a href="https://tinybangs.com/">“Tiny Bangs”</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/oliveabercrombie/?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Olive Abercrombie</a> if you’re sceptical).</p>



<div data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month\/"}' class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="3640" data-permalink="/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month/untitled5-1/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled5-1.png?fit=510%2C382&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="510,382" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Untitled5-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled5-1.png?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled5-1.png?fit=510%2C382&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="510" height="382" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled5-1.png?resize=510%2C382" alt="" class="wp-image-3640" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled5-1.png?w=510&amp;ssl=1 510w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Untitled5-1.png?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 510px) 100vw, 510px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p style="text-align:center" class="has-small-font-size"><em>“Tiny Bangs” rocking their classic Manic Panic locks</em></p>



<p>As someone who has used a range of hair dye brands over the years, including Schwarzkopf and Bleach London, I can confirm that – for me – my hair has felt healthier and more vibrant when I use Manic Panic over any of the other brands I’ve tried.</p>



<p>Not only this, but Manic Panicalso manufacture hair lighteners, gels, sprays, and a professional hair colouring range, so that their products can be used both at home, and in the salon, all over the world.</p>



<p><strong>“Dye-Hard” Activists</strong></p>



<p>Not only are Manic Panic famous for their vegan, cruelty-free products, but they are also well known for their activism and charitable work. Every year, 15% of all <em>Manic Panic</em> profits go to a number of charities, including the <em>Breast Cancer Research Foundation, WWF, </em>the <em>Visual Arts Foundation, </em>and the <em>Beauty Bus Foundation.</em></p>



<p>In addition, in 2017 Manic Panic collaborated with the American National LGBT Cancer Network in order to raise awareness about the disproportionately high cancer rates among the LGBT community (information on which can be found <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.payalvpatel.com/manic-panic" target="_blank">here</a>.) 100% of the proceeds made from their “Dye-ing to Stop Cancer” rainbow dye kit went to the LGBT Cancer Network, to help pay for the screenings of hundreds of LGBT individuals. Manic Panic mobile salons were also a feature at Pride festivals all over the US that year. Festival goers could show their support for the cause through funky and spontaneous dye-jobs and work towards raising awareness.</p>



<p>In an interview with <em>Got a Girl Crush, </em>Tish and Snooky were modest about Manic Panic’s role in charity and activism, saying that <em>“<a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.manicpanic.com/charities" target="_blank">We’ve always [been taking a stance]</a>, but we haven’t been tooting our horn about it.”</em> They talk about their core belief that “charity and good deeds should remain anonymous” but also recognise their responsibility as a successful brand to put them out there in promoting charity and activism. Snooky sums it up nicely: <em>“It’s so great that we’ve gotten so successful we can give back and give a lot. That’s why you should want to be successful and have money – so you can give it to worthy causes and be of help.”</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Flo Wadey<br>Picture research by Anna Irina; featured image from </strong><em><strong>manicpanic.com</strong></em><strong>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month/">SUBCULTURED’s Sustainable Beauty Brand Of The Month</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/subcultureds-sustainable-beauty-brand-of-the-month/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3632</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Skincare That Won’t Leave You Skint</title>
		<link>/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint</link>
					<comments>/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 17:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3546</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>All cosmetics consumers can appreciate the dent that lotions and potions leave in our pocket, especially if you’re a student. Whilst we can perhaps pass on the latest ABH palette or Dior foundation, when it comes to skincare, subsidizing on high-end products isn’t quite as straightforward. We are all too familiar with the lofty claims [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint/">Skincare That Won’t Leave You Skint</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>All cosmetics consumers can appreciate the dent
that lotions and potions leave in our pocket, especially if you’re a student.
Whilst we can perhaps pass on the latest ABH palette or Dior foundation, when
it comes to skincare, subsidizing on high-end products isn’t quite as
straightforward. We are all too familiar with the lofty claims of cheap
alternatives, promising to eliminate acne or leave you with baby-soft skin&#8230;a
lot of the time, the results simply don’t live up to the hype.&nbsp; </p>



<p>It doesn’t have to be this way, however &#8211; enter
Revolution Makeup: an affordable yet high-quality drugstore beauty brand,
endorsed by the likes of Jeffree Star, Khloé Kardashian and other major
influencers in the beauty community. In case you missed it, the British brand
went viral in 2018 following the ‘Conceal and Define Concealer’, crowned to be
the affordable dupe for Tarte’s infamous ‘Shape Tape’. Multiple MUAs, vloggers
and journalists were quick to pick up on the buzz and since then, Revolution
has continued to dominate UK drugstores.</p>



<p>The brand’s latest drop has been the Revolution
Skincare line, launched in August 2018, and keeping closely akin to the brand’s
philosophy of praiseworthy products which won’t break the bank. If the price
tag of ₤10 or less and outstanding website reviews weren’t appealing enough,
the whole range is 100% cruelty-free, mostly vegan and &#8211; as always &#8211; promoted
using a beautifully diverse and inclusive range of models. </p>



<p>The range currently consists of a number of
facial oils, essences, and serums, catering to a comprehensive range of skin
types. Whether you’re looking for something to give you a daily boost of
hydration and glow, experiencing dryness, or tackling acne-prone skin,
Revolution Skincare is certainly worth a try. </p>



<p>Two products I have been doting on from the collection are the ‘Skin Blemish and Pore Refining Serum &#8211; 10% Niacinamide + 1% Zinc’ and the ‘Revolution Skin CBD Essence Spray’ (both priced at just ₤6).</p>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-2 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3548" data-permalink="/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint/revolution-skin-blemish-and-pore-refining-serum-10-niacinamide-1-zinc/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Blemish-and-Pore-Refining-Serum-10-Niacinamide-1-Zinc.jpg?fit=450%2C450&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="450,450" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Revolution Skin Blemish and Pore Refining Serum &#8211; 10% Niacinamide + 1% Zinc" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Blemish-and-Pore-Refining-Serum-10-Niacinamide-1-Zinc.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Blemish-and-Pore-Refining-Serum-10-Niacinamide-1-Zinc.jpg?fit=450%2C450&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="450" height="450" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Blemish-and-Pore-Refining-Serum-10-Niacinamide-1-Zinc.jpg?resize=450%2C450" alt="" data-id="3548" data-link="/?attachment_id=3548" class="wp-image-3548" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Blemish-and-Pore-Refining-Serum-10-Niacinamide-1-Zinc.jpg?w=450&amp;ssl=1 450w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Blemish-and-Pore-Refining-Serum-10-Niacinamide-1-Zinc.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Blemish-and-Pore-Refining-Serum-10-Niacinamide-1-Zinc.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Blemish-and-Pore-Refining-Serum-10-Niacinamide-1-Zinc.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption><em>via revolutionbeauty.com</em></figcaption></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3554" data-permalink="/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint/revolution-skin-cbd-essence-spray-2/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-CBD-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?fit=450%2C450&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="450,450" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Revolution Skin CBD Essence Spray" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-CBD-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-CBD-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?fit=450%2C450&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="450" height="450" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-CBD-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?resize=450%2C450" alt="" data-id="3554" data-link="/?attachment_id=3554" class="wp-image-3554" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-CBD-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?w=450&amp;ssl=1 450w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-CBD-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-CBD-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-CBD-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption><em>via revolutionbeauty.com</em></figcaption></figure></li></ul>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-0 is-cropped"></ul>



<p>Having used a prescribed acne treatment for around a year, my complexion is relatively clear these days (touch wood), but the Skin Blemish Serum helps to keep any miniature breakouts at bay. The CBD Essence Spray meanwhile aids in keeping my skin hydrated and with banishing red tones; whilst the acne treatment did clear up my skin, it has also left it dry and irritated in places. The essence helps to combat these effects without smothering my skin in layers of greasy, comedogenic creams. If you have oily or dry skin I highly recommend the serum or essence, respectively, or try using them in tandem for temperamental combination skin like mine.</p>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-2 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3550" data-permalink="/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint/revolution-skin-rosehip-seed-oil-gold-elixir/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Rosehip-Seed-Oil-Gold-Elixir.jpg?fit=450%2C450&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="450,450" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Revolution Skin Rosehip Seed Oil &#8211; Gold Elixir" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Rosehip-Seed-Oil-Gold-Elixir.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Rosehip-Seed-Oil-Gold-Elixir.jpg?fit=450%2C450&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="450" height="450" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Rosehip-Seed-Oil-Gold-Elixir.jpg?resize=450%2C450" alt="" data-id="3550" data-link="/?attachment_id=3550" class="wp-image-3550" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Rosehip-Seed-Oil-Gold-Elixir.jpg?w=450&amp;ssl=1 450w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Rosehip-Seed-Oil-Gold-Elixir.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Rosehip-Seed-Oil-Gold-Elixir.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Rosehip-Seed-Oil-Gold-Elixir.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption><em>Other Revolution skincare products you may want to try out include the Rosehip Seed Oil Gold Elixir&#8230;</em></figcaption></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3555" data-permalink="/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint/revolution-skin-superfruit-essence-spray-2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Superfruit-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?fit=450%2C450&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="450,450" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Revolution Skin Superfruit Essence Spray" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Superfruit-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Superfruit-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?fit=450%2C450&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="450" height="450" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Superfruit-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?resize=450%2C450" alt="" data-id="3555" data-link="/?attachment_id=3555" class="wp-image-3555" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Superfruit-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?w=450&amp;ssl=1 450w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Superfruit-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Superfruit-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Revolution-Skin-Superfruit-Essence-Spray-1.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption><em>and the Superfruit Essence Spray (via revolutionbeauty.com)</em>.</figcaption></figure></li></ul>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-0 is-cropped"></ul>



<p>The entire Revolution Skincare collection can be found in stores and online at Superdrug, BEAUTY BAY, ULTA Beauty, ASOS, or on their website: <a href="https://www.revolutionbeauty.com/en/Skincare/c-58.aspx?CategoryIDs=97,46" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="https://www.revolutionbeauty.com/en/Skincare/c-58.aspx?CategoryIDs=97,46 (opens in a new tab)">https://www.revolutionbeauty.com/en/Skincare/c-58.aspx?CategoryIDs=97,46</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Claudia Rae</strong></p>



<p><strong>Featured image researched by Anna Irina; source: Pinterest.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint/">Skincare That Won’t Leave You Skint</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/skincare-that-wont-leave-you-skint/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3546</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Interview with Adriana Blanc</title>
		<link>/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=an-interview-with-adriana-blanc</link>
					<comments>/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 18:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>So it’s nearing the end of February, and I’m sure most of us have fallen off the wagon when it came to our well intentioned New Year’s resolution to get back in the gym and start getting fit. Well, not all hope is lost! We sat down and spoke with Adriana Blanc, a student and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/">An Interview with Adriana Blanc</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>So it’s nearing the end of February, and I’m sure
most of us have fallen off the wagon when it came to our well intentioned New
Year’s resolution to get back in the gym and start getting fit. Well, not all
hope is lost! We sat down and spoke with Adriana Blanc, a student and personal
trainer who is making it her mission to empower young women to be the best,
healthiest and happiest versions of themselves. With easy to follow workouts
and delicious looking meal prep ideas, Adriana uses Instagram and YouTube to
connect with hundreds of young women struggling with their fitness journey.
With specific advice for university students trying to juggle a healthy
lifestyle with deadlines and the odd night out, Adriana offers practical advice
whilst being your own personal hype girl. </p>



<p>Adriana’s personality shines through in the
following interview, it’s clear she feels passionately about health and
well-being. So give it a read, get inspired and keeping pursuing those health
and fitness goals. We can’t wait to see what she does next!</p>



<p><strong>Hi! First
of all, could you just introduce and tell us a little bit about yourself and
what you do?</strong></p>



<p>Hi! I’m Adriana Blanc, I’m a 21 year old final
year student at the University of Bath studying Chemistry and I’m also a
personal trainer. </p>



<p>I have a genuine love and interest in helping young, newly independent females like myself implement long term and sustainable healthy habits, so I created an Instagram account called <a href="https://www.instagram.com/adrianablancfit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="@adrianablancfit (opens in a new tab)">@adrianablancfit</a> aiming to achieve just that. The «&nbsp;Healthy at Uni&nbsp;»&nbsp; Facebook community I created has two groups with over 140+ girls in both so that I can connect to them more personally. As a uni student, with both of these platforms I aim to help female students healthily transition into and experience university life by providing them with informative resources on exercise, nutrition, and mindset. </p>



<p>I also have various off and online personal
training clients, and teach circuit training fitness classes at university to
girls&nbsp;!</p>



<p><strong>Where did
you start with your fitness journey? Have you always liked working out or was
it a lifestyle change for you?</strong></p>



<p>It was never a lifestyle change for me as I’ve always been in love with sports – my family is very athletic so I grew up playing volleyball, tennis, and football competitively and am currently on the university volleyball team. I got into structured gymming/working out during my first year of university – just working out in my dorm room because I felt way too intimidated by the university gym (Uni of Bath is literally known for their huge athletes!) In second year, I decided to overcome my fear and just hit up the gym and slowly but surely my confidence in there built up. I started to love mixing heavy weightlifting with circuits, High intensity training, and cardio as an overall fitness routine, so have continued since and will continue for life!</p>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-1 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3530" data-permalink="/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/img_6755/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?fit=4032%2C3024&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="4032,3024" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1540833972&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;40&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.04&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_6755" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?fit=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="4032" height="3024" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?fit=1024%2C768" alt="" data-id="3530" data-link="/?attachment_id=3530" class="wp-image-3530" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?w=4032&amp;ssl=1 4032w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></li></ul>



<p><strong>What made
you want to start your fitness Instagram account?</strong></p>



<p>I was getting asked a lot for advice and help
from my friends, and I noticed that often their questions were self-sabotage
driven, such as “I hate how I look in this” or “I want to get rid of this”.
While I of course understand the motivation behind those worries, with my
account, I want to instill in all girls my age the mindset that exercise and
healthy eating should come from a desire for self improvement, self care, and
self love, NOT from a place of shame, self-hatred, and wanting to fundamentally
change yourself. It is so important to develop this mindset. It’s essential to
establishing long-term habits that make you enjoy the process, that make you
patient (rather than have you searching for a «&nbsp;quick fix&nbsp;») that
make you feel proud of your efforts (rather than feeling frustrated for the
speed of your progress) and that make you KIND to yourself. </p>



<p>With my stories and posts that just show my
realistic day to day life of my nights out, stressing over uni coursework,
having fun meals with friends, but still being able to fit in exercise and
cooking OVERALL, I want to show that it really is a LIFESTYLE, not a strict set
of rules that we have to 100% live for.&nbsp; </p>



<p>The reason I wanted to create a “healthy at uni”
theme to my account is because university is a
particularly vulnerable point in the lives of young females; it is the first
time we are fully independent and rely on our own willpower/motivation for self
care (cooking, exercising, socialising). It is widely known that this often
results in a lack of self care; in US colleges a popular term called the
“Freshman 15” refers to this in that freshers may gain or lose 15 lbs in their
first year of university at the expense of their health. An overall <strong>trend</strong> has been observed: often
this quick decline in health in first year directly affects many other aspects
of our lives, such as academic performance, self confidence, and body image
(especially given our tendency to spend so much time on social media channels
that portray a “ideal” body). Also, <strong>gym/exercise
intimidation</strong> is especially prevalent in student university gyms (and even
more so at the #1 UK 2018 sports university) where gym members tend to be known
acquaintances and already knowledgeable and experienced athletes. This often
deters young female students from either joining, consistently attending, or
making the most out of the gym. With my Instagram account, I wanted to create
resources (workout programs, budget/quick meal recipes, and self
help/development messages) that are dedicated to and account for university
life and culture. </p>



<p>With
guidance, it is completely possible to <strong>both</strong>
enjoy and have fun at university (the social/drinking/eating out/late nights
aspect of it) <strong>while</strong> developing and
implementing healthy habits. When practiced from the VERY beginning of
university, I genuinely believe the students will be able to overall make the
most out of and feel our best throughout university: mentally, physically, and
academically.</p>



<p><strong>It’s
great to see that you don’t just focus on exercise, but on well-being and
nutrition too! Why is that stuff so important to you?</strong></p>



<p>Exercise is just one form of self-care, and
knowing how to use it in a way that is enjoyable, that benefits your ambitions
and that you can actually stick to is what will make it enhance your life. </p>



<p><strong>What
advice to you have for someone too scared to start their own fitness journey?</strong></p>



<p>I talk about this topic all the time because I
feel so passionate about giving people the courage to push past their fear of
change, others people’s judgments, so that they can just START doing the things
they know they want to do. </p>



<p>Like anything in life, the beginning is
uncomfortable. Usually, there are 3 reasons why someone would feel intimidated
or scared: You’re unsure if you’re doing things correctly, you’re intimidated
by those who are more experienced/you compare yourself to them, and you think
you will have to dedicate 100% of your effort all the time to “being healthy”. </p>



<p>I have a YouTube video that discusses gym
confidence which you can check out!</p>



<p>This is a post I wrote dedicated to this topic:</p>



<p>To
all the ladies that tell me you really struggle with lacking confidence when
doing any of this fitnessy stuff&#8230;</p>



<p>Here’s
the thing my gals: confidence comes from a series of repeated actions. That’s
all it really is <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f917.png" alt="🤗" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Repeated actions. </p>



<p>Think
about it: you probably lacked confidence at your first local job because at
first, everyone else knew how it all worked, where everything was, and how it
all got done, while you did not. But now? You know your job like the back of
your hand, walk around like you own the place <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, and you’re bros with
your boss</p>



<p>So,
when you’re <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4aa-1f3fc.png" alt="💪🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />goin at it<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4aa-1f3fc.png" alt="💪🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, think of that. And if you start to get
uncomfortable, and you start to get frustrated, wishing you just had the
confidence to properly get it done, remind yourself that:</p>



<p>Discomfort
is normal. </p>



<p>Discomfort
is good.</p>



<p>Discomfort
is your friend. </p>



<p>Discomfort
is opportunity for growth. </p>



<p>Because
the coolest thing is that if you keep exposing yourself to it, you will soon
overcome it. </p>



<p>Don’t
convince yourself that discomfort, or lack of confidence, is a legitimate
barrier for going for what you KNOW you want to go for. It is PART of the
process. Everyone has felt it. </p>



<p>And overcoming it, little by little, is what creates that confidence you will very soon feel. So KEEP IT UP my gal<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2764.png" alt="❤" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-1 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3532" data-permalink="/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/screen-shot-2019-02-18-at-10-37-05-2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?fit=1152%2C920&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1152,920" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2019-02-18 at 10.37.05" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?fit=300%2C240&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?fit=1024%2C818&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1152" height="920" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?fit=1024%2C818" alt="" data-id="3532" data-link="/?attachment_id=3532" class="wp-image-3532" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?w=1152&amp;ssl=1 1152w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?resize=300%2C240&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?resize=1024%2C818&amp;ssl=1 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1152px) 100vw, 1152px" /></figure></li></ul>



<p><strong>How do
you balance all of it with university? </strong></p>



<p>I view it as a priority! self care will always be
a priority for me; I will perform much better as a student, friend, athlete,
you name it – if I am taking care of myself. </p>



<p>I’ve written a couple posts on the workout side
of this: </p>



<p><strong>MINDSET TIPS </strong></p>



<p>I want to highlight these 3 mindset shifts that SERIOUSLY helped me because <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />mindset <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />is everything<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />!!!!</p>



<p>1.PRACTICE SELF AWARENESS</p>



<p>be
REAL with yourself and realise that, girlies, we DO have time. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/23f1.png" alt="⏱" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />how often do we
open insta/twitter/snapchat and scroll through for 15 minutes? As I write this
while chillin, it’s probably my 5th/6th of the day, and as you read this, it
may be yours as well. No need to feel guilty, because we like doing it &#8211; but
pointing it out is a perfect way to be self aware that we DO have the time.
Realise it and convince yourself of it &#8211; so that you can use it.</p>



<p>2. VIEW IT AS A PRIORITY</p>



<p>Here’s
the thing amigas, there will literally ALWAYS be coursework you can get ahead
on, lecture notes to write, socials to attend, nights out calling our names, a
shift at work to get to. And it’s honestly overwhelming that uni life is KNOWN
for that fact that no one can really tell us what to do anymore; WE have to set
our priorities. So: consider the workout JUST AS IMPORTANT as the lab report &#8211;
so that you go when you said you would, EVEN IF you didn’t get as ahead in the
assignment as you said you would. Why? Keep reading heheh (look at me buildin
up the suspense)</p>



<p>3. Realise that it will IMPROVE YOUR TIME MANAGEMENT and productivity</p>



<p>When
you schedule it in, you subconsciously motivate yourself to plan a structure
around it, and stick to that plan. AND without getting too scientific, there
are a SHIETton of studies that directly correlate exercise to boosts of
productivity; whether they’re immediate (we all know that post workout high!)
or long term (memory improvement, energy generation, stress relief OH SO MAny) </p>



<p>So
when you are struggling to fit in your workouts/cooking as a student, start
with your mindset. Convince yourself of these three things:</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> You DO have the time</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> It IS a priority</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> It WILL improve your time management, productivity, and make you a better student</p>



<p><strong>PRACTICAL TIPS </strong></p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> In short, REDUCE the amount of decision making you have to spend on aaaaany of it!! </p>



<p>1. SCHEDULE IT IN</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Whether its a class, or a gym date with a pal, or a YouTube workout. I encourage you to write<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f44f-1f3fc.png" alt="👏🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />it<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f44f-1f3fc.png" alt="👏🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />down<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f44f-1f3fc.png" alt="👏🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Gives you a sense of accountability that will help you as a student IMMenseLy trust meh (and the fact that i tried to go 4 months of my first year chemistry degree without an agenda LOL #itdidntwork #atall)</p>



<p>2. BE REALISTIC WITH YOUR SCHEDULING so that you can literally only set yourself up for success</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Is it a particularly reeeally busy week? So it looks like you can only do 2 workouts (even though your plan requires 4). That’s fine! Schedule in those 2 workouts, and do them. Think about the mental significance of this: you can be proud that you ACHIEVED the 2 workouts you scheduled in, rather than frustrated for writing off 2 that were unrealistically put in. </p>



<p>3. ALWAYS HAVE A PREPARED GYM BAG so that if it’s a workout day, all you have to do is pick it up</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> For a long while I literally used a grocery bag lol and just always had it by my door. quickly replaced the sweaty with the clean, set it back down by the door, ready for its next use. (tbh often I don’t even switch out some stuff ewies heheh but gotta save the wash monies where we can)<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f937-1f3fb-200d-2640-fe0f.png" alt="🤷🏻‍♀️" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<p>4. WORK OUT EFFICIENTLY by following a planned guide/structure so you don’t faff around</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Nothing worse than walking in and feeling like “sooo what now” or walking out and being like “what did I just do in the past hour”!!Walk in, check through each planned move, walk out feeling lit and sassy (and sweaty) af</p>



<p>5. <em>(personal preference) </em>GET IT DONE IN THE MORNING</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> teehee. There’s just something about starting your day with a huge check to your to do list and a boost of energy. It takes getting used to FOR SURE but try it <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2764.png" alt="❤" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<p><strong>MEAL PREP TIPS</strong></p>



<p>You
save so much time and money meal prepping! Instead of spending 30 min in the kitchen
every night, lots of time queuing for/deciding on food on campus, you spend 1
hour every 3 or 4 nights making food you know you’ll like and for much cheaper.
</p>



<ul><li>Buy food on Sunday. Then meal prep on Sunday and Wednesday evening. </li><li>Make one pot (4ish portions worth) and one oven based (4ish portions worth) recipe at once – so that way in 30 min you have yourself 8 meals. </li><li>Instead of putting it in individual Tupperware (that’s 8ish tupperware…way too much) put each recipe in one huge Tupperware (so you’ll have 2 tupperware that easily stack on each other in the fridge). </li></ul>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-1 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3533" data-permalink="/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/screen-shot-2019-02-18-at-10-37-19/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?fit=1526%2C1148&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1526,1148" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2019-02-18 at 10.37.19" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?fit=300%2C226&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?fit=1024%2C770&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1526" height="1148" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?fit=1024%2C770" alt="" data-id="3533" data-link="/?attachment_id=3533" class="wp-image-3533" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?w=1526&amp;ssl=1 1526w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?resize=300%2C226&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?resize=1024%2C770&amp;ssl=1 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></li></ul>



<p><strong>Do you
think this sort of lifestyle is compatible with being a student that maybe
drinks and has dominos more than they really should? </strong></p>



<p>Of course! That is the entire message of my
platform and what I stand for. I want us gals to realise and remember that
progress (of any form) comes from CONSISTENCY, not RIGIDITY. I want us to
realise that drinks out, occasional dominoes, and some late nights are all a
part of this fun stage in our life, and to stop mentally bullying ourselves
into thinking we “failed” at “being healthy” when this happens. Focus on what
you can “control” on the WHOLE, such as the self-made food you can nourish
yourself with (and save lots of money on), and the workouts you can get energy
from. The other fun bits are called LIFE. </p>



<p>As uni students there is a social
aspect so entrenched in the uni experience (drinking with friends, having food
out, late nights etc) that may make “aesthetic” results slower than if we were
at another point in our lives &#8211; I fully realise this and embrace it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I always encourage
students to shift your mentality to view consistent exercise as an investment
in your LONG term health, discipline, and happiness, rather than an immediate
way to get aesthetic results (as it’s so often marketed as). </p>



<p>When I’m lacking
motivation, I turn to my beloved science for some: SO MANY studies consistently
demonstrate how daily exercise boosts your brain capacity, helps to prevent
depression, and prevents long-term chronic diseases (Type 2 Diabetes, heart
disease, dementia etc).&nbsp;</p>



<p>So now I view every half
hour workout as this: an opportunity for major endorphin release immediately
after, an opportunity to have some daily time to focus on myself, and an
opportunity to better my long-term health.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&nbsp;&nbsp;prioritise
getting my exercise in as much as I&nbsp;&nbsp;prioritise writing up that
essay. In the long term, the mental clarity and brain boost I feel from every
workout, and the confidence in myself that I’ve developed from a consistent
exercise routine, has contributed so much to my discipline as a hard-working
student. If I can trust myself to squeeze in a 30 minute workout even when I’m
not really in the mood, I can trust myself to just write up those lecture notes
when I know I should. so STICK TO IT: the time will pass anyway, so may as well
fulfil those daily self-promises to workout that your long term self will
seriously thank and feel proud of you for.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>How did
you balance it with working full time? Do you have any top tips for staying
motivated when the 9-5 has you ready to collapse into bed the minute you’re
home?</strong></p>



<p>My biggest (and probably most annoying!) tip is
to get it done in the morning. It takes getting used to but here is a post I
wrote on it: </p>



<p>Things
I do the night before: </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I sleep in my workout outfit (it’s clean and comfy don’t you worry heh) </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I place my alarm clock (phone) across the room &#8211; classsssic trick</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I place my headphones, a water bottle, my shoes and my jacket next to it</p>



<p>So
the morning of goes something like this: </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f449-1f3fc.png" alt="👉🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> The stupid flippin “diddledumdumdumdumdum…. dumdumdumdum” iPhone alarm goes off (literally singing that in my head right now)</p>



<p>And
I’m tired. I don’t want to get up. The bed is so warm. Oh so very warm. But I
literally have to get up &#8211; to turn the world’s worst tune off. </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> So I do. </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4a6.png" alt="💦" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> And drink the water, it perks me up a lil</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f3a7.png" alt="🎧" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> And put on the headphones, play “Move Your Feet” by Junior Senior &#8211; that tune perks me up a lil more </p>



<p>And
I’m up: in my outfit, headphones on, water bottle in my hand and jacket/shoes
right there…lesssss just go my gals!</p>



<p><strong>For the
girls who aren’t already ‘fit and slim’ how do you cater for them in terms of
lower impact exercises, diet change etc.? </strong></p>



<p>In my fitness classes, I always encourage the
girls to do what they can while MAKING SURE to challenge themselves. All of us
know our levels, and we all know when we are challenging ourselves (even if we
don’t admit it!) </p>



<p>Learn how to build up every move: the squat, the
pushup, pull up, etc!</p>



<p>Never ever be embarrassed of your current
abilities. Everybody starts somewhere, so don’t convince yourself you’re
naturally restricted to certain abilities! </p>



<p>For diet change, I always emphasise the
importance of adding habits rather than removing very engrained ones as a form
of gradual habit formation. For example, ADD ON drinking 2L of water a day, add
on veggies to your plate, ADD ON cooking your own meals instead of buying out.
Once you see it’s pretty simple to stick to those habits, you trust yourself to
be able to remove some habits you don’t think are that great for you!</p>



<p>It is never ever
too late to start adding on exercise and self-cooking into your life, no matter
your life circumstances, current fitness level, body type, etc. Exercise and
diet change is not “one size fits all”, and every little effort counts. </p>



<p><strong>What are
your own personal goals for your growing fitness empire? What change do you
want to make? </strong></p>



<p>I would love to make a big community out of it
like Kayla Itsines has done – where I can offer a subscription service (like an
app) with workouts, meal prep ideas for one, written articles on mindset help,
and have the ability to personally meet anyone that uses it with big meetups.
I’d especially want to emphasise the “connection” and “community” factor. The thing
is; you can google workouts and recipes at any point in time anywhere, but I
want to humanise the process by appreciating their actions, easing their
frustrations, congratulating them for their efforts. </p>



<p>That’s why I like to put a lot of thought into my captions! Each post is a chance to connect with someone, and encourage them. While we are subconsciously taught to “want” to work out and eat well to I want to instil in every person that comes across my platforms and encourage them, and make them feel fully capable!</p>



<p>You can find Adriana here:</p>



<p>Instagram: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="@adrianablancfit (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.instagram.com/adrianablancfit/" target="_blank"><em>@adrianablancfit</em></a></p>



<p>YouTube: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Adriana Blanc  (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCtgOYBxEUX6fCcxsa_U3Whw" target="_blank"><em>Adriana Blanc</em></a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Holly Butteriss</strong></p>



<p><strong>In-text photos provided by Adriana Blanc</strong></p>



<p><strong>Picture research by Juliey Pham; featured image by  <br>@fezbot2000 on Unplash.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/">An Interview with Adriana Blanc</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3526</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Shop Cruelty-Free Makeup On A Student Budget</title>
		<link>/how-to-shop-cruelty-free-makeup-on-a-student-budget/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-shop-cruelty-free-makeup-on-a-student-budget</link>
					<comments>/how-to-shop-cruelty-free-makeup-on-a-student-budget/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 19:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3364</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We don’t know about you, but we think it is time to stop our makeup products being tested on animals. Although we appreciate our cosmetics being tested for safety purposes, millions of rabbits, mice, cats and dogs undergo painful procedures in order for us to be able to contour our faces. Somehow, we don’t think [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-shop-cruelty-free-makeup-on-a-student-budget/">How To Shop Cruelty-Free Makeup On A Student Budget</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>We don’t know about you, but we think it is time to stop our makeup products being tested on animals. Although we appreciate our cosmetics being tested for safety purposes, millions of rabbits, mice, cats and dogs undergo painful procedures in order for us to be able to contour our faces. Somehow, we don’t think this is right.</p>



<p>The unfortunate reality is that many beauty companies still test their products on animals. Although many claim to be ‘cruelty-free’ in the UK, their products are still being sold in countries that require cosmetics to be tested on animals by law. It is a common misconception that shopping cruelty-free is expensive and can’t be done in high street stores. So, here are five of our favourite high street, cruelty-free beauty brands that mean cruelty-free makeup doesn’t have to break the bank:</p>



<p> </p>



<p><strong>Barry M</strong> </p>



<p>We are starting with a #throwback and taking it back to our teenage years with Barry M. With a strong animal testing policy, all Barry M products are cruelty-free and can be found in your local Boots or Superdrug. Their products are perfect for creating a day or night-time look that is considerate to a student budget (prices range from £2.50- £13.00). Our personal favourite is their ‘Gelly Nail Paints that are long-lasting and have a high-shine, glossy finish.</p>



<p> </p>



<p><strong>Revolution + Revolution PRO</strong></p>



<p>A relatively new beauty brand on our high street is Makeup Revolution that is 100% cruelty-free and has an extensive range of lip, eye and face products. Their makeup is fun, affordable and also caters to a variety of skin tones. The Revolution PRO collection is especially good if you’re looking for professional quality makeup that is wedding and photoshoot proof without the extortionate prices. They also offer dupes to your favourite non-cruelty-free eyeshadow pallets at a fraction of the price &#8211; a win-win situation!</p>



<p> </p>



<p><strong>Lush</strong> </p>



<p>Lush is a pioneer in cruelty-free product sand offers vegan alternatives to your everyday beauty items. Although they are famous for their bath bombs and shampoos, their makeup is a hidden gem! From their long-lasting lip stains to their highlighters, you can ensure that their beauty products are all ethically formulated. Lush is also introducing a new makeup range that aims to reduce the amount of unnecessary packaging in its products and aims to make all make-up packaging compostable, recyclable or refillable when used!</p>



<p> </p>



<p><strong>Kat Von D</strong> </p>



<p>This one is for those student loan shopping-sprees when our good friend SFE allows us to treat ourselves to more extravagant makeup products. With the slogan “Made with Love, Not withAnimals”, we can be sure that Kat Von D makeup is 100% cruelty-free. It offers an extensive range of high-pigment, highlighters, eye makeup and award-winning liquid lipsticks that will be sure to make a statement and enhance your everyday look. Kat Von D ‘Tattoo Liner’ is a bestseller and promises24-hour-wear- perfect for creating a killer cat-eye flick! Kat Von D products are available at Debenhams and online.</p>



<p> </p>



<p><strong>MUA Makeup Academy</strong> </p>



<p>Found exclusively at Superdrug, MUA MakeupAcademy is often overlooked when considering cruelty-free alternatives to your favourite beauty products. It is by far the cheapest brand featured on this list but that is not a reflection on its quality! With highly pigmented eyeshadows, highlighters and blushers, along with all your other beauty must-haves, MUA have you covered. Prices range from a bargain £1.00 to a modest£8.00 and is therefore perfect for trying out a new, perhaps experimental makeup look.</p>



<p>Shopping cruelty-free is definitely possible on a student budget, with many high-street shops stocking good quality products at affordable prices. It is worth checking out drug stores own-brand beauty items as these are often cruelty-free or having a look for the ‘BUAV Approved’ logo at the back of products to check if they have been approved by CrueltyFree International. PETA also have a handy database of companies that do and don&#8217;t test their products on animals! </p>



<p>Our consumer habits are crucial when large corporations are considering their company policies, therefore, it is important to support ethical companies that are 100% against animal testing. It may feel like an insignificant act, but by taking a stand on cosmetic animal testing and not purchasing from these particular brands, we are sending a clear message to these companies: animal testing is wrong.</p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Text by Parul Obhrai</strong></p>



<p><strong>Picture research by Anna Irina, featured image from </strong><em><strong>canacopegdl.com.</strong></em></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-shop-cruelty-free-makeup-on-a-student-budget/">How To Shop Cruelty-Free Makeup On A Student Budget</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/how-to-shop-cruelty-free-makeup-on-a-student-budget/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3364</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Protecting Your Skin In Sub-Zero Temperatures</title>
		<link>/protecting-skin-sub-zero-temperatures/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=protecting-skin-sub-zero-temperatures</link>
					<comments>/protecting-skin-sub-zero-temperatures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 18:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With the UK battling sub-zero temperatures in the past few weeks, and then the arrival of last week’s storm, the ‘beast from the east’, protecting our skin from the cold, dry air has never been so important. In a dry environment, your skin cells start to lose water, which is why many will notice dry, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/protecting-skin-sub-zero-temperatures/">Protecting Your Skin In Sub-Zero Temperatures</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">With the UK battling sub-zero temperatures in the past few weeks, and then the arrival of last week’s storm, the ‘beast from the east’, protecting our skin from the cold, dry air has never been so important.</p>
<p>In a dry environment, your skin cells start to lose water, which is why many will notice dry, chapped lips as a result of cold weather. This is having the same effect on your skin, but it may not be as obvious, therefore, it is useful to start preventing winter damage to your skin as soon as you notice chapped lips. A simple layer of moisturiser will help but won’t do the trick, especially if you already suffer from skin conditions such as acne, eczema or psoriasis, which can all be aggravated by harsh weather conditions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Change your indoor habits</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Avoid hot, steamy showers </strong>Prolonged exposure in a humid environment after being in the cold can cause the skin to lose natural oils, resulting in a further loss in moisture</li>
<li><strong>Stay hydrated </strong>Whether it’s 25ºC or -5ºC, drinking the recommended 2 litres of water a day keeps the skin hydrated</li>
<li><strong>Wear soft cotton or silk </strong>Dry, itchy skin (also known as the ‘winter itch’) can be irritated by scratchy woollen fabrics</li>
<li><strong>Eat healthy fats </strong>Eating foods such as fish, nuts and avocados is a way Eskimos keep their skin healthy in the cold as they have anti-inflammatory properties</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Remedies</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Lip balm with SPF </strong>This will help relieve your dry, chapped lips. Avoid lip balms containing camphor, phenol, menthol, OL, or salicylic acid, as these actually dry your lips</li>
</ol>
<p><div id="attachment_2660" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2660" data-attachment-id="2660" data-permalink="/protecting-skin-sub-zero-temperatures/carmex-lip-balm-pot-classic-7-5g-p23109-92872_image/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/carmex-lip-balm-pot-classic-7-5g-p23109-92872_image.jpg?fit=1000%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1000,1000" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="carmex-lip-balm-pot-classic-7-5g-p23109-92872_image" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/carmex-lip-balm-pot-classic-7-5g-p23109-92872_image.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/carmex-lip-balm-pot-classic-7-5g-p23109-92872_image.jpg?fit=1000%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2660 size-medium" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/carmex-lip-balm-pot-classic-7-5g-p23109-92872_image-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/carmex-lip-balm-pot-classic-7-5g-p23109-92872_image.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/carmex-lip-balm-pot-classic-7-5g-p23109-92872_image.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/carmex-lip-balm-pot-classic-7-5g-p23109-92872_image.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/carmex-lip-balm-pot-classic-7-5g-p23109-92872_image.jpg?w=1000&amp;ssl=1 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2660" class="wp-caption-text">Carmex Lip Pot Original &#8211; £2.69 (Boots)</p></div></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><a href="http://www.boots.com/carmex-lip-pot-original-10091770" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://www.boots.com/carmex-lip-pot-original-10091770</a></em></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Sunscreen or makeup with SPF </strong>Don’t be fooled by the temperature, you can still get sunburn, and more likely, wind burn</li>
</ol>
<p><div id="attachment_2661" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2661" data-attachment-id="2661" data-permalink="/protecting-skin-sub-zero-temperatures/attachment/2619367/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2619367.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="500,500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="2619367" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2619367.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2619367.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2661 size-medium" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2619367-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2619367.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2619367.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2619367.jpg?w=500&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2619367.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2661" class="wp-caption-text">No7 Protect &amp; Perfect Foundation SPF15 &#8211; £16.50 (Boots)</p></div></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><a href="http://www.boots.com/no7-protect-and-perfect-foundation-10143728" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://www.boots.com/no7-protect-and-perfect-foundation-10143728</a></em></p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Sleep with socks and gloves on </strong>If you are suffering from extremely dry hands or feet, moisturise them and then sleep with socks/gloves on to help lock in moisture</li>
<li><strong>Deeply nourishing moisturiser </strong>Penetrating moisturisers are a good way of regaining moisture in the skin</li>
</ol>
<p><div id="attachment_2662" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2662" data-attachment-id="2662" data-permalink="/protecting-skin-sub-zero-temperatures/51af8jzqnfl-_sl1000_/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/51AF8JZqNFL._SL1000_.jpg?fit=1000%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1000,1000" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="51AF8JZqNFL._SL1000_" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/51AF8JZqNFL._SL1000_.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/51AF8JZqNFL._SL1000_.jpg?fit=1000%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2662 size-medium" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/51AF8JZqNFL._SL1000_-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/51AF8JZqNFL._SL1000_.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/51AF8JZqNFL._SL1000_.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/51AF8JZqNFL._SL1000_.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/51AF8JZqNFL._SL1000_.jpg?w=1000&amp;ssl=1 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2662" class="wp-caption-text">Nivea Rich Nourishing Body Moisturiser For Dry Skin &#8211; £3.75 (Boots)</p></div></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em> <a href="http://www.boots.com/nivea-rich-nourishing-body-moisturiser-for-dry-skin-250ml-10016620" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://www.boots.com/nivea-rich-nourishing-body-moisturiser-for-dry-skin-250ml-10016620</a></em></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<ol start="5">
<li><strong>Olive oil </strong>Putting a small amount of olive oil on the skin can help rejuvenate the cells as it has antioxidants and fatty acids which help with dry skin<strong>. </strong>This can also be mixed with fine brown sugar and honey for a moisturising exfoliator</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Ella Gannon</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Ella Gannon and Juliey Pham; featured image from <em>metro.co.uk</em>.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/protecting-skin-sub-zero-temperatures/">Protecting Your Skin In Sub-Zero Temperatures</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/protecting-skin-sub-zero-temperatures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2654</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breaking Gender Binaries In Fashion And Beauty</title>
		<link>/breaking-gender-binaries-fashion-beauty/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=breaking-gender-binaries-fashion-beauty</link>
					<comments>/breaking-gender-binaries-fashion-beauty/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 18:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The fashion and beauty industry has traditionally been considered a feminine pursuit (despite a large proportion of the biggest designers being male, queue the eyeroll) with relatively strict gender binaries. Girls wear makeup and love fashion, boys can’t because fashion and makeup is frivolous and feminine; you know the drill. &#160; However, over the last [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/breaking-gender-binaries-fashion-beauty/">Breaking Gender Binaries In Fashion And Beauty</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">The fashion and beauty industry has traditionally been considered a feminine pursuit (despite a large proportion of the biggest designers being male, queue the eyeroll) with relatively strict gender binaries. Girls wear makeup and love fashion, boys can’t because fashion and makeup is frivolous and feminine; you know the drill.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>However, over the last few years we have seen huge changes in the recognition of different genders in the fashion and beauty industry. Whether it’s Jaden Smith advocating androgynous fashion by wearing skirts and dresses as often as he wears jeans. Or Ruby Rose representing gender fluidity in the public eye, comfortable in her masculinity and her femininity. Or Jeffree Star who doesn’t want to label himself as anything other than a person who loves makeup, wears heels and wigs, but doesn’t see it as a gendered choice. There has undeniably been a shift in the way the public view gender in relation to fashion and beauty in recent times. Turns out, boys can like fashion and makeup too! Who knew?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There have always been celebrities who have challenged gender stereotypes. Julia Roberts accepted her first Golden Globe in 1990 wearing an oversized suit and Brendon Urie has been rocking that classic black eyeliner for decades. But in recent years more and more celebrities are celebrating the diversity of gender and representing it in their own unique ways. Tilda Swinton’s androgynous style or Lady Gaga’s ever-experimental fashion choices are just two examples of women looking fashion designers in the eye and saying those infamous words<em> “Florals? For Spring? Groundbreaking.”</em> If Miranda Priestly isn’t content with spring florals, then why should modern women be content with traditionally ‘feminine’ fashion? Fashion is about creative expression and freedom, not antiquated ideas about what men and women should and shouldn’t wear. And it would seem that the fashion industry has finally started catching up.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>On the other side of things, it would seem that men are equally tired of pretending that they don’t care if their belt matches their shoes, or that they don’t secretly put some concealer on a spot. With a surge of male-identifying social media influencers publicly expressing themselves through the medium of makeup, men like Manny MUA, James Charles and Patrick Starr are uploading reviews and tutorials and slaying the game; proving that there is no reason a guy can’t beat his face to perfection, wear a wig or get his nails done. It opens the door for ‘ordinary’ boys and men to try their hand at contouring. For those of you who have been watching <em>Educating Manchester</em>, Mitchell Farrelly is just one example of a young boy who openly enjoys and wears makeup in his daily life; he picked up the beauty blender and didn’t care what anyone else thought.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Even mainstream brands are picking up on the idea of gender neutral fashion, with John Lewis’ recent decision to make their childrenswear genderless. Perhaps this suggests that the future of fashion won’t be tied to outdated ideas of gender.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The fashion and beauty industry are being forced to keep up with the changing face of gender diversity. Transgender women like Laverne Cox are being given opportunities to publicly embrace their femininity in a variety of ways, instead of feeling ashamed of their gender identity; the fashion and beauty worlds are embracing them. ‘Plus size’ men and women who have rarely been given the chance to dress fashionably before, are seeing plus size ranges pop up in retailers like ASOS, offering a whole new world of fashion. All of which is heralded by influencers and models like Tess and Nick Holliday, who are unapologetically ‘plus size’ <em>and </em>fashionable. The changes in this industry are the first steps in a much larger journey to a fashion and beauty world that celebrates diversity in all its forms, not just the prepackaged white, slim feminine ‘ideal’.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So maybe you’d like to knock down a few bricks in that gender wall, but you aren’t sure how. SUBCULTURED have a few ideas on how you can be part of the movement to diversify fashion, to experiment with your own concepts of femininity and masculinity and find your style, unique to you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol>
<li>Try masculine/feminine scents (depending on which gender -if any- you identify with!). There’s no reason a woman can’t smell like sandalwood if she wants to, and a man should be able to enjoy a light floral scent if he’s so inclined. It’s a small, subtle way of challenging gender stereotypes.</li>
<li>Try a more minimalist style, the androgyny vibe is versatile and so easy to wear. But doesn’t immediately scream “I’m a guy in a mini skirt!”</li>
<li>If you’re traditionally ‘masculine’ try some basic ‘everyday’ makeup, a little concealer and a light layer of mascara can go a long way. Experimenting with makeup in any capacity is a fun way to look at your style differently, there are no rules and it washes off &#8211; so go ahead and try something new.</li>
<li>Try different hair looks, maybe you’ve always secretly wanted short hair but you’ve been afraid you’ll look boyish. Or the opposite, that growing out your hair long is too feminine. If you’re ready to give gender stereotypes the middle finger, just go for it. And if you hate it, well there’s always a wig.</li>
</ol>
<p>Ultimately, listen to yourself. If you’re wearing clothes because you feel like you <em>should </em>be wearing that style and not because you want to, change it. If you love the artistry of makeup and think you could rock a smokey eye, do it. Live authentically and don’t be held back by society&#8217;s definitions of gender. You do you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Holly Butteriss</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Donna Darafshian; featured image from <em>beautylish.com</em>.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/breaking-gender-binaries-fashion-beauty/">Breaking Gender Binaries In Fashion And Beauty</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/breaking-gender-binaries-fashion-beauty/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2470</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Korean Skincare: The Low-Down</title>
		<link>/korean-skincare-low/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=korean-skincare-low</link>
					<comments>/korean-skincare-low/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As someone who has dealt with more than their fair share of acne, as well as the countless trips to the dermatologist that come with it, finding a skincare regime that works for me has been a quest. However, after discovering the 10-step skincare routine last March, it’s truly revolutionised the way I look after [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/korean-skincare-low/">Korean Skincare: The Low-Down</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">As someone who has dealt with more than their fair share of acne, as well as the countless trips to the dermatologist that come with it, finding a skincare regime that works for me has been a quest. However, after discovering the 10-step skincare routine last March, it’s truly revolutionised the way I look after my acne-prone combination (oily and dry) skin. With the country investing so much in skincare, Korea’s products use technology seven years ahead of that found in Western products; it’s no surprise that the world of beauty is turning towards the East for inspiration; BB creams, sheet masks and the increased use of collagen are only a taste of what is on offer.</p>
<p>The products we’ve recommended have been checked on <em>cosdna.com</em> so that none of the ingredients have an irritant or acne rating of above 2, making them acceptable to use on acne-prone and sensitive skin.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Step 1: Oil Cleansing:</strong> A first cleanse used to remove oil-based debris from the surface of the skin; think make-up, sunscreen and pollution. The double cleansing method is unique to Korean skincare, and ensures that the face is as clean as possible.</p>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Product Recommendation:</span> Banila Co. Clean-It Zero Cleansing Balm</em></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1960" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1960" data-attachment-id="1960" data-permalink="/korean-skincare-low/banila_co_classic/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Banila_Co_Classic.jpg?fit=1200%2C628&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1200,628" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Banila_Co_Classic" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Banila_Co_Classic.jpg?fit=300%2C157&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Banila_Co_Classic.jpg?fit=1024%2C536&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1960" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Banila_Co_Classic.jpg?resize=1200%2C628" alt="via sokoglam.com" width="1200" height="628" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Banila_Co_Classic.jpg?w=1200&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Banila_Co_Classic.jpg?resize=300%2C157&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Banila_Co_Classic.jpg?resize=1024%2C536&amp;ssl=1 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1960" class="wp-caption-text">via sokoglam.com</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Step 2: Foam Cleansing:</strong> This removes dirt from further inside the pores. Simply lather your preferred cleanser before applying it on the face, being sure to spend at least minute cleansing using gentle, circular motions with your fingers.</p>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Product Recommendation:</span> COSRX Low pH Good Morning Gel Cleanser</em></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1961" style="width: 490px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1961" data-attachment-id="1961" data-permalink="/korean-skincare-low/cosrx-low-ph-morning-gel-cleanser-01/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/COSRX-Low-pH-Morning-Gel-Cleanser-01.jpg?fit=480%2C480&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="480,480" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="COSRX-Low-pH-Morning-Gel-Cleanser-01" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/COSRX-Low-pH-Morning-Gel-Cleanser-01.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/COSRX-Low-pH-Morning-Gel-Cleanser-01.jpg?fit=480%2C480&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1961" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/COSRX-Low-pH-Morning-Gel-Cleanser-01.jpg?resize=480%2C480" alt="via sokoglam.com" width="480" height="480" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/COSRX-Low-pH-Morning-Gel-Cleanser-01.jpg?w=480&amp;ssl=1 480w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/COSRX-Low-pH-Morning-Gel-Cleanser-01.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/COSRX-Low-pH-Morning-Gel-Cleanser-01.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/COSRX-Low-pH-Morning-Gel-Cleanser-01.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1961" class="wp-caption-text">via sokoglam.com</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Step 3: Exfoliating:</strong> Ideally done twice a month, helping to improve skin turn-over, reducing the ability for acne to develop. This step helps improve the circulation in the face, resulting in a natural glow.</p>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Product Recommendation:</span> Holika Holika Smoothie Peeling Jam (Grape Expectation)</em></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1962" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1962" data-attachment-id="1962" data-permalink="/korean-skincare-low/smoothiepeelingjam75ml__46599-1409216464-500-750/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/SmoothiePeelingJam75ml__46599.1409216464.500.750.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="500,500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="SmoothiePeelingJam75ml__46599.1409216464.500.750" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/SmoothiePeelingJam75ml__46599.1409216464.500.750.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/SmoothiePeelingJam75ml__46599.1409216464.500.750.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1962" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/SmoothiePeelingJam75ml__46599.1409216464.500.750.jpg?resize=500%2C500" alt="via holikaholika.com.my" width="500" height="500" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/SmoothiePeelingJam75ml__46599.1409216464.500.750.jpg?w=500&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/SmoothiePeelingJam75ml__46599.1409216464.500.750.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/SmoothiePeelingJam75ml__46599.1409216464.500.750.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/SmoothiePeelingJam75ml__46599.1409216464.500.750.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1962" class="wp-caption-text">via holikaholika.com.my</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Step 4: Toner:</strong> This step is commonly overlooked, but really important in regulating the ph levels of the skin, removing residue from your cleanser and for providing the perfect base for the layers that are yet to come. Toners are very watery, so are best applied with a cotton pad.</p>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Product Recommendation:</span> Etude House Wonder Pore Freshner 10-in-1</em></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1963" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1963" data-attachment-id="1963" data-permalink="/korean-skincare-low/wonder-pore-freshner-10-in-1-2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Wonder-Pore-Freshner-10-in-1-2.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="500,500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Wonder-Pore-Freshner-10-in-1-2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Wonder-Pore-Freshner-10-in-1-2.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Wonder-Pore-Freshner-10-in-1-2.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1963" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Wonder-Pore-Freshner-10-in-1-2.jpg?resize=500%2C500" alt="via ikute.vn" width="500" height="500" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Wonder-Pore-Freshner-10-in-1-2.jpg?w=500&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Wonder-Pore-Freshner-10-in-1-2.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Wonder-Pore-Freshner-10-in-1-2.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Wonder-Pore-Freshner-10-in-1-2.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1963" class="wp-caption-text">via ikute.vn</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Step 5: Sheet Masks:</strong> Although many Korean women use a sheet mask a day, twice a week is enough to reap the benefits. A material layer soaked in an essence featuring ingredients such as collagen or aloe vera. These allow the skin to absorb the ingredients better than just using a cream, as the sheet acts as a blanket, slowing down the rate at which the product evaporates.</p>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Product Recommendation:</span> Etude House I Need You Mask &#8211; Green Tea Mask</em></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1964" style="width: 549px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1964" data-attachment-id="1964" data-permalink="/korean-skincare-low/etude_house_-_i_need_you_mask_-_green_tea/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Etude_House_-_I_Need_You_Mask_-_Green_Tea.jpg?fit=539%2C555&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="539,555" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Etude_House_-_I_Need_You_Mask_-_Green_Tea" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Etude_House_-_I_Need_You_Mask_-_Green_Tea.jpg?fit=291%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Etude_House_-_I_Need_You_Mask_-_Green_Tea.jpg?fit=539%2C555&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1964" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Etude_House_-_I_Need_You_Mask_-_Green_Tea.jpg?resize=539%2C555" alt="via laalaa-ca.myshopify.com" width="539" height="555" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Etude_House_-_I_Need_You_Mask_-_Green_Tea.jpg?w=539&amp;ssl=1 539w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Etude_House_-_I_Need_You_Mask_-_Green_Tea.jpg?resize=291%2C300&amp;ssl=1 291w" sizes="(max-width: 539px) 100vw, 539px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1964" class="wp-caption-text">via laalaa-ca.myshopify.com</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Step 6 &amp; 7:</strong> <strong>Essences and Emulsions:</strong> These affect the skin on a cellular level, and as they are the first product to go into the pores, they have arguably the greatest effect. Essences help increase the cell turnover rate, helping reduce levels of acne and for improving and brightening dark spots, such as acne scars.</p>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Product Recommendation:</span> COSRX Advanced Snail 96 Mucin Power Essence</em></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1965" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1965" data-attachment-id="1965" data-permalink="/korean-skincare-low/dsc_0516/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/DSC_0516.jpg?fit=600%2C400&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="600,400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="DSC_0516" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/DSC_0516.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/DSC_0516.jpg?fit=600%2C400&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1965" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/DSC_0516.jpg?resize=600%2C400" alt="via chubbylamb.ca" width="600" height="400" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/DSC_0516.jpg?w=600&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/DSC_0516.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/DSC_0516.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1965" class="wp-caption-text">via chubbylamb.ca</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Step 8:</strong> <strong>Serums:</strong> Serums can be layered on top of each other in order to combat more than one skin issue. For example, one may use a vitamin c serum to brighten the skin and a serum featuring collagen to aid with skin healing.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em>Product Recommendation:</em></span><em> Skin Food Black Sugar Perfect First Serum</em></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1966" style="width: 730px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1966" data-attachment-id="1966" data-permalink="/korean-skincare-low/skinfood-black-sugar-perfect-first-serum_2/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/skinfood-black-sugar-perfect-first-serum_2.jpg?fit=720%2C480&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="720,480" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="skinfood-black-sugar-perfect-first-serum_2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/skinfood-black-sugar-perfect-first-serum_2.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/skinfood-black-sugar-perfect-first-serum_2.jpg?fit=720%2C480&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1966" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/skinfood-black-sugar-perfect-first-serum_2.jpg?resize=720%2C480" alt="via awesomejulianne.com" width="720" height="480" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/skinfood-black-sugar-perfect-first-serum_2.jpg?w=720&amp;ssl=1 720w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/skinfood-black-sugar-perfect-first-serum_2.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/skinfood-black-sugar-perfect-first-serum_2.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1966" class="wp-caption-text">via awesomejulianne.com</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Step 9:</strong> <strong>Ampoule:</strong> Often referred to as ‘serums’ in the Western beauty market, they are more concentrated versions of essences.</p>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Product Recommendation:</span> Missha Time Revolution Night Repair Science Activator Ampoule </em>(Note that this product has the same key ingredients as the Estee Lauder Advanced Night Repair, but is half of the price.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1967" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1967" data-attachment-id="1967" data-permalink="/korean-skincare-low/time_revolution_night_repair_science_activator_ampoule/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/time_revolution_night_repair_science_activator_ampoule.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="500,500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="time_revolution_night_repair_science_activator_ampoule" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/time_revolution_night_repair_science_activator_ampoule.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/time_revolution_night_repair_science_activator_ampoule.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1967" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/time_revolution_night_repair_science_activator_ampoule.jpg?resize=500%2C500" alt="via misshaus.com" width="500" height="500" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/time_revolution_night_repair_science_activator_ampoule.jpg?w=500&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/time_revolution_night_repair_science_activator_ampoule.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/time_revolution_night_repair_science_activator_ampoule.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/time_revolution_night_repair_science_activator_ampoule.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1967" class="wp-caption-text">via misshaus.com</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Step 10:</strong> <strong>Night Cream (Night):</strong> A thick layer of aloe vera helps lock in the moisture, which is particularly important for oily skin; the more moisture the skin receives, the less sebum it will produce, in turn regulating the skin’s oil production.</p>
<p><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Product Recommendation:</span> Nature Republic Aloe Vera 92% Soothing Gel</em></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1968" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1968" data-attachment-id="1968" data-permalink="/korean-skincare-low/avgsplash/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/AVGSplash.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="500,500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="AVGSplash" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/AVGSplash.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/AVGSplash.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1968" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/AVGSplash.jpg?resize=500%2C500" alt="via snowwhiteandtheasianpear.com" width="500" height="500" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/AVGSplash.jpg?w=500&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/AVGSplash.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/AVGSplash.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/AVGSplash.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1968" class="wp-caption-text">via snowwhiteandtheasianpear.com</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Amy Furney</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Juliey Pham and Donna Darafshian; featured image taken from <em>citygirlsearching.com</em>.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/korean-skincare-low/">Korean Skincare: The Low-Down</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/korean-skincare-low/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1957</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Student-Budget Beauty Buys</title>
		<link>/student-budget-beauty-buys/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=student-budget-beauty-buys</link>
					<comments>/student-budget-beauty-buys/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 18:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As students, we’ve all -pretty much- accepted living on a budget, which sometimes leads to buying items of lower quality than we’d usually expect (thank you Student Finance!). And for those of us who like to keep up to date with the beauty world, it can feel as if miracle products are being teased in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/student-budget-beauty-buys/">Student-Budget Beauty Buys</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">As students, we’ve all -pretty much- accepted living on a budget, which sometimes leads to buying items of lower quality than we’d usually expect (thank you Student Finance!).<br />
And for those of us who like to keep up to date with the beauty world, it can feel as if miracle products are being teased in front of us daily, but our tight pockets don’t always allow us to buy the latest palette or foundation reviewed by Jeffree Star or Nikkie Tutorials. Because, come on &#8211; who has $1000 lying around to spend on a 24K gold face mask?</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1858" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1858" data-attachment-id="1858" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o.jpg?fit=1024%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,1024" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o.jpg?fit=1024%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1858 size-medium" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300" alt="17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17342056_10207088858698978_1017873100_o.jpg?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1858" class="wp-caption-text">via adorecosmetics.com</p></div></p>
<p>It&#8217;s so easy to become entranced by a particular brand or artist; but what if I told you there are fantastic, cheaper alternatives to palettes like Anastasia Beverley Hills’ Modern Renaissance, or Jeffree Star’s Peach Goddess Highlighter?</p>
<p><div class="sixcol first"></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1860" style="width: 770px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1860" data-attachment-id="1860" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17351315_10207088858658977_1265438219_n/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351315_10207088858658977_1265438219_n.jpg?fit=760%2C625&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="760,625" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17351315_10207088858658977_1265438219_n" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351315_10207088858658977_1265438219_n.jpg?fit=300%2C247&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351315_10207088858658977_1265438219_n.jpg?fit=760%2C625&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1860" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351315_10207088858658977_1265438219_n.jpg?resize=760%2C625" alt="via temptalia.com" width="760" height="625" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351315_10207088858658977_1265438219_n.jpg?w=760&amp;ssl=1 760w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351315_10207088858658977_1265438219_n.jpg?resize=300%2C247&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 760px) 100vw, 760px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1860" class="wp-caption-text">via temptalia.com</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></div><div class="sixcol last"></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1865" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1865" data-attachment-id="1865" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17360865_10207088859579000_752352116_n/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360865_10207088859579000_752352116_n.jpg?fit=600%2C600&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="600,600" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17360865_10207088859579000_752352116_n" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360865_10207088859579000_752352116_n.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360865_10207088859579000_752352116_n.jpg?fit=600%2C600&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1865" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360865_10207088859579000_752352116_n.jpg?resize=600%2C600" alt="via beautylish.com" width="600" height="600" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360865_10207088859579000_752352116_n.jpg?w=600&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360865_10207088859579000_752352116_n.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360865_10207088859579000_752352116_n.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360865_10207088859579000_752352116_n.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-1865" class="wp-caption-text">via beautylish.com</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></div><div class="clearfix"></div>A short trip into Guildford town could save you a lot of money, and for some items, you don’t even have to leave your room! There are many UK friendly sites that skip the dreaded international shipping, and you don&#8217;t necessarily need to spend your rent to get a high-end look.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>Primer:</u></strong> <span style="color: #ff00ff;"><em><a style="color: #ff00ff;" href="http://www.nyxcosmetics.com/angel-veil-skin-perfecting-primer/NYX_139.html" target="_blank">NYX Angel Veil</a></em></span>, £13, Boots</p>
<p>Perfect for all skin types, as it both hydrates and minimizes shine while creating a flawless base for makeup. Can be worn alone for a more even complexion.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="1857" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n.jpg?fit=400%2C400&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="400,400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n.jpg?fit=400%2C400&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1857 size-medium" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300" alt="17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17328031_10207088854898883_592093797_n.jpg?w=400&amp;ssl=1 400w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>Foundation:</u></strong> <span style="color: #ff00ff;"><em><a style="color: #ff00ff;" href="https://www.walgreens.com/store/c/maybelline-fit-me!-matte-%2B-poreless-foundation/ID=prod6268422-product" target="_blank">Maybelline Fit Me Matte And Poreless Foundation</a></em></span>, £7.99, Boots</p>
<p>Blurred pores and long-lasting wear in 19 versatile shades for normal to oily skin.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="1854" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n.jpg?fit=400%2C400&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="400,400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n.jpg?fit=400%2C400&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1854 size-medium" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300" alt="17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17274667_10207088854938884_1413006258_n.jpg?w=400&amp;ssl=1 400w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>Contour/Highlight:</u></strong> <em><span style="color: #ff00ff;"><a style="color: #ff00ff;" href="https://www.tambeauty.com/en/Makeup-Revolution-Ultra-Palette-Golden-Sugar-2---Blush-Bronze-and-Highlight/m-1372.aspx" target="_blank">Makeup Revolution Ultra Contour Palette</a></span></em>, £8, Superdrug/tambeauty.com</p>
<p>Extremely versatile palette that include contour, highlight, and blush. Comes in various editions, including rose gold, and has a cream alternative.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="1855" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o.jpg?fit=1000%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1000,1000" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o.jpg?fit=1000%2C1000&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1855 size-medium" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300" alt="17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17310490_10207088855098888_928205331_o.jpg?w=1000&amp;ssl=1 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>Blush:</u></strong> <span style="color: #ff00ff;"><em><a style="color: #ff00ff;" href="http://www.bourjois.co.uk/catalog/make_up/complexion/blush/little_round_pot_blush" target="_blank">Bourjois Little Round Pot Blush</a></em></span>, £7.99, Boots/Superdrug</p>
<p>Adorable, transportable little pot in 21 different shades for every look.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="1862" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n.png?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="500,500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n.png?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n.png?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1862 size-medium" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n-300x300.png?resize=300%2C300" alt="17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n.png?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n.png?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n.png?w=500&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17352615_10207088859619001_722503195_n.png?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>Powder:</u></strong> <span style="color: #ff00ff;"><em><a style="color: #ff00ff;" href="https://www.makeupalley.com/product/showreview.asp/ItemId=176825/HD-PRO-Setting-Powder/L.A.-Girl/Loose-Powders" target="_blank">L.A Girl Pro Powder</a></em></span>, £6, beautybay.com</p>
<p>Sets makeup perfectly in place, and reduces the appearance of lines by stopping foundation from settling into creases in the skin. Apply under eyes with a damp sponge and then brush off for best anti-creasing results.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="1863" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="500,500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1863 size-medium" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300" alt="17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n.jpg?w=500&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17354702_10207088859538999_1728949346_n.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>Setting Spray:</u></strong> <span style="color: #ff00ff;"><em><a style="color: #ff00ff;" href="http://www.eyeslipsface.co.uk/studio/face/tools/matte_magic_mist_set" target="_blank">e.l.f. Studio Matte Magic Mist &amp; Set</a></em></span>, £5, eyeslipsface.co.uk</p>
<p>A light spray to lock in hydration and hold on makeup for an all-day stay.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="1861" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n.png?fit=900%2C900&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="900,900" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n.png?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n.png?fit=900%2C900&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1861 size-medium" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n-300x300.png?resize=300%2C300" alt="17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n.png?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n.png?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n.png?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17351355_10207088855058887_1431235091_n.png?w=900&amp;ssl=1 900w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>Mascara:</u></strong> <span style="color: #ff00ff;"><em><a style="color: #ff00ff;" href="https://uk.rimmellondon.com/products/eyes/scandaleyes-reloaded-waterproof" target="_blank">Rimmel Scandaleyes Reloaded Waterproof</a></em></span>, £6.99, Boots/Superdrug</p>
<p>Thick brush to grab and coat every lash for intense volume and length. Bright orange packaging means you won&#8217;t lose it in your bag either!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="1877" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/rimmel_scandaleyes_reloaded_waterproof_final_1-3_0/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/rimmel_scandaleyes_reloaded_waterproof_final_1-3_0.jpg?fit=204%2C680&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="204,680" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="rimmel_scandaleyes_reloaded_waterproof_final_1-3_0" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/rimmel_scandaleyes_reloaded_waterproof_final_1-3_0.jpg?fit=90%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/rimmel_scandaleyes_reloaded_waterproof_final_1-3_0.jpg?fit=204%2C680&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1877 size-medium" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/rimmel_scandaleyes_reloaded_waterproof_final_1-3_0-90x300.jpg?resize=90%2C300" alt="rimmel_scandaleyes_reloaded_waterproof_final_1-3_0" width="90" height="300" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/rimmel_scandaleyes_reloaded_waterproof_final_1-3_0.jpg?resize=90%2C300&amp;ssl=1 90w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/rimmel_scandaleyes_reloaded_waterproof_final_1-3_0.jpg?w=204&amp;ssl=1 204w" sizes="(max-width: 90px) 100vw, 90px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p><strong><u>Brows:</u></strong> <em><span style="color: #ff00ff;"><a style="color: #ff00ff;" href="http://www.kikocosmetics.com/en-gb/make-up/eyes/eyebrows//p-KM0030800900144" target="_blank">KIKO Precison Pencil</a></span></em>, £5.90, KIKO Cosmetics</p>
<p>Easy use pencil with a brush on one end to tidy any stray hairs. Various colours for all hair types.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="1864" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n.jpg?fit=900%2C900&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="900,900" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Spring Studios&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n.jpg?fit=900%2C900&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1864 size-medium" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300" alt="17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17360793_10207088859699003_939078500_n.jpg?w=900&amp;ssl=1 900w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>Palettes:</u></strong> <span style="color: #ff00ff;"><em><a style="color: #ff00ff;" href="http://www.bhcosmetics.com/28-neutral-eyeshadow-color-palette" target="_blank">BH Cosmetics Neutral Eyes 28 Colour Eyeshadow Palette</a></em></span> (varying editions), £13, beautybay.com</p>
<p>Beautifully pigmented matte and shimmer eyeshadows for excellent value; 28 shades included.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="1856" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="500,500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n.jpg?fit=500%2C500&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1856 size-medium" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300" alt="17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n.jpg?w=500&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17321555_10207088858538974_585108833_n.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>Lips:</u></strong> <em><span style="color: #ff00ff;"><a style="color: #ff00ff;" href="https://milanicosmetics.com/Amore-Matte-Lip-Creme.html" target="_blank">Milani Amore Matte Lip Crème</a></span></em>, £9.99, Boots/milanimakeup.co.uk</p>
<p>31 matte shades with metallic twins. Affordable and good quality for a high-street liquid lip.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="1859" data-permalink="/student-budget-beauty-buys/17349287_10207088858578975_407905701_o/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17349287_10207088858578975_407905701_o.jpg?fit=914%2C1040&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="914,1040" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Lynda Green&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="17349287_10207088858578975_407905701_o" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17349287_10207088858578975_407905701_o.jpg?fit=264%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17349287_10207088858578975_407905701_o.jpg?fit=900%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1859 size-medium" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17349287_10207088858578975_407905701_o-264x300.jpg?resize=264%2C300" alt="17349287_10207088858578975_407905701_o" width="264" height="300" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17349287_10207088858578975_407905701_o.jpg?resize=264%2C300&amp;ssl=1 264w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17349287_10207088858578975_407905701_o.jpg?resize=900%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 900w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/17349287_10207088858578975_407905701_o.jpg?w=914&amp;ssl=1 914w" sizes="(max-width: 264px) 100vw, 264px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Holly Gibbons</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Holly Gibbons, Juliey Pham and Donna Darafshian; featured image taken from Danielle Smith&#8217;s blog (Miss Sunshine and Sparkle).</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/student-budget-beauty-buys/">Student-Budget Beauty Buys</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/student-budget-beauty-buys/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1833</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
