<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Film Review &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/culture/film-review/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A fashion, culture, art and music publication, written by students about students.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 18:49:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/cropped-12773305_10206631248554054_481252708_o.jpg?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Film Review &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107671177</site>	<item>
		<title>The Social Dilemma Review &#8211; “The Greatest Existential Threat Of Our Time?”</title>
		<link>/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time</link>
					<comments>/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 17:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Social media &#8211; the biggest existential threat that we&#8217;ve ever faced? SUBCULTURED takes a look at the latest Netflix film kicking up some dirt on Silicon Valley&#8217;s biggest tech companies. The Social Dilemma, which arrived on Netflix earlier this month, is an exposing docu-drama from Jeff Orlowski, with help from a vast club of co-founders [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/">The Social Dilemma Review &#8211; “The Greatest Existential Threat Of Our Time?”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Social media &#8211; the biggest existential threat that we&#8217;ve ever faced? SUBCULTURED takes a look at the latest Netflix film kicking up some dirt on Silicon Valley&#8217;s biggest tech companies.</strong></p>



<p><em>The Social Dilemma</em>, which arrived on Netflix earlier this month, is an exposing docu-drama from Jeff Orlowski, with help from a vast club of co-founders and designers who have now left some of the most influential social media companies in the world. The title nods to the popular 2010 film &#8216;<em>The Social Network</em>&#8216;, attempting to unpick the platform and other social media sites, while unearthing the dark truths behind these companies.</p>



<p>The film opens with slick camera shots against modernistic backgrounds, as various tech experts disclose their ex-Silicon Valley employers before their interviews begin. It is apparent that they are about to expose some of what goes on behind our screens; they seem nervous, as if unsure how their revelations will be received. One former Google employee awkwardly reveals that he &#8220;spent eight months talking back and forth with lawyers&#8221; about this interview, before others express their concern for the ethics of the companies they worked for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the next scene, we are presented with a dystopian-style barrage of social media-related American news reports on teenagers’ mental health, extremist groups, mass violence and Coronavirus misinformation. The essence of the problem, as explained by main contributor Tristan Harris and his industry friends, is this: the biggest tech companies are no longer the ones who simply create a product and sell it to their users. Instead, they are the ones whose customers are advertisers who pay to show their ads; and the product is you.</p>



<p>Their goal, then, becomes &#8220;how can we capture as much of their attention as possible?”, to hook us on the app, resulting in more ad exposure. These apps are therefore designed to be as addictive as possible, exploiting psychological vulnerabilities; meanwhile, the algorithms determine what to show us that will best engage us based on the data they have. These algorithms, however, are blind to false information and tend to bias extreme content and ideas, polarising nations and encouraging conspiracy theories and extremist groups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Not only does social media create its own problems of addiction, depression and anxiety; it also divides and misinforms, preventing people from focusing on solutions to the bigger issues at hand. Combined, these implications mean social media is fast being considered an existential threat to our humanity.</p>



<p>The film is interlaced with emotive dramatizations portraying the extreme capabilities of the technology we interact with on a level nothing short of a typical Black Mirror episode &#8211; also equipped with all of the eerie nostalgia and unsettling intensity courtesy of the background music.</p>



<p>However, the enactments create the challenge of distinguishing frenzied exaggeration from true portrayal; it&#8217;s hard to tell what data your devices are collecting from you, or to what extent different apps can use this data; do they really wait for gaps in your calendar app to ping an enticing notification your way? Do they really queue posts in your news feed from a person who is near to your location, and if so, is it really as stark as its Hollywood portrayal? It’s unclear which of the capabilities of these apps is the hard, cold truth, and how much is pure hyperbole designed &#8211; quite ironically &#8211; to get our attention?</p>



<p>Confusingly, the film seems to peddle the idea that social media companies are using manipulative, persuasive features to addict their users to the apps, while the co-founder and ex-designer interviewees seem reluctant to admit that there was anything inherently misguided about the way that they designed these apps. “nobody, I believe, ever intended any of these consequences”, reports former Twitter Executive Jeff Seibert. Some level of unfiltered honesty is displayed, but not a full admission of guilt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sure, the kind of gratification you get from receiving an email or notification is fairly unavoidable, but the hijacking of these addictive pathways is clearly deliberate. but there are blatant and intentional ways that the addictive pathways are being designed, too. Sean Parker, former president of Facebook, says of this manipulation, &#8220;[We all] understood this. But we did it anyway.&#8221; Surely, they couldn’t pretend to be ‘victims of a dangerous business model’. Perhaps this reveals the dark side of what went on &#8211; and is still going on &#8211; within these companies.</p>



<p>Ultimately, the “attention extraction” model that these companies have adopted, which views human beings as a resource to profit from, isn’t much less of a definition of exploitation than slavery or human trafficking. It&#8217;s just that this new kind of abuse and manipulation is far subtler, embedded in hidden webs of human psychology and algorithmic complexity; and therefore, all the more dangerous.</p>



<p>After taking on a rather solemn tone towards the end, with talk of the inevitable entrapment that the advertising business model and shareholder pressure bring, the film ends with a more optimistic, spirited call to remember what technology was created to be — something that helped us and connected us. This kind of technology can be designed humanely by returning to our original goal: “How do we make the world a better place, for everyone?” It’s what we all want, and it’s what social media companies promised; but it&#8217;s not delivering.</p>



<p>At least these ex-employees of the big tech companies have moved on, and begun to expose and discuss the secrets from within the industry. Have they helped to create these problems? Yes. Should you trust them? Probably. Having left the companies, contributed to this film, and some even helped to found an institute pursuing a humane technology agenda, you&#8217;d better believe them. In fact, our future may depend on it.</p>



<p><em>The Social Dilemma is available now on Netflix. To find out more about the project behind the film and continue the conversation, go to <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.thesocialdilemma.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">www.thesocialdilemma.com</a></span>.</em></p>



<p><strong>Text by Barney Venable<br>Featured image via <em>Forbes</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/">The Social Dilemma Review &#8211; “The Greatest Existential Threat Of Our Time?”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4343</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Netflix’s Indian Matchmaking: A Step Forwards Or Backwards For South Asian Culture?</title>
		<link>/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture</link>
					<comments>/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 18:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While mainstream TV shows and films helmed by South Asians were once few and far between, the increasing diversification of media indicates that one-note depictions of South Asians might soon become a thing of the past. But, at present, with so few cultural touchpoints when it comes to representations of South Asians, the stakes are [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/">Netflix’s Indian Matchmaking: A Step Forwards Or Backwards For South Asian Culture?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>While mainstream TV shows and films helmed by South Asians were once few and far between, the increasing diversification of media indicates that one-note depictions of South Asians might soon become a thing of the past. But, at present, with so few cultural touchpoints when it comes to representations of South Asians, the stakes are higher. In this light, it’s easy to understand why South Asians are divided over Netflix’s latest runaway hit <em>Indian Matchmaking</em>, which explores the contentious practice of arranged marriage. Some have argued that the show is a step backwards, <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/scaachikoul/indian-matchmaking-criticism-family-karma" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">presenting “South Asian identity” as “uniquely fraught,”</span></a> while others argue the show is just <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/07/indian-matchmaking-dating-reality-tv-colorism.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“telling it like it is.”</a>&nbsp;</span></p>



<p>Showrunner Smriti Mundhra was as frustrated as some of her critics with shows that were only <a href="https://medium.com/the-international-wave/interview-with-smriti-mundhra-storytelling-without-a-script-9edb2b7848ae" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">“about the trauma and the stereotypes that our communities are known for,”</span></a> seeking to present a fluffier alternative. <a href="https://medium.com/the-international-wave/interview-with-smriti-mundhra-storytelling-without-a-script-9edb2b7848ae" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">In an interview preceding its release on Netflix</span></a>, she stated that she “packaged” <em>Indian Matchmaking, </em>which<em> </em>documents matchmaker Sima Taparia as she journeys between India and America to find her clients a suitable spouse, as “a fun dating show” in the hopes that it would “be more accessible to a wider range of people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Inevitably, the South Asian community formed the show’s largest and most vocal viewership. The show is wryly funny, lightly ribbing some of the ridiculous views that are often espoused by South Asians, its editing poking fun at the absurd criteria that Taparia’s clients insist on and interspersing her meme-able observations in between scenes depicting her clients on their quest for love. Multiple episodes of the show open with <em>When Harry Met Sally</em>-esque interviews featuring bickering couples who had an arranged marriage, adding to its sentimental feel. At first glance, its cast seems to be formed of caricatures of South Asians we know and may or may not love – the highly-strung overachiever, the regressive aunty, the overbearing mother and the coddled mummy’s boy. However, the show does not solely relegate its cast to sources of comedy. In part, it endeavours to demonstrate a fuller picture of who Taparia’s clients are and why they ended up in front of her, such as fan favourite Nadia, who seeks to find a partner who is accepting of both her Indian and Guyanese heritage and Ankita, a self-assured businesswoman who is ready to move onto the next stage of her life, but only on her own terms.</p>



<p>As much as the <em>Indian Matchmaking</em> audience’s familiarity with the communities and cultures heightens its relatability and humour, it also renders its lurid veneer transparent. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2020/08/netflix-indian-matchmaking-and-the-shadow-of-caste/614863/?utm_source=feed" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">As Yashica Dutt writes</a></span>, the show’s “coding” of caste through seemingly benign phrases like “shared communities” or “respectable families” serves to disfigure the reality of the caste system and the discrimination and violence it creates. Many have criticised the show for being uncritical of the misogyny upheld by matchmakers and clients alike, who idealise fair skin and prize compliance to men, insisting that potential brides be “flexible,” while women who are unwavering in their standards are labelled “not stable.” It has not gone unnoticed that the burdens of belonging to such a family-orientated and image-based culture and the resulting pressure to conform, as well as the consequences of not conforming,&nbsp; are a frequent theme in the storylines of nearly all of Taparia’s clients.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mundhra is well aware of the arguments surrounding her subject, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.thecut.com/2020/07/indian-matchmaking-review.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">having faced pressure to have an arranged marriage herself</a></span>, as well as having directed the slightly more critical documentary<em> A Suitable Girl </em>in 2017. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.glamour.com/story/netflix-indian-matchmaking" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Her own view of arranged marriage</a></span> is that “it was designed to preserve caste and class and to subjugate women,” but that it has since “evolved from that.” She appears to argue that arranged marriage is a choice, that, as <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-53499195" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Anna MM Vetticad states</span></a>, it is merely “a practical Indian version of the dating game in the West,” whereby the only difference is that your potential matches are presented to you by your parents and matchmaker rather than Tinder. It’s an argument that may ring familiar to many South Asians for whom this half-truth is a balm to their affection for their culture against Western paternalism and condescension. Yet, in spite of the optimistic perspective that informs it, <em>Indian Matchmaking’s</em> light-hearted approach jars with the tensions implicit in the situations we witness, almost satirical in its absurdity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In&nbsp; acknowledgement of the criticism of<em> Indian Matchmaking</em>,&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.glamour.com/story/netflix-indian-matchmaking" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mundhra has stated that</a></span> “It’s not possible to show the entire perspective, of course, and the show leaves a lot on the table,” inviting others to hold her “accountable.” By relying on its audience to complete the unfinished picture that <em>Indian Matchmaking</em> presents of arranged marriage, particularly those most negatively affected by the prejudicial practices it upholds, the show admits its failure to prove its thesis. As it turns out, <a href="https://www.womenshealthmag.com/relationships/a33368001/indian-matchmaking-netflix-couples-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">none of Taparia’s clients that featured on the show found a match through her</span></a>. Sometimes, reality cannot be easily repackaged as a romcom. Nor should the unique struggles faced by South Asians living in the West, often tied to their cultures and traditions, be obscured, to prevent others viewing South Asian identity as “uniquely fraught.” As much as South Asians are tired of being represented as repressed objects of ridicule, it’s apparent that the solution is to treat these issues with nuance, not to sandpaper over the breadth of our experiences with generalised positivity.</p>



<p><strong>Text by Madhu Manivannan<br>Featured image via Vanity Fair.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/">Netflix’s Indian Matchmaking: A Step Forwards Or Backwards For South Asian Culture?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4282</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Film Fanatic&#8217;s Guide To Staycation</title>
		<link>/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation</link>
					<comments>/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 11:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown American chef Anthony Bourdain cited his experience filming an episode of his show Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations in Lebanon in the midst of the 2006 Israel-Lebanon War as having significantly reshaped his attitude towards his work. He remarked that “I just saw that there were realities beyond what was on my [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/">A Film Fanatic&#8217;s Guide To Staycation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong><em>Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown</em></strong></p>



<p>American chef Anthony Bourdain cited his experience filming an episode of his show <em>Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations</em> in Lebanon in the midst of the 2006 Israel-Lebanon War as having significantly reshaped his attitude towards his work. <a href="https://explorepartsunknown.com/beirut/field-notes-from-beirut/">He remarked that</a> “I just saw that there were realities beyond what was on my plate, and those realities almost inevitably informed what was—or was not—for dinner. To ignore them had come to seem monstrous.” <em>Anthony Bourdain:</em> <em>Parts Unknown</em> is a reflection of these realities, following Bourdain as he journeys around the world, sampling native delicacies from the Chickenjoy bucket at Jollibee to fish and chips in a greasy spoon. <em>Parts Unknown </em>is a celebration of food and its multifaceted significance, whether it serves a communal purpose or constitutes an expression of love, or it is rooted in historical significance and acts as an expression of identity and culture.</p>



<p><em>Seasons 1 to 12 available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>The Imagineering Story</em></strong></p>



<p>Over the past few months, many of us have realised that the American Dream is just that, a dream. One of the most tangible manifestations of this dream is Main Street, U.S.A., a themed area of Disneyland parks across the world, the first of which was inspired by Walt Disney’s childhood memories of growing up in Missouri. In many ways, the story told in <em>The Imagineering Story</em>, the story of the original Disneyland and its expansion across the world, is a story about America, as well as a tribute to the creative endeavors of the “Imagineers” who made the ornate attractions of Disneyland possible, albeit a whitewashed one. Among the companies admitting their past wrongdoings and vowing to do better in the wake of the Black Lives Matter protests was Disney, who finally decided to overhaul the last conspicuous acknowledgement of their racist 1946 film, <em>Song of the South</em>. The ride Splash Mountain will now be <a href="https://twitter.com/DisneyParks/status/1276187686672437249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1276187686672437249%7Ctwgr%5E&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.smithsonianmag.com%2Fsmart-news%2Fdisney-will-completely-reimagine-controversial-splash-mountain-ride-180975198%2F" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“<em>reimagined with a new story</em>”</a> inspired by <em>The Princess and the Frog</em>, the 2009 film that introduced Disney’s first Black princess, Tiana. As illustrated by <em>The Imagineering Story</em>, Disneyland continues to evolve alongside America, an amalgamation of its hopes and desires, both past and present. </p>



<p><em>Episodes 1 to 6 available on Disney+.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Elite</em></strong></p>



<p>Catch up on the frothy teen drama before the release of its fourth season, for which Netflix Spain recently revealed the four new additions to its cast. <em>Elite</em>’s first season revolves around three working class students who win a scholarship to study at an exclusive private school as they navigate high society alongside typical adolescent struggles. While it’s a hard sell on intellectual merit alone, the heightened melodrama and extravagance of <em>Elite</em> makes for pure mindless fun.</p>



<p><em>Seasons 1 to 3 available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Time to Hunt (2020)</em></strong></p>



<p>This South Korean thriller is set within a dystopia, where a financial crisis has devastated the South Korean economy. <em>Time to Hunt</em> follows a group of three small time criminals, one of whom is played by Choi Wooshik, who you may recognize as Kiwoo from Parasite. As they embark on one last heist to escape their miserable situation by leaving for Taiwan, things go awry as they are hunted down by a mysterious assassin. Although the ominous nature of the film’s setting may leave you with questions by the time the credits roll, it also serves to heighten the atmospheric and thrilling journey of the three protagonists while alluding to themes of class and brotherhood.</p>



<p><em>Available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>A Suitable Girl (2017)</em></strong></p>



<p>Netflix’s <em>Indian Matchmaking</em>, a reality TV show documenting matchmaker Sima Taparia from Mumbai as she attempts to find her clients a spouse, has set the South Asian diaspora ablaze. Discussion about the show is equally as abundant with memes as with disapproval for its uncritical depiction of arranged marriage, touching on but ultimately glossing over a host of issues such as colourism and misogyny. Taparia is presumably no stranger to such criticisms, having previously starred in <em>A Suitable Girl</em>, a documentary following three women in India, including Taparia’s daughter Ritu, as they search for a spouse and adjust to married life. <em>A Suitable Girl</em> focuses not on delightfully extravagant personalities like Pradhyuman and Aparna, but the experiences of ordinary women as they reflect on how notions of marriage and gender have shaped their lives. Unassuming yet powerful, <em>A Suitable Girl</em> is an insight into the quotidian cultural and familial pressures faced by Indian women.</p>



<p><em>Available on Netflix.&nbsp;&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><strong><em>The Half of It (2020)</em></strong></p>



<p><em>The Half of It</em> revolves around shy recluse Ellie Chu, a Chinese-American teenager on the cusp of adulthood who is stuck in the small town of Squahamish for the foreseeable future. Strapped for cash, she agrees to mediate on the behalf of inarticulate jock Paul Munsky who pays her to write love letters to his crush, the popular daughter of a conservative pastor, Aster Flores. However, Paul and Ellie learn that you can’t plan love, as the three teenagers’ feelings act independently of their preordained destinations, growing unexpectedly deeper and more complicated. Alice Wu’s first film since 2005’s <em>Saving Face</em> is a refreshing, funny and heartwarming take on the “teen movie”, investigating the interlinking themes of adolescent identity, friendship and love.</p>



<p><em>Available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong>Text by Madhu Manivannan<br>Featured image via <em>reddit.com</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/">A Film Fanatic&#8217;s Guide To Staycation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4267</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five Climate Conscious Flicks</title>
		<link>/five-climate-conscious-flicks/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=five-climate-conscious-flicks</link>
					<comments>/five-climate-conscious-flicks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bust lockdown boredom and catch up with our top 5 films championing environmental issues. Movies have the power to shape narratives, introduce new perspectives and they can be particularly compelling when bringing awareness to environmental issues. Below find SUBCULTURED writer Nathaniel’s recommendations, some are documentaries and some aren’t – but their stories are all a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/five-climate-conscious-flicks/">Five Climate Conscious Flicks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p style="font-size:18px"><strong>Bust lockdown boredom and catch up with our top 5 films championing environmental issues.</strong></p>



<p>Movies have the power to shape narratives, introduce new perspectives and they can be particularly compelling when bringing awareness to environmental issues.</p>



<p>Below find SUBCULTURED writer Nathaniel’s recommendations, some are documentaries and some aren’t – but their stories are all a must-watch.</p>



<p><strong><em>WALL-E</em> (2008)</strong> | Directed by Andrew Stanton &amp; Written by Andrew Stanton and Jim Reardon</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/aM4ZyAm7LUv2kYj7TXfyAaKRL8wUIZCSFnjGYDTcYrN_CITOqieE-5xsy-x5-Z41kVlyiCpAdfIessXisp2G9mIBfESER13uVhPpWnlcxNHDRRO88X96kINexon7uiBvV7rJMkc" alt="Nonconformity - Corpron_Transcendentalism"/></figure>



<p><em>WALL-E</em>’s cinematography and screenplay are amazing in depicting the story of WALL-E (standing for ‘Waste Allocation Load Lifter Earth-class’) [voiced by Ben Burtt], who’s the last robot on Earth. WALL-E’s tasked to tidy the planet as mankind’s had to abandon Earth after becoming filled with rubbish. WALL-E ultimately embarks on an exciting adventure when he meet EVE [voiced by Elissa Knight]: a sleek probe sent back to Earth on a scanning mission. However, one message is clear: we need to manage waste, look after nature and protect our planet. <em>WALL-E</em> won the 2008 Golden Globe Award for Best Animated Feature Film and 2009 Hugo Award for Best Long Form Dramatic Presentation.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Earth</em> (2007)</strong> | Directed by Alastair Fothergill and Mark Linfield &amp; Written Alastair Fothergill, Mark Linfield and Leslie Megahey</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/wdwfBTGNFdkZDcfAAhi8r1l8H8R0Rp54_tYc6v3VvHMzaW8vjt14oewQs06W9c6YTXiUzTpsafgvSA4UR7ggFATgVppSr-8Gl8p6MTvfum3WDx22hhOTZFLcr4JIm77nhC8xuhI" alt="Earth (2007 film) - Alchetron, The Free Social Encyclopedia"/></figure>



<p><em>Earth</em> documents a viewers’ journey from the North Pole to the South Pole over the course of twelve months; and focuses on the polar bear, the African bush elephant and the humpback whale. This film further follows a range of other animals in their natural environment during the calendar year. Cinematically, the film has stunning scenes, as time-lapse cameras are used to enable the enthralling action moments on screen. Based on the BBC’s Planet Earth: Patrick Stewart narrates this movie, which is the second highest grossing nature documentary of all time behind <em>March of the Penguins</em> (2005).</p>



<p><strong><em>Avatar</em> (2009)</strong> | Directed and Written by James Cameron</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/0tTZlxTBVwsP9xM55iBcPZTFBuQF08LulFHLij3FDTBOrIzJaLTh2_vOOS7gU_hbnP01ON_3bx0uaG7O-L36DIBtS7uS3FCCi21XwLRBR5QYz8Qdus1ia-Z6mtyP0n9cDYtpyXY" alt="Avatar filming delayed in New Zealand due to coronavirus | Metro News"/></figure>



<p><em>Avatar</em> follows the events that transpire for the Na’vi on the lush and vibrant alien moon of Pandora after humans work to colonise the land and mine the mineral unobtanium directly from the surface. The overuse of natural resources on Earth has forced humans to find supply of energy elsewhere. <em>Avatar</em> studies ecology, the environment and implications of personal choice when our protagonist Jake Sully [played by Sam Worthington], a former marine who joins the Avatar programme (which involves humans remotely operating genetically engineered Na&#8217;vi body to breathe and interact with true Na’vi on Pandora to support the humans’ mining efforts), becomes close to Neytiri [played by Zoe Saldana], daughter of the Omaticaya leader (the Na&#8217;vi clan central to this story). Cinematically, <em>Avatar</em>’s visual effects are incredible; and the film went to become the highest grossing of all-time at $2.79 billion globally, surpassing Cameron’s own record for <em>Titanic</em> (1997), which previously held this status, until <em>Avengers: Endgame</em> (2019) grossed $2.797 billion. James Cameron signed with 20th Century Fox to produce four sequels; with <em>Avatar 2</em> expected to be released on December 17<sup>th</sup>, 2021!&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Trashed</em> (2012)</strong> | Directed and Written by Candida Brady</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/H9kbUtOZe7_uSBzaYkxhHT8MwBqQH3RcPmQ2vdqxe-qhNFMlt6p0QT6RiHp0m63RJX5o4RGNYmNEeBOnZ2evcOKpOvtngDiInwbufEsP-bB0xeLZiBr8z_aLtUmjmeKfKDMQad0" alt="Jeremy Irons: Fighting Trash in Bali and Beyond • The Yak Online"/></figure>



<p><em>Trashed</em>, is an environmental documentary in which Jeremy Irons ‘discovers the extent and effects of the global waste problem, as he travels around the world to beautiful destinations tainted by pollution’. This film has been released in over 40 countries and has even had special showings at the Houses of Parliament and the European Parliament– and it’s a must-watch for film fans and climate activists alike. The goal of zero-waste is discussed alongside issues of rubbish build-up leading to groundwater, greenhouse gas and animal danger. The film premiered at Cannes Film Festival in 2012 and it was further nominated for Camera d&#8217;Or.</p>



<p><strong><em>Chasing Ice</em> (2012) </strong>| Directed by Jeff Orlowski &amp; Written by Mark Monroe</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/bJFETPyru0VK61_ADdlcpOrC3QdlY7lZm21dbVQgI9u8d81l2Y4F60zQDIJ1qNXeLVGZp-RWMBIoN6WGmJkLyDo1ssxCkRVWpQr7-3yLIuuy54_PYQaPqA4WLoY5o2AwXmRPDoo" alt="A snow covered mountain

Description automatically generated"/></figure>



<p><em>Chasing Ice</em> is a documentary that follows conservation photographer James Balog capturing the effects of global warming on glaciers in Greenland, Iceland and Alaska through the use of time-lapse cameras. Cinematically, this film is shot beautifully, which only heightens concerns against the earth’s atmospheric temperature gradually increasing over time. Balog states at its end that – “when my daughters look at me 25 to 30 years from now and say ‘what were you doing when global warming was happening and you guys knew what was coming down the road’, I want to be able to say I was doing everything I knew how to do”. This drive is evidenced throughout the movie by the filmmakers continuing to record despite technical difficulties, camera issues, team pressures and injuries. The documentary premiered at Sundance and won the Satellite Award for Best Documentary Film in 2012, a testament to its pioneering dedication to countering climate change.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Text by Nathaniel Nelson-Williams</strong><br><strong>Featured image via&nbsp;</strong><strong><em>https://newmediarockstars.com/</em></strong><strong>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/five-climate-conscious-flicks/">Five Climate Conscious Flicks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/five-climate-conscious-flicks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4198</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Bookseller’s Guide To A Pandemic: March Picks</title>
		<link>/a-booksellers-guide-to-a-pandemic-march-picks/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-booksellers-guide-to-a-pandemic-march-picks</link>
					<comments>/a-booksellers-guide-to-a-pandemic-march-picks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 18:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While everyone is retreating to their home or student accommodation or camping in an isolated area in the library, your brave booksellers are keeping the high street alive. I wholeheartedly advise against picking up the latest pandemic-related fiction or diving into Camus’ The Plague, but if you are willing to enter solitary confinement, the tagline [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-booksellers-guide-to-a-pandemic-march-picks/">A Bookseller’s Guide To A Pandemic: March Picks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>While everyone is retreating to their home or student accommodation or camping in an isolated area in the library, your brave booksellers are keeping the high street alive. I wholeheartedly advise against picking up the latest pandemic-related fiction or diving into Camus’ <em>The Plague</em>, but if you are willing to enter solitary confinement, the tagline should be something like ‘self-isolate with a good book.’ Preferably something that will take your mind off the widespread panic and will keep you and your lifelong supply of hand sanitisers good company. Here is a list, therefore, curated by me and featuring a selection of fiction and non-fiction books, which can function as panic-repellents but can also double as Mother’s day gifts. I’ve gone the extra mile and included uplifting titles for these difficult times.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Actress</em> by Anne Enright</strong></p>



<p>This novel is so skilfully written that I at times forgot it wasn’t an actual biography slash memoir and had to remind myself that Katherine O’Dell, the actress in the centre of the book, was not a real person. Written from her daughter’s perspective, the book traces the famous actress’s life from her humble beginnings in Ireland to her success in post-war America to the final days of her life. Norah spends a lot of this time in the wings and gives us details about her own life as well as what it was like to grow up with a mother that was adulated by so many people. With a strong mother-and-daughter relationship at its core, this addictive read offers fresh insights on fame, power, and trauma.</p>



<p><strong><em>Queenie</em> by Candice Carty-Williams</strong></p>



<p>If you are looking for something with the self-deprecating wit of Bridget Jones, <em>Queenie </em>is your fix for that and so much more. You didn’t know you needed to hear about Queenie Jenkins, a young journalist navigating being a woman, especially a black woman, and dealing with all the issues young adulthood throws her way, but now you do. Witty and honest, <em>Queenie </em>tackles every subject: from the pitfalls of dating white guys to bad Tinder dates to body image issues and mental health.&nbsp; The character of Queenie is the perfect vehicle for anxious young adults that love to self-analyse.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>I Feel Bad About My Neck</em> by Nora Ephron </strong></p>



<p>Non-fiction at its most entertaining, because Nora Ephron simply cannot do it any other way (if you are wondering who wrote <em>When Harry Met Sally</em> and revealed to everyone that it’s not that easy to tell when someone is faking an orgasm, that would be her). In this collection of essays, Ephron picks apart our conceptions of ‘womanhood’ by examining a range of topics. Whether she’s confessing her insecurities about aging or trying to understand the complicated relationship between women and bags or giving us a short and hilarious version of her life story, Ephron never fails to capture our attention.</p>



<p><strong><em>Sex and Lies</em> by Leila Slimani</strong> </p>



<p>I first encountered Leila Slimani when I read A<em>dèle, </em>the story of a woman who tries to live a normal life while battling her sex addiction. Why would Slimani be drawn to this subject? Precisely because she grew up in Morocco, where the constraint of sexual freedom makes sex a topic of obsession. In this book, she continues to explore the complicated nature of sexuality and takes aim at the systematic hypocrisy of a conservative, patriarchal society by sharing the stories of Moroccan women who have to live under its rules and suffer because of them.</p>



<p><strong><em>My Dark Vanessa</em> by Kate Elizabeth Russell</strong></p>



<p>Russell’s debut is coming out in the UK at the end of March and it’s a book worth keeping an eye out for. Vanessa is a student who embarks on a relationship with her boarding-school teacher when she is fifteen. The book travels back and forth, between her younger years and her current life, as Vanessa attempts to understand that very relationship. As a string of allegations against her teacher starts to surface, her conception of their story as a love story is threatened. Russell traps us in Vanessa’s mind, pulling us into her attempts to make sense of her own experiences: is Vanessa a victim of sexual abuse by an older man or is she the Lolita-like nymph her teacher paints her to be, because she wanted to be in a relationship with him? Were they in love? If she tells her story, will this Lolita receive sympathy?</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Alice Papadopoulou<br>Featured image from <em>unsplash.com</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-booksellers-guide-to-a-pandemic-march-picks/">A Bookseller’s Guide To A Pandemic: March Picks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/a-booksellers-guide-to-a-pandemic-march-picks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4163</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five Films You Haven’t Seen But Probably Should</title>
		<link>/five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should</link>
					<comments>/five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 21:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As part of SUBCULTURED’s International Women’s Day celebrations we’re showcasing our favourite, but sadly underrated, films directed by women. Women across the world are continuing to make vital and thought-provoking contributions to film &#8211; but from just watching award shows alone, it isn’t obvious. In comparison to their male counterparts, films directed by women are [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should/">Five Films You Haven’t Seen But Probably Should</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>As part of SUBCULTURED’s International Women’s Day celebrations
we’re showcasing our favourite, but sadly underrated, films directed by women.</p>



<p>Women across the world are continuing to make vital and thought-provoking contributions to film &#8211; but from just watching award shows alone, it isn’t obvious. In comparison to their male counterparts, films directed by women are systematically underrepresented during award seasons; in all its 92 years of existence, the Academy Award for Best Director has only been won once by a woman, Kathryn Bigelow, in 2009 for her film <em>The Hurt Locker</em>.</p>



<p><strong><em>Little Forest</em> (2018, Lim Soon-rye)</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4133" data-permalink="/five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should/1-27/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/1.png?fit=940%2C470&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="940,470" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/1.png?fit=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/1.png?fit=940%2C470&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="940" height="470" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/1.png?resize=940%2C470" alt="" class="wp-image-4133" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/1.png?w=940&amp;ssl=1 940w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/1.png?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>In <em>Little Forest</em>, Hae-won (played by Kim Tae-ri) leaves the stifling grind of city life in Seoul. After failing to qualify as a teacher, she returns to the rural village where she grew up. Food is a central part of the narrative &#8211; seasons are marked by the harvesting of crops, and Hae-won uses cooking to reconnect with her childhood friends and ultimately face her present: coming to terms with her feelings towards her estranged mother. Imbued with a sense of warmth, <em>Little Forest </em>is a comforting Korean film about what it means to choose your own path in life as an adult.</p>



<p><strong><em>Helter Skelter</em> (2018, Mika Ninagawa)</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4134" data-permalink="/five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should/2-22/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/2.png?fit=940%2C470&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="940,470" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/2.png?fit=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/2.png?fit=940%2C470&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="940" height="470" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/2.png?resize=940%2C470" alt="" class="wp-image-4134" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/2.png?w=940&amp;ssl=1 940w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/2.png?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p><em>Helter Skelter</em> is a psychological horror that examines the pervasive and destructive nature of the pursuit of the feminine ideal. Drawing from her background as a photographer, director Mika Ninagawa tells the story of Liliko (played by Erika Sawajiri) who, after undergoing countless full-body surgeries, transforms herself into a supermodel. However, beneath the rich colours, elaborate costuming and preternatural beauty, her career and and personal life begin to unravel as she desperately clings to her top spot in the industry.</p>



<p><strong><em>Novitiate</em> (2017, Maggie Betts)</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4135" data-permalink="/five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should/3-20/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/3.png?fit=940%2C470&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="940,470" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/3.png?fit=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/3.png?fit=940%2C470&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="940" height="470" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/3.png?resize=940%2C470" alt="" class="wp-image-4135" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/3.png?w=940&amp;ssl=1 940w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/3.png?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>Maggie Betts’ directorial debut grapples with questions of faith, identity, love and sacrifice. In <em>Novitiate</em>, Cathleen Harris, played by Margaret Qualley, joins a convent at the age of seventeen. Under the strict tutelage of her Mother Superior, Cathleen struggles to reconcile her religious beliefs in the Church with her own identity.</p>



<p><strong><em>Certain Women</em> (2016, Kelly Reichardt)</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4136" data-permalink="/five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should/4-14/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/4.png?fit=940%2C458&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="940,458" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="4" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/4.png?fit=300%2C146&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/4.png?fit=940%2C458&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="940" height="458" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/4.png?resize=940%2C458" alt="" class="wp-image-4136" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/4.png?w=940&amp;ssl=1 940w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/4.png?resize=300%2C146&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>The screen adaptation of <em>Certain Women</em> is based on three short stories written by Maile Meloy, composed of three vignettes. The star-studded female cast sees Laura Dern (as a troubled lawyer), Michelle Williams (as a wife and mother who feels increasingly alienated from her family), Kristen Stewart (as a young stripped-for-cash lawyer teaching night classes) and Lily Gladstone (as a lonely ranch hand) portray the lives of 4 ordinary women in a sleepy town in Montana. The film shows how their narratives are subtly threaded together by the overarching themes of loneliness and longing.</p>



<p><strong><em>Take Care of My Cat</em> (2001, Jeong Jae-eun)</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4137" data-permalink="/five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should/5-23/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/5.png?fit=940%2C470&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="940,470" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="5" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/5.png?fit=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/5.png?fit=940%2C470&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="940" height="470" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/5.png?resize=940%2C470" alt="" class="wp-image-4137" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/5.png?w=940&amp;ssl=1 940w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/5.png?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p><em>Take Care of My Cat</em> focuses on five high school friends from Incheon, Korea as they struggle to maintain their friendship while navigating their early twenties. While issues of status and wealth create tension in their relationships, it also unifies them – in particular, Tae-hee (played by Bae Doo-na), who feels increasingly listless and isolated from the expectations of her middle class family, Ji-young (Ok Ji-young), a textiles student, who grows increasingly frustrated with living in poverty, and Hae-joo (Lee Yo-won), who wants to move upwards in the corporate world, but is not taken seriously by her co-workers at a brokerage firm due to her lack of a formal college education. Set during the Asian financial crisis, <em>Take Care of My Cat</em> articulates timeless concerns about class, friendship and adulthood.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should/">Five Films You Haven’t Seen But Probably Should</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/five-films-you-havent-seen-but-probably-should/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4132</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Parasite [‘Gisaengchung’]: Film Review (Non-Spoiler)</title>
		<link>/parasite-gisaengchung-film-review-non-spoiler/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=parasite-gisaengchung-film-review-non-spoiler</link>
					<comments>/parasite-gisaengchung-film-review-non-spoiler/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4086</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This year’s Best Picture. Parasite made history at this year’s Academy Awards as the first Korean film to (1) secure an Oscar and (2) win Best Picture as a foreign-language film; as well as winning Oscars for Best Director, Best Screenplay and Best International Feature. This film was further nominated for Best Film Editing and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/parasite-gisaengchung-film-review-non-spoiler/">Parasite [‘Gisaengchung’]: Film Review (Non-Spoiler)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>This year’s Best
Picture.</strong></p>



<p><em>Parasite </em>made history at this year’s Academy
Awards as the first Korean film to (1) secure an Oscar and (2) win Best Picture
as a foreign-language film; as well as winning Oscars for Best Director, Best
Screenplay and Best International Feature. This film was further nominated for
Best Film Editing and Best Production Design; and since the Oscars, <em>Parasite</em>’s
had the biggest post-Oscar ticket sales boost in the past decade at 234% for
$205.3 million globally and rising.</p>



<p><em>Parasite</em> director and co-writer Bong Joon-ho describes his film as “a comedy without clowns, a tragedy without villains” and this view perfectly captures the tone of the film. In his previous works, such as <em>The Host</em> (2006), <em>Snowpiercer</em> (2013) and <em>Okja</em> (2017), Bong Joon-ho explores implications of class in contemporary society; and <em>Parasite</em> emphasises social realism to do so in thrilling dark comedy.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4088" data-permalink="/parasite-gisaengchung-film-review-non-spoiler/untitled-1-4/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Untitled-1.png?fit=944%2C396&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="944,396" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Untitled-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Untitled-1.png?fit=300%2C126&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Untitled-1.png?fit=944%2C396&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="944" height="396" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Untitled-1.png?resize=944%2C396" alt="Description: Image result for parasite" class="wp-image-4088" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Untitled-1.png?w=944&amp;ssl=1 944w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Untitled-1.png?resize=300%2C126&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 944px) 100vw, 944px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center has-small-font-size"><em>From left to right: Choi Woo-shik, Song Kang-ho, Chang Hyae-jin and Park So-dam in ‘Parasite’</em> <em>(via rogerebert.com)</em></p>



<p>The plot follows Ki-taek (Song
Kang-ho) and Chung-sook (Chang Hyae-jin), and their son Ki-woo (Choi Woo-shik)
and daughter Ki-jung (Park So-dam), who live in a squalid basement apartment.
When son Ki-woo secures a job as an English language tutor for the wealthy Park
family: he develops a plan to then find employment for his parents and sister
in the same household. They rehearse lines, invent aliases and work to replace
the current employees at the Park house and fully integrate. However, when the
Kim’s are ultimately threatened with exposure: our gripping story spirals out
of control.</p>



<p><em>Parasite</em> is masterfully acted, written and
filmed. Every scene flows to form the sequences that deliver an overarching
study of class against the extended metaphor of a ‘parasite’, which, like
Jordan Peele’s ‘Us’, is ambiguous. The film is unpredictable and engaging and
Bong perfectly captures the suspense of the story through sound and camera
movements. The evocative cinematography of Hong Kyung-pyo only adds to the
films’ impact. <em>Parasite</em> is without a doubt a must-watch.</p>



<p><em>Parasite’s</em> critical and box office performance
is exceptional; alongside a 92% audience score on Rotten Tomatoes. Many people,
including myself, were excited to watch following its win of Palme d’Or win at Cannes
Film Festival last year and the cast and crew have truly exceeded expectations.
As a non-western film, it’s a commercial breakthrough that reflects the growing
reach of South Korean cinema in the West. South Korea is the fifth largest film
market globally in terms of box office sales and the Korean Film Council has
allocated 100 billion won (£65m; $85m) for film development: a 32% increase
from last year. This film will also bring awareness to Neon as the independent
studio behind <em>Parasite</em> – they will likely experience growth in their awareness
and profile among filmmakers who are looking to launch their own creative
projects.</p>



<p>Overall: <em>Parasite</em> is an
incredible film that deserves all of its acclaim. I’d definitely recommend.</p>



<p>Rating [out of seven]: ★ ★ ★ ★ ★ ★ ★</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Nathaniel Nelson-Williams</strong><br><strong>Featured image via <em>news.sky.com/</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/parasite-gisaengchung-film-review-non-spoiler/">Parasite [‘Gisaengchung’]: Film Review (Non-Spoiler)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/parasite-gisaengchung-film-review-non-spoiler/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4086</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five Foreign Language Films You Need To Watch</title>
		<link>/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch</link>
					<comments>/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 19:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you can put up with the subtitles there is a world of cinematic wonder out there… Whether it be escapism, wanderlust inspiration, language practice or simply curiosity, here are five foreign language films you simply MUST see. The Intouchables (2011) &#8211; France The Intouchables is a brilliantly uplifting and thought-provoking French language film from [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch/">Five Foreign Language Films You Need To Watch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>If you can put up with the subtitles there is a world of cinematic wonder out there… Whether it be escapism, wanderlust inspiration, language practice or simply curiosity, here are five foreign language films you simply MUST see.</p>



<p><em><strong>The Intouchables</strong></em><strong> (2011)</strong> &#8211; France</p>



<p><em>The Intouchables</em> is a brilliantly uplifting and thought-provoking French language film from 2011. Directed by Olivier Nakache and Éric Toledano, frequent collaborators, <em>The Intouchables</em> shot main actor, Omar Sy into superstardom and redefined his entire career. The film centres on a quadriplegic aristocrat (François Cluzet) who hires a young man (Sy) to be his caregiver. Despite the characters’ disparate social backgrounds and contrasting personal histories, the two men overcome their own issues and their companionship blossoms into a meaningful friendship. A fun watch with a compassionate relationship at its core, <em>The Intouchables</em> is a must-watch film with something for everyone. How can you not feel good when the credits role?<br>Available on: Amazon Video to rent for £2.49</p>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery aligncenter columns-0"></ul>



<div data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch\/"}' class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="3823" data-permalink="/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch/img_7839/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7839.jpg?fit=486%2C274&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="486,274" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_7839" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7839.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7839.jpg?fit=486%2C274&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="486" height="274" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7839.jpg?resize=486%2C274" alt="" class="wp-image-3823" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7839.jpg?w=486&amp;ssl=1 486w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7839.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 486px) 100vw, 486px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p><em><strong>Train to Busan</strong></em><strong> (2016)</strong> &#8211; Korea</p>



<div data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch\/"}' class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="3824" data-permalink="/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch/img_7840/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7840.jpg?fit=562%2C316&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="562,316" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_7840" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7840.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7840.jpg?fit=562%2C316&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="562" height="316" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7840.jpg?resize=562%2C316" alt="" class="wp-image-3824" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7840.jpg?w=562&amp;ssl=1 562w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7840.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 562px) 100vw, 562px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>Arguably, Korean masterpiece, <em>Train to Busan,</em> has plenty for zombie enthusiast and zombie sceptics alike. <em>Train to Busan</em> is a film about a father’s quest to deliver his daughter to his estranged wife and themes of love, determination and sacrifice are prevalent throughout. There are plenty of emotionally dramatic scenes to entice fans of all films, whilst the contorted way that the people become zombies will intrigue and fascinate those who have seen all types of zombie films. The train as a set piece works phenomenally and I can guarantee that you will be on edge throughout, a testament to Yeon Sang-ho’s brilliant direction.<br>Available on: YouTube and Amazon Video to rent for £2.49</p>



<p><em><strong>Who Would You Take to a Deserted Island?</strong></em><strong> (2019)</strong> &#8211; Spain</p>



<div data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch\/"}' class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="3828" data-permalink="/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch/img_7847/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7847.jpg?fit=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1536,1024" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_7847" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7847.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7847.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="683" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7847-1024x683.jpg?resize=1024%2C683" alt="" class="wp-image-3828" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7847.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7847.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7847.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7847.jpg?w=1536&amp;ssl=1 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>Brand new Spanish-language film, streaming <em>right now </em>on Netflix, immediately transports you to a sweltering summer in Madrid. It follows four youths as they take the next step forward in their lives and an interesting secret which threatens this progression. <em>Who Would You Take to a Deserted Island?</em> combines relationship drama and emotional tension in the best possible way. Actors, Jaime Lorente and María Pedraza, have brilliant chemistry, which is probably due to their real life relationship and their past work together in <em>La Casa de Papel</em> and<em> Élite</em>. Their opening bedroom scene will have you laughing along with them and will endear you to their respective characters; Pedraza’s understated performance steals the show.<br>Available on: Netflix</p>



<p><em><strong>Vampyr</strong></em><strong> (1932)</strong> &#8211; Germany</p>



<div data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch\/"}' class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="3827" data-permalink="/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch/img_7845/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7845.jpg?fit=540%2C302&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="540,302" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_7845" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7845.jpg?fit=300%2C168&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7845.jpg?fit=540%2C302&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="540" height="302" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7845.jpg?resize=540%2C302" alt="" class="wp-image-3827" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7845.jpg?w=540&amp;ssl=1 540w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7845.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>Yes, the “1932” may make you want to scroll past immediately, but please don’t! <em>Vampyr</em> is a precursor to every good horror film we respect and enjoy today. A German language passion project led by Nicholas de Gunzburg, who starred in the film under the pseudonym Julian West, and directed by celebrated Danish director, Carl Theodor Dreyer. <em>Vampyr </em>uses some brilliant practical effects, including placing gauze over the camera to create a hazy illusion, to create a true atmosphere of unease. Despite its age, this film will unnerve you in the most human ways by subverting many scientific and emotional expectations to turn the world as you understand it on its head. Oh and it’s available on YouTube to watch for FREE!<br>Available on: YouTube</p>



<p><em><strong>Spirited Away</strong></em><strong> (2001)</strong> &#8211; Japan</p>



<div data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch\/"}' class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img data-attachment-id="3825" data-permalink="/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch/img_7842/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7842.jpg?fit=466%2C252&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="466,252" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_7842" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7842.jpg?fit=300%2C162&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7842.jpg?fit=466%2C252&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="466" height="252" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7842.jpg?resize=466%2C252" alt="" class="wp-image-3825" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7842.jpg?w=466&amp;ssl=1 466w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_7842.jpg?resize=300%2C162&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 466px) 100vw, 466px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>Although <em>Ringu</em> (1998) or <em>Ju-On: The Grudge</em>, (2002) are Japanese classics, anime can’t be forgotten. A favourite of anime newbies and old fans alike, <em>Spirited Away</em> is widely known as Studio Ghibli’s <em>pièce de résistance</em>. A story about a 10 year old girl exploring a magical world after she and her parents move to a new home and visit an abandoned amusement park with an interesting secret. <em>Spirited Away</em> is heartfelt, bizarre and brilliant in all the best ways. If you’ve never watched an anime before, this is a brilliant place to start.<br>Available on: Amazon Prime</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Beth Roberts</strong><br><strong>Picture research by Anna Irina.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch/">Five Foreign Language Films You Need To Watch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/five-foreign-language-films-you-need-to-watch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3821</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mason: The Lost Tapes</title>
		<link>/mason-the-lost-tapes/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=mason-the-lost-tapes</link>
					<comments>/mason-the-lost-tapes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 20:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At the end of the documentary Manson: The Lost Tapes, Bobby BeauSoleil, a former member of theManson family, attempts to pierce the illusion of Charles Manson as a messianic figure, suggesting that Manson was not “a master” and had no plan, and rather that the murders were beyond his control. As ultimately pathetic as Manson [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/mason-the-lost-tapes/">Mason: The Lost Tapes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>At the end of the documentary <em>Manson: The Lost Tapes</em>, Bobby BeauSoleil, a former member of theManson family, attempts to pierce the illusion of Charles Manson as a messianic figure, suggesting that Manson was not “a master” and had no plan, and rather that the murders were beyond his control. As ultimately pathetic as Manson is generally understood to be, with a former cellmate describing him as a “guy to make fun of” in the documentary, he was able to form and hold power over his cult thanks to the virulent misogyny of the counterculture movement of the 1960s.Manson, who was described as someone that would “do anything to survive,”gained a following through preying on young and vulnerable girls, who he manipulated through sexual abuse and rampant drug usage. </p>



<p><em>Manson:The Lost Tapes</em> illustrates this through unused footage from Robert Hendrickson’s 1973 Oscar nominated documentary <em>Manson</em>, as well as present day interviews held with two former members of the cult, Catherine Share and Diane Lake. Both women had in common with each other a troubled home life, with Share being a Holocaust survivor whose adopted mother committed suicide, while Lake, who joined the cult when she was only 14 years old, admits to having parents that were not the “warm, fuzzy, hugging variety.” They describe having found an approximation of the affection that they craved on Spahn Ranch, the abandoned movie set turned horse rental business that the Manson family made their base. While the public’s sympathy for the so-called “Manson girls” has understandably been limited, the documentary draws attention to the plight of teenage girls by contextualising the actions of the women who joined Manson’s cult within a culture that had alienated them.</p>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/mason-the-lost-tapes\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-1 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3410" data-permalink="/mason-the-lost-tapes/img_4490/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/IMG_4490.jpg?fit=660%2C371&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="660,371" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_4490" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/IMG_4490.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/IMG_4490.jpg?fit=660%2C371&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="660" height="371" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/IMG_4490.jpg?resize=660%2C371" alt="" data-id="3410" data-link="/?attachment_id=3410" class="wp-image-3410" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/IMG_4490.jpg?w=660&amp;ssl=1 660w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/IMG_4490.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>via bbc.com</figcaption></figure></li></ul>



<p>The documentary shows how intimacy was mimicked by Manson through his liberal approach to sexuality, which, far from challenging patriarchy, actually created a culture of male entitlement to women’s bodies. Members of the cult were encouraged by Manson to frequently engage in sexual activities, supposedly in order to lose their inhibitions.However, Share’s description of the sexual abuse committed by Manson suggests that his attitude towards sex was born less out of an inclination to free the girls from their own societal norms but rather to maintain control over them and gain a sense of power. While the free love movement did rightfully encourage women to embrace their sexuality, and is often remembered for doing so, this was often without a critical consideration about why or why not they might make the choices they do, leaving them vulnerable to predation.</p>



<p>Archival footage gives us a sense of what life on Spahn Ranch was like, emblematic of the counter culture movement in the frequent experimentation with drugs, the rejection of authority and prevailing social norms and the uninhibited approach to sexuality. Share reminisced on her fonder memories of her time within the family, stating that she did not “see the dust,” only the quaintness, while Lake observed that the“total reliance on each other” and the “idea of family” present within the cult created the perfect grounds to spread Manson’s philosophy. This idyllic view may be shared by modern viewers, as the 60s have become immortalised within pop culture as a time of hippies, bell bottoms and weed. </p>



<p>However, it is undercut by the interwoven recounting of Windy Bucklee, a worker at Spahn Ranch while Manson’s cult was present, who only ever saw the family as “trashy people,” describingManson as a “predator.” Indeed, both Lake and Share describe how it felt to come to this realisation themselves as the effect of Manson’s spell eventually wore off, which they both refer to as a feeling of being conned. Perhaps they, and countless other women, had not only been conned by Manson, but also by a movement that promised them freedom, but gave them the opposite. <em>Manson: The Lost Tapes</em> serves not to exonerate the members of the Manson family from the horrific crimes they committed, but to explain how they came to exist in their own words, and in doing so, sheds a light on the darker, often forgotten side of the counterculture movement.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Madhu Manivannan</strong></p>



<p><strong>Picture research by Anna Irina; featured image from </strong><em><strong>people.howstuffworks.com</strong></em><strong>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/mason-the-lost-tapes/">Mason: The Lost Tapes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/mason-the-lost-tapes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3390</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sense8, Netflix, and Pride Month</title>
		<link>/sense8-netflix-pride-month/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=sense8-netflix-pride-month</link>
					<comments>/sense8-netflix-pride-month/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 07:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pride month started with a blow to the LGBT+ community with the cancellation of one of the most pro-LGBT+ shows around—Netflix’s ‘Sense8’. However, by the end of pride month, fans of the show had successfully won a 2-hour finale, now planned for release in 2018, through twitter campaigning and online petitions. &#160; The show follows [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/sense8-netflix-pride-month/">Sense8, Netflix, and Pride Month</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">Pride month started with a blow to the LGBT+ community with the cancellation of one of the most pro-LGBT+ shows around—Netflix’s <strong>‘Sense8’</strong>. However, by the end of pride month, fans of the show had successfully won a 2-hour finale, now planned for release in 2018, through twitter campaigning and online petitions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The show follows the lives of eight people who had never met each other. By living in various parts of the world and leading different lives, they were never have meant to have met. However, after being “birthed” by a woman called Angelica, these eight people learn that they are part of a different species of human beings, <em>sensates</em>, who share a telepathic connection with each other. They share emotions, skills, language and knowledge enabling them to work together to deal with individual problems and to fight a common enemy, the Biological Preservation Organisation (BPO) who are trying to hunt them down. Together, they become a ‘cluster’ and form a family-like bond.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The 8 main characters are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Will (a cop from Chicago, USA)</li>
<li>Nomi (a trans-woman and hacker from San Francisco, USA)</li>
<li>Sun (a businesswoman and skilled kickboxer from Seoul, Korea)</li>
<li>Wolfgang (a locksmith and safe-cracker from Berlin, Germany)</li>
<li>Riley (an Icelandic-born DJ living in London, England)</li>
<li>Kala (a pharmacist from Mumbai, India)</li>
<li>Capheus (a matatu driver from Nairobi, Kenya)</li>
<li>Lito (a closeted actor from Mexico City, Mexico)</li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2239" style="width: 863px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2239" data-attachment-id="2239" data-permalink="/?attachment_id=2239" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Untitled1.png?fit=853%2C505&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="853,505" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Untitled1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Untitled1.png?fit=300%2C178&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Untitled1.png?fit=853%2C505&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2239" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Untitled1.png?resize=853%2C505" alt="@ Yahoo! France" width="853" height="505" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Untitled1.png?w=853&amp;ssl=1 853w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Untitled1.png?resize=300%2C178&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 853px) 100vw, 853px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2239" class="wp-caption-text">@ Yahoo! France</p></div></p>
<p>While sci-fi shows are increasingly popular, Sense8 is atypical of its genre and reaches new heights and crosses all boundaries. It explores many topics, like sexuality, politics, religion, family, love, identity, drug and gang culture. It has, in particular, been praised for its diverse representation of different races, cultures, sexualities and gender identities. Many upcoming shows have also actively tried to portray more representation. However, with Sense8, it is not something that is just vacantly present, but also a core component of the story. This inclusion is also active behind the screens as the Wachowski sisters, creators of the show, are both transwomen themselves. Meanwhile, Nomi, is played by transgender actress, Jamie Crayton, rather than a cis actress; as is the case in other shows. So when Crayton’s character, Nomi, says “For a long time, I was afraid to be who I am”, you can feel the sincerity of those words and the connection Crayton must feel with her character.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The range of diversity is key in the show’s overall message that despite all the differences between the sensates, friendship and love transcends all. The sensates are able to ‘visit’ each other telepathically in their respective countries and cities despite being thousands of miles away. They often find themselves ‘visiting’ each other during emotionally poignant moments in their lives, and it is through the mental sharing of these emotions that their differences turn into empathy and understanding. It is these emotions and their connections that are the driving forces of the story of Sense8.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The show also deals with sex in a mature manner. It does not shy away from showing it explicitly or artistically, nor does it shy away from showing intimate homosexual scenes. This does represent a cultural shift in western media to be increasingly acceptable of homosexual relationships; a reflection of western society itself. At the same time, it continues to be more progressive than most TV shows we watch. But of course, the sensates are from different countries and cultures and thus Sense8 also represents different attitudes towards sex. While Wolfgang is seen having casual sex, having proclaimed himself that “Germans aren’t so uptight about nudity”, Kala is, in contrast, a virgin and nervous about sex. It is portrayed as more than just a physical act as the sensates are able to experience each other’s emotions during sex through their emotional and mental link, resulting in two orgy scenes in the series.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Admittedly the first 2-3 episodes are harder to process and get through. But having been shot in 17 different cities and accompanied with a stunning soundtrack and breath-taking cinematography, the series contains some of the most beautiful scenes I have witnessed in TV show history. The editing is slick and clever, with many of the scenes being two interconnected to one, and the (numerous) action scenes are truly thrilling and entertaining to watch.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I, like many of the show’s fans, was very disappointed at the show’s cancellation. It is highly unlikely that anything more than the promised 2-hour finale will progress, but help keep the show alive by watching it and tweeting to Netflix about it!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I highly recommend this show!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><strong>SUBCULTURED Score: 10/10</strong></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>All Sense8 episodes are available to watch on Netflix.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text and picture research by AK Gurung; featured image from<em> spoilertv.com</em>.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/sense8-netflix-pride-month/">Sense8, Netflix, and Pride Month</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/sense8-netflix-pride-month/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2241</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
