<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Culture &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/culture/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A fashion, culture, art and music publication, written by students about students.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 18:43:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/cropped-12773305_10206631248554054_481252708_o.jpg?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Culture &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107671177</site>	<item>
		<title>The Social Dilemma Review &#8211; “The Greatest Existential Threat Of Our Time?”</title>
		<link>/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time</link>
					<comments>/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 17:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Social media &#8211; the biggest existential threat that we&#8217;ve ever faced? SUBCULTURED takes a look at the latest Netflix film kicking up some dirt on Silicon Valley&#8217;s biggest tech companies. The Social Dilemma, which arrived on Netflix earlier this month, is an exposing docu-drama from Jeff Orlowski, with help from a vast club of co-founders [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/">The Social Dilemma Review &#8211; “The Greatest Existential Threat Of Our Time?”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Social media &#8211; the biggest existential threat that we&#8217;ve ever faced? SUBCULTURED takes a look at the latest Netflix film kicking up some dirt on Silicon Valley&#8217;s biggest tech companies.</strong></p>



<p><em>The Social Dilemma</em>, which arrived on Netflix earlier this month, is an exposing docu-drama from Jeff Orlowski, with help from a vast club of co-founders and designers who have now left some of the most influential social media companies in the world. The title nods to the popular 2010 film &#8216;<em>The Social Network</em>&#8216;, attempting to unpick the platform and other social media sites, while unearthing the dark truths behind these companies.</p>



<p>The film opens with slick camera shots against modernistic backgrounds, as various tech experts disclose their ex-Silicon Valley employers before their interviews begin. It is apparent that they are about to expose some of what goes on behind our screens; they seem nervous, as if unsure how their revelations will be received. One former Google employee awkwardly reveals that he &#8220;spent eight months talking back and forth with lawyers&#8221; about this interview, before others express their concern for the ethics of the companies they worked for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the next scene, we are presented with a dystopian-style barrage of social media-related American news reports on teenagers’ mental health, extremist groups, mass violence and Coronavirus misinformation. The essence of the problem, as explained by main contributor Tristan Harris and his industry friends, is this: the biggest tech companies are no longer the ones who simply create a product and sell it to their users. Instead, they are the ones whose customers are advertisers who pay to show their ads; and the product is you.</p>



<p>Their goal, then, becomes &#8220;how can we capture as much of their attention as possible?”, to hook us on the app, resulting in more ad exposure. These apps are therefore designed to be as addictive as possible, exploiting psychological vulnerabilities; meanwhile, the algorithms determine what to show us that will best engage us based on the data they have. These algorithms, however, are blind to false information and tend to bias extreme content and ideas, polarising nations and encouraging conspiracy theories and extremist groups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Not only does social media create its own problems of addiction, depression and anxiety; it also divides and misinforms, preventing people from focusing on solutions to the bigger issues at hand. Combined, these implications mean social media is fast being considered an existential threat to our humanity.</p>



<p>The film is interlaced with emotive dramatizations portraying the extreme capabilities of the technology we interact with on a level nothing short of a typical Black Mirror episode &#8211; also equipped with all of the eerie nostalgia and unsettling intensity courtesy of the background music.</p>



<p>However, the enactments create the challenge of distinguishing frenzied exaggeration from true portrayal; it&#8217;s hard to tell what data your devices are collecting from you, or to what extent different apps can use this data; do they really wait for gaps in your calendar app to ping an enticing notification your way? Do they really queue posts in your news feed from a person who is near to your location, and if so, is it really as stark as its Hollywood portrayal? It’s unclear which of the capabilities of these apps is the hard, cold truth, and how much is pure hyperbole designed &#8211; quite ironically &#8211; to get our attention?</p>



<p>Confusingly, the film seems to peddle the idea that social media companies are using manipulative, persuasive features to addict their users to the apps, while the co-founder and ex-designer interviewees seem reluctant to admit that there was anything inherently misguided about the way that they designed these apps. “nobody, I believe, ever intended any of these consequences”, reports former Twitter Executive Jeff Seibert. Some level of unfiltered honesty is displayed, but not a full admission of guilt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sure, the kind of gratification you get from receiving an email or notification is fairly unavoidable, but the hijacking of these addictive pathways is clearly deliberate. but there are blatant and intentional ways that the addictive pathways are being designed, too. Sean Parker, former president of Facebook, says of this manipulation, &#8220;[We all] understood this. But we did it anyway.&#8221; Surely, they couldn’t pretend to be ‘victims of a dangerous business model’. Perhaps this reveals the dark side of what went on &#8211; and is still going on &#8211; within these companies.</p>



<p>Ultimately, the “attention extraction” model that these companies have adopted, which views human beings as a resource to profit from, isn’t much less of a definition of exploitation than slavery or human trafficking. It&#8217;s just that this new kind of abuse and manipulation is far subtler, embedded in hidden webs of human psychology and algorithmic complexity; and therefore, all the more dangerous.</p>



<p>After taking on a rather solemn tone towards the end, with talk of the inevitable entrapment that the advertising business model and shareholder pressure bring, the film ends with a more optimistic, spirited call to remember what technology was created to be — something that helped us and connected us. This kind of technology can be designed humanely by returning to our original goal: “How do we make the world a better place, for everyone?” It’s what we all want, and it’s what social media companies promised; but it&#8217;s not delivering.</p>



<p>At least these ex-employees of the big tech companies have moved on, and begun to expose and discuss the secrets from within the industry. Have they helped to create these problems? Yes. Should you trust them? Probably. Having left the companies, contributed to this film, and some even helped to found an institute pursuing a humane technology agenda, you&#8217;d better believe them. In fact, our future may depend on it.</p>



<p><em>The Social Dilemma is available now on Netflix. To find out more about the project behind the film and continue the conversation, go to <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.thesocialdilemma.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">www.thesocialdilemma.com</a></span>.</em></p>



<p><strong>Text by Barney Venable<br>Featured image via <em>Forbes</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/">The Social Dilemma Review &#8211; “The Greatest Existential Threat Of Our Time?”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-social-dilemma-review-the-greatest-existential-threat-of-our-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4343</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Room Of One’s Own: Some Thoughts On Isolation</title>
		<link>/a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation</link>
					<comments>/a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 17:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is certainly not what Virginia Woolf had in mind. For the majority of us, who live our lives by making plans, laying down brick by brick the path to our best future, this lockdown was not what we had in mind either. The rug was pulled out from under our feet. We tripped and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation/">A Room Of One’s Own: Some Thoughts On Isolation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>This is certainly not what Virginia Woolf had in mind.</p>



<p>For the majority of us, who live our lives by making plans, laying down brick by brick the path to our best future, this lockdown was not what we had in mind either. The rug was pulled out from under our feet. We tripped and when we came back up, the world had turned upside down. With the restrictions lifting, most of us still are encouraged to stay indoors, which means we are still contemplating how we can exist in a universe where time is standing still.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It feels like we (let me indulge and speak for those in early adulthood) are sidestepping minefields constantly. From Brexit to the constant threat of climate change to Trump to a pandemic, our futures never look that certain and taking those first steps into adulthood is becoming harder and harder when the world around us seems to be fighting for breath day after day. I suppose one of the side-effects of the world stopping on its axis is anxiety about the future and a certain hopelessness. I actively try to fight against the idea that our future is bleak. Because that’s all I am getting at the moment; be it through anxious conversations with my parents, or Doomsday reports about a global recession, or because I am unable to offer some true comfort to friends who are losing jobs, money, or their sanity.</p>



<p>I am thankfully safe and happy in my own home, but this forced moving-back-in certainly makes me feel unfree. It’s a particular feeling that only comes when you realise that you can’t live your life on your own terms; there is no concrete end date to how long you are meant to stand there and watch life pass you by. Even in the happiest of families, the home is no longer just a place that can bring people who love each other together; it is somewhere you must stay. I feel powerless, like a child, but I can’t expect the adults to figure this one out. And neither can I fully step in, be the adult, tell my parents: don’t worry, we’ll figure it all out.&nbsp; Because I don’t really believe that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Things would be easier if we could pick up where we left off, but the endless sea of uncertainty that is the future – emerging from lockdown, recovering from the financial dip, eventually dealing with Brexit – takes away that comfort. So it’s not so much that we are enjoying quality time with our loved ones, as that we are rooted to the spot, looking at things unfurling with terror. I feel ill-equipped to face the difficulties of the future. How am I going to face the ‘new normal’? For how long will we live our lives tiptoeing around, fearing infection? What jobs will be there for us to hustle for? As a generation already prone to anxiety and other mental health issues, can we even deal with more anxiety and uncertainty? Can we rebuild? Only to have things knocked down again when Brexit is added to the mix and whatever else comes next?</p>



<p>These are the depressing thoughts that pass through my mind. Spiralling has probably become a trend for anyone just starting out in their adult life, past the green grass (hm, actually, it wasn’t that green) of the early university years. I don’t really know what dreams to hold on to, because dreaming right now feels pointless.&nbsp; I have this constant urge to get out there and make things happen, but then I remember.</p>



<p>I am rooted to the spot.</p>



<p>But I am safe. I am healthy. As an international community, we are committed to preserving health for as many people as possible. We are staying in, we are wearing masks, we are doing all these things to save lives, to build a safer future if not the best future imaginable. Seldom have personal liberties been sacrificed for a better cause. Even through our screens, we have come together in great solidarity, fighting united against this pandemic, and I have hope that this solidarity will continue as we attempt to rebuild. These past few months have been a turning point: we learnt to act to protect others, we had a moment to reflect on our impact on the environment, we had a reckoning on racial injustice, and we gained clarity on the failures and successes of politicians around the world. We now clearly know what we are asking for: we are asking governments to protect us and support public health, we are asking for a society that truly cares about diversity and equality, we are asking for a greener future. No, we are not asking, we are demanding, because we can’t turn a blind eye anymore. Within ourselves, we have also redefined what success means to us, what we are hustling for and what we want in life. We have come to appreciate our health and be more grateful about the things we have and are truly worth fighting for: our loved ones, our community, the world’s future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Things will not be the same for a long time, but we have to hold on tight to the fact that we <em>can</em> make them better. If we can’t get back to normal, we might as well start thinking about what we want to replace that normal with.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Text by Alice Papadopoulou</strong><br><strong>Featured image via Tumblr.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation/">A Room Of One’s Own: Some Thoughts On Isolation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/a-room-of-ones-own-some-thoughts-on-isolation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4286</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Netflix’s Indian Matchmaking: A Step Forwards Or Backwards For South Asian Culture?</title>
		<link>/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture</link>
					<comments>/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 18:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While mainstream TV shows and films helmed by South Asians were once few and far between, the increasing diversification of media indicates that one-note depictions of South Asians might soon become a thing of the past. But, at present, with so few cultural touchpoints when it comes to representations of South Asians, the stakes are [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/">Netflix’s Indian Matchmaking: A Step Forwards Or Backwards For South Asian Culture?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>While mainstream TV shows and films helmed by South Asians were once few and far between, the increasing diversification of media indicates that one-note depictions of South Asians might soon become a thing of the past. But, at present, with so few cultural touchpoints when it comes to representations of South Asians, the stakes are higher. In this light, it’s easy to understand why South Asians are divided over Netflix’s latest runaway hit <em>Indian Matchmaking</em>, which explores the contentious practice of arranged marriage. Some have argued that the show is a step backwards, <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/scaachikoul/indian-matchmaking-criticism-family-karma" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">presenting “South Asian identity” as “uniquely fraught,”</span></a> while others argue the show is just <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/07/indian-matchmaking-dating-reality-tv-colorism.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“telling it like it is.”</a>&nbsp;</span></p>



<p>Showrunner Smriti Mundhra was as frustrated as some of her critics with shows that were only <a href="https://medium.com/the-international-wave/interview-with-smriti-mundhra-storytelling-without-a-script-9edb2b7848ae" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">“about the trauma and the stereotypes that our communities are known for,”</span></a> seeking to present a fluffier alternative. <a href="https://medium.com/the-international-wave/interview-with-smriti-mundhra-storytelling-without-a-script-9edb2b7848ae" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">In an interview preceding its release on Netflix</span></a>, she stated that she “packaged” <em>Indian Matchmaking, </em>which<em> </em>documents matchmaker Sima Taparia as she journeys between India and America to find her clients a suitable spouse, as “a fun dating show” in the hopes that it would “be more accessible to a wider range of people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Inevitably, the South Asian community formed the show’s largest and most vocal viewership. The show is wryly funny, lightly ribbing some of the ridiculous views that are often espoused by South Asians, its editing poking fun at the absurd criteria that Taparia’s clients insist on and interspersing her meme-able observations in between scenes depicting her clients on their quest for love. Multiple episodes of the show open with <em>When Harry Met Sally</em>-esque interviews featuring bickering couples who had an arranged marriage, adding to its sentimental feel. At first glance, its cast seems to be formed of caricatures of South Asians we know and may or may not love – the highly-strung overachiever, the regressive aunty, the overbearing mother and the coddled mummy’s boy. However, the show does not solely relegate its cast to sources of comedy. In part, it endeavours to demonstrate a fuller picture of who Taparia’s clients are and why they ended up in front of her, such as fan favourite Nadia, who seeks to find a partner who is accepting of both her Indian and Guyanese heritage and Ankita, a self-assured businesswoman who is ready to move onto the next stage of her life, but only on her own terms.</p>



<p>As much as the <em>Indian Matchmaking</em> audience’s familiarity with the communities and cultures heightens its relatability and humour, it also renders its lurid veneer transparent. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2020/08/netflix-indian-matchmaking-and-the-shadow-of-caste/614863/?utm_source=feed" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">As Yashica Dutt writes</a></span>, the show’s “coding” of caste through seemingly benign phrases like “shared communities” or “respectable families” serves to disfigure the reality of the caste system and the discrimination and violence it creates. Many have criticised the show for being uncritical of the misogyny upheld by matchmakers and clients alike, who idealise fair skin and prize compliance to men, insisting that potential brides be “flexible,” while women who are unwavering in their standards are labelled “not stable.” It has not gone unnoticed that the burdens of belonging to such a family-orientated and image-based culture and the resulting pressure to conform, as well as the consequences of not conforming,&nbsp; are a frequent theme in the storylines of nearly all of Taparia’s clients.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mundhra is well aware of the arguments surrounding her subject, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.thecut.com/2020/07/indian-matchmaking-review.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">having faced pressure to have an arranged marriage herself</a></span>, as well as having directed the slightly more critical documentary<em> A Suitable Girl </em>in 2017. <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.glamour.com/story/netflix-indian-matchmaking" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Her own view of arranged marriage</a></span> is that “it was designed to preserve caste and class and to subjugate women,” but that it has since “evolved from that.” She appears to argue that arranged marriage is a choice, that, as <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-53499195" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Anna MM Vetticad states</span></a>, it is merely “a practical Indian version of the dating game in the West,” whereby the only difference is that your potential matches are presented to you by your parents and matchmaker rather than Tinder. It’s an argument that may ring familiar to many South Asians for whom this half-truth is a balm to their affection for their culture against Western paternalism and condescension. Yet, in spite of the optimistic perspective that informs it, <em>Indian Matchmaking’s</em> light-hearted approach jars with the tensions implicit in the situations we witness, almost satirical in its absurdity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In&nbsp; acknowledgement of the criticism of<em> Indian Matchmaking</em>,&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.glamour.com/story/netflix-indian-matchmaking" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mundhra has stated that</a></span> “It’s not possible to show the entire perspective, of course, and the show leaves a lot on the table,” inviting others to hold her “accountable.” By relying on its audience to complete the unfinished picture that <em>Indian Matchmaking</em> presents of arranged marriage, particularly those most negatively affected by the prejudicial practices it upholds, the show admits its failure to prove its thesis. As it turns out, <a href="https://www.womenshealthmag.com/relationships/a33368001/indian-matchmaking-netflix-couples-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">none of Taparia’s clients that featured on the show found a match through her</span></a>. Sometimes, reality cannot be easily repackaged as a romcom. Nor should the unique struggles faced by South Asians living in the West, often tied to their cultures and traditions, be obscured, to prevent others viewing South Asian identity as “uniquely fraught.” As much as South Asians are tired of being represented as repressed objects of ridicule, it’s apparent that the solution is to treat these issues with nuance, not to sandpaper over the breadth of our experiences with generalised positivity.</p>



<p><strong>Text by Madhu Manivannan<br>Featured image via Vanity Fair.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/">Netflix’s Indian Matchmaking: A Step Forwards Or Backwards For South Asian Culture?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/netflixs-indian-matchmaking-a-step-forwards-or-backwards-for-south-asian-culture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4282</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Film Fanatic&#8217;s Guide To Staycation</title>
		<link>/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation</link>
					<comments>/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 11:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown American chef Anthony Bourdain cited his experience filming an episode of his show Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations in Lebanon in the midst of the 2006 Israel-Lebanon War as having significantly reshaped his attitude towards his work. He remarked that “I just saw that there were realities beyond what was on my [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/">A Film Fanatic&#8217;s Guide To Staycation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong><em>Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown</em></strong></p>



<p>American chef Anthony Bourdain cited his experience filming an episode of his show <em>Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations</em> in Lebanon in the midst of the 2006 Israel-Lebanon War as having significantly reshaped his attitude towards his work. <a href="https://explorepartsunknown.com/beirut/field-notes-from-beirut/">He remarked that</a> “I just saw that there were realities beyond what was on my plate, and those realities almost inevitably informed what was—or was not—for dinner. To ignore them had come to seem monstrous.” <em>Anthony Bourdain:</em> <em>Parts Unknown</em> is a reflection of these realities, following Bourdain as he journeys around the world, sampling native delicacies from the Chickenjoy bucket at Jollibee to fish and chips in a greasy spoon. <em>Parts Unknown </em>is a celebration of food and its multifaceted significance, whether it serves a communal purpose or constitutes an expression of love, or it is rooted in historical significance and acts as an expression of identity and culture.</p>



<p><em>Seasons 1 to 12 available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>The Imagineering Story</em></strong></p>



<p>Over the past few months, many of us have realised that the American Dream is just that, a dream. One of the most tangible manifestations of this dream is Main Street, U.S.A., a themed area of Disneyland parks across the world, the first of which was inspired by Walt Disney’s childhood memories of growing up in Missouri. In many ways, the story told in <em>The Imagineering Story</em>, the story of the original Disneyland and its expansion across the world, is a story about America, as well as a tribute to the creative endeavors of the “Imagineers” who made the ornate attractions of Disneyland possible, albeit a whitewashed one. Among the companies admitting their past wrongdoings and vowing to do better in the wake of the Black Lives Matter protests was Disney, who finally decided to overhaul the last conspicuous acknowledgement of their racist 1946 film, <em>Song of the South</em>. The ride Splash Mountain will now be <a href="https://twitter.com/DisneyParks/status/1276187686672437249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1276187686672437249%7Ctwgr%5E&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.smithsonianmag.com%2Fsmart-news%2Fdisney-will-completely-reimagine-controversial-splash-mountain-ride-180975198%2F" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“<em>reimagined with a new story</em>”</a> inspired by <em>The Princess and the Frog</em>, the 2009 film that introduced Disney’s first Black princess, Tiana. As illustrated by <em>The Imagineering Story</em>, Disneyland continues to evolve alongside America, an amalgamation of its hopes and desires, both past and present. </p>



<p><em>Episodes 1 to 6 available on Disney+.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Elite</em></strong></p>



<p>Catch up on the frothy teen drama before the release of its fourth season, for which Netflix Spain recently revealed the four new additions to its cast. <em>Elite</em>’s first season revolves around three working class students who win a scholarship to study at an exclusive private school as they navigate high society alongside typical adolescent struggles. While it’s a hard sell on intellectual merit alone, the heightened melodrama and extravagance of <em>Elite</em> makes for pure mindless fun.</p>



<p><em>Seasons 1 to 3 available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Time to Hunt (2020)</em></strong></p>



<p>This South Korean thriller is set within a dystopia, where a financial crisis has devastated the South Korean economy. <em>Time to Hunt</em> follows a group of three small time criminals, one of whom is played by Choi Wooshik, who you may recognize as Kiwoo from Parasite. As they embark on one last heist to escape their miserable situation by leaving for Taiwan, things go awry as they are hunted down by a mysterious assassin. Although the ominous nature of the film’s setting may leave you with questions by the time the credits roll, it also serves to heighten the atmospheric and thrilling journey of the three protagonists while alluding to themes of class and brotherhood.</p>



<p><em>Available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>A Suitable Girl (2017)</em></strong></p>



<p>Netflix’s <em>Indian Matchmaking</em>, a reality TV show documenting matchmaker Sima Taparia from Mumbai as she attempts to find her clients a spouse, has set the South Asian diaspora ablaze. Discussion about the show is equally as abundant with memes as with disapproval for its uncritical depiction of arranged marriage, touching on but ultimately glossing over a host of issues such as colourism and misogyny. Taparia is presumably no stranger to such criticisms, having previously starred in <em>A Suitable Girl</em>, a documentary following three women in India, including Taparia’s daughter Ritu, as they search for a spouse and adjust to married life. <em>A Suitable Girl</em> focuses not on delightfully extravagant personalities like Pradhyuman and Aparna, but the experiences of ordinary women as they reflect on how notions of marriage and gender have shaped their lives. Unassuming yet powerful, <em>A Suitable Girl</em> is an insight into the quotidian cultural and familial pressures faced by Indian women.</p>



<p><em>Available on Netflix.&nbsp;&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><strong><em>The Half of It (2020)</em></strong></p>



<p><em>The Half of It</em> revolves around shy recluse Ellie Chu, a Chinese-American teenager on the cusp of adulthood who is stuck in the small town of Squahamish for the foreseeable future. Strapped for cash, she agrees to mediate on the behalf of inarticulate jock Paul Munsky who pays her to write love letters to his crush, the popular daughter of a conservative pastor, Aster Flores. However, Paul and Ellie learn that you can’t plan love, as the three teenagers’ feelings act independently of their preordained destinations, growing unexpectedly deeper and more complicated. Alice Wu’s first film since 2005’s <em>Saving Face</em> is a refreshing, funny and heartwarming take on the “teen movie”, investigating the interlinking themes of adolescent identity, friendship and love.</p>



<p><em>Available on Netflix.</em></p>



<p><strong>Text by Madhu Manivannan<br>Featured image via <em>reddit.com</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/">A Film Fanatic&#8217;s Guide To Staycation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/a-film-fanatics-guide-to-staycation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4267</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Stay Motivated For Online Courses</title>
		<link>/tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses</link>
					<comments>/tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 17:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s all extended-holidays and sleep-ins until we&#8217;re back to home lectures and compulsory studying, right guys? The real question is: how do I stay motivated when doing online courses? It&#8217;s definitely not easy, whether it be younger siblings who just love being in your space, or that you’re home alone and can’t help feeling distracted. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses/">How To Stay Motivated For Online Courses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>It’s all extended-holidays and sleep-ins until we&#8217;re back to home lectures and compulsory studying, right guys? The real question is: how do I stay motivated when doing online courses? It&#8217;s definitely not easy, whether it be younger siblings who just love being in your space, or that you’re home alone and can’t help feeling distracted. Both are unbearable for trying to get work done depending on your study habits, so here are our top tips for staying focused at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>First things first: establishing a clear workspace</strong>.</p>



<p>Whether it be in your room, the living room or even the dining room, it is important that you don’t attempt to work from your bed. While it may be the most comfortable spot in the house, it’s also the biggest temptress for sleeping. Speaking for the majority, it’s the first mistake you can make when trying to work from home. To avoid this, try and find a place in your house that will allow you to maintain a separate workspace; where you can physically and mentally disconnect yourself from distractions and other such things that are not a part of working hours, and means you can leave study-mode when it’s time to relax.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Remember to take time for yourself every day.</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;Apart from attending your compulsory online lectures, studying itself shouldn’t be a complete chore. While you have many things to do such as writing and typing out your notes, reading chapters or planning out reports, it is important that you spread out your tasks throughout the day and week, and not try and complete them in one sitting for the sake of “getting them out of the way”. This way of working gives you a little permission to still be human and decompress between workloads during the day, instead of building up stress and then becoming unmotivated. Prioritising allows you to get the pain-staking tasks out of the way; so that you can work more leisurely in completing your less-demanding tasks throughout the week.</p>



<p>Although it’s important to spread out your work through the day, we all operate differently; what works for one person may not necessarily work for the next. To organise yourself in a way that suits your style, try out different plans of action to discover what studying plan is performance-effective for you. It could be that you feel more stimulated to do work in the evenings, or that you might have more energy after your morning workout.</p>



<p><strong>Finally, re-establish that motivation and asking yourself “why am I doing this?”</strong></p>



<p>Being work-focused in your home is never going to be the same as in the lecture theatre &#8211; surrounded by other students eager to learn. Let’s be honest, it&#8217;s those sitting through the 2-hour 9.00am lectures that are the serious candidates. That said, if you know you&#8217;re not that type of person, it is important you become that person. Remind yourself why you need to work harder than if you were on campus&#8230; in other words, to secure the bag and get that degree.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Tobi Ogunjemilua<br>Featured image via<a href="https://www.freepik.com/free-photo/flat-lay-laptop-mockup-with-notepad_4181729.htm"> </a><em>freepik.com</em></strong>.</p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses/">How To Stay Motivated For Online Courses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/tips-to-cope-with-coming-back-to-a-changed-uni-how-to-stay-motivated-when-doing-online-courses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4264</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Terrace House: Yet Another Reality TV Show Which Hasn’t Learnt Its Lesson</title>
		<link>/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson</link>
					<comments>/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 20:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Japanese show, Terrance House, has attracted a devoted international audience who herald it as a softer alternative to traditionally abrasive, overtly manufactured reality shows like Big Brother and Love Island. Terrace House is Not Like Other Reality TV Shows, at least that’s the implicit promise that lies behind its minimalistic premise of following a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/">Terrace House: Yet Another Reality TV Show Which Hasn’t Learnt Its Lesson</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>The Japanese show, Terrance House, has attracted a devoted international audience who herald it as a softer alternative to traditionally abrasive, overtly manufactured reality shows like Big Brother and Love Island.</p>



<p>Terrace House is <em>Not Like Other Reality TV Shows,</em> at least that’s the implicit promise that lies behind its minimalistic premise of following a rotating cast of six, (mostly) ordinary strangers, as they go about their daily lives and learn to live together in a lavishly decorated house. They are free to end their arc at any time by leaving the house. After each scene, the show cuts to a celebrity panel, who watch and react alongside you. Each member of the panel assumes an archetype, allowing their acute dissection to play out like a skit, while also acting as a surrogate viewer voice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Terrace House’s so-called utopia has been called into question following the death of Hana Kimura, a pro wrestler, as well as a cast member on its most recent season, Terrace House: Tokyo 2019-2020. Shortly before her death last month, Hana tweeted “Every day, I receive nearly 100 honest opinions and I cannot deny that I get hurt,” as <a href="https://www.japantimes.co.jp/culture/2020/05/26/entertainment-news/suicide-note-written-pro-wrestler-terrace-house-star-hana-kimura-discovered/#.Xs_XAy3Mzs0" target="_blank" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">translated by Japan Times</span></a>. These hateful tweets had apparently escalated following the airing of an episode in Japan in which she had a heated argument with another cast member.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Defined by its obsession with the interpersonal conflicts that inevitably arise between housemates, Terrace House feeds of as what Troy Patterson described in the New Yorker as the “honest friction of minor personality flaws and conflicting personal needs”.&nbsp; Yet, the last three complete seasons just happen to be punctuated by the dramatization of a major argument between multiple cast members. Although these arguments do, to an extent, appear to be driven by “honest friction,” it is also apparent that the spectre of the camera looms behind them.</p>



<p>Another facet to the lens through which Terrace House is dramatized is the culture of prurience that underlies the show, which, admittedly, is not atypical within the reality TV genre. Much of the critical discussion about misogyny in Terrace House revolves around its portrayal and discussion of consent, particularly with regards to the relationships between Seina and Shohei in Opening New Doors and Boss and Yume in Tokyo 2019-2020. The voyeuristic nature of the show facilitates its panel in scrutinising and shaming its female cast members for how they express their sexuality.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery aligncenter columns-1 is-cropped"><ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson\/"}' class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="4235" data-permalink="/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/image-12/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?fit=750%2C422&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="750,422" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?fit=750%2C422&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="750" height="422" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?resize=750%2C422" alt="" data-id="4235" data-full-url="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?resize=750%2C422" data-link="/?attachment_id=4235" class="wp-image-4235" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?w=750&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/image.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></li></ul><figcaption class="blocks-gallery-caption"><em>via Time Out</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The show’s regressive attitudes towards women have never been so blatantly mean spirited as in the panel’s treatment of 22 year old student Emika In Tokyo 2019-2020, a storyline involved both Emika and Hana, who eventually became friends within the house, competing for the attention of basketball player Ryo. Emika was framed as the manipulative seductress in opposition to Hana’s innocent naïf through the editing of the show and the panel’s vulgar commentary. Another unique aspect of Terrace House’s format is that episodes may air in a matter of weeks after they were filmed, so housemates sitting in the “playroom” to watch and reflect on the episodes they star in together is a frequent fixture of the show. In Emika’s penultimate episode, she watches an episode in the playroom which casts her in an unflattering light. After hearing the unsympathetic words of the panel, she leaves the room. She breaks down crying, finding online hate comments and the panel’s unrelenting scrutiny to be “excruciating,” and ultimately decides to leave the house. The episode then cuts to the panel, who stand by their criticism and refuse to show any empathy for Emika or to reflect on the veracity and tone of their criticisms. In Emika’s final episode, the guest panellist, Mei Nagano, states “I believe we received the correct impression from her actions,” which the rest of the panel concur with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Terrace House’s panellists appear not only to function as a form of comedic relief, but also as moral arbiters, their observations acting as trials through which Terrace House cast members undergo self-realisation and improvement. Despite, only watching carefully curated scenes edited and chopped to intentionally depict a heightened version of real life, the panelists ignore this superficial construction of reality. As a consequence, they allow wry commentary based on the events of the show to quickly descend into vindictive insults mired in prejudice that blur the lines between the cast members as real people and characters.</p>



<p>In the wake of Hana’s death, Japanese government officials have called for tougher action to be taken on cyberbullying and Terrace House’s Tokyo 2019-2020 season was <a href="https://www.japantimes.co.jp/culture/2020/05/27/entertainment-news/terrace-house-canceled-hana-kimura-suicide/#.XuOFNy3Mzs3">announced to be cancelled</a> on May 27<sup>th</sup>, although the future of the show itself is unclear. What is clear is that the show is untenable in its current format. Its deceptively simple premise belies the fact that living in Terrace House could turn into a pressure cooker of expectations imposed by its panellists, production team, audience and the cast members themselves. But if Terrace House were to be cancelled, its problems might continue to exist. Reality TV shows may continue to mischaracterise their participants through editing and broadcast their lowest moments with little regard as to how this could affect them. Audiences may still take what they see at face value, flattening real people into caricatures that can neatly be placed into the category of “hero” or “villain,” while cast members are left to fend for themselves as social media platforms are used to weaponize these assumptions against them.</p>



<p>Terrace House turned out not to be an idyllic utopia but a microcosm, shining a light on our shortcomings as a society and as digital citizens. Although it is defined by its Japanese cultural context, we are familiar with some of the reality TV tropes and regressive attitudes it employed in the west, reflecting a world where we are quick to make condemnatory judgements and reserve our harshest criticism for women who act outside of their prescribed societal role, rather than men who forcibly kiss their romantic interests and ogle over their female housemates’ “assets.” But while it could stoke our worst impulses, Terrace House was also capable of celebrating understanding and compassion. Despite its problems, the wide majority of fans tuned in for scenes of housemates diligently plating party snacks and arranging balloons for surprise birthday dinners, of couples navigating the first stages of their relationships, of friendships evolving from nervous introductions to tearful hugs goodbye. In its best moments, Terrace House was an ode to human connection, finding the beauty in its most joyful as well as its most painful moments. In the wake of tragedy, this aspect of the show has taken on a poignant relevancy.</p>



<p><strong>Text by Madhu Manivannan<br>Featured image via <em>Eater</em>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/">Terrace House: Yet Another Reality TV Show Which Hasn’t Learnt Its Lesson</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/terrace-house-yet-another-reality-tv-show-which-hasnt-learnt-its-lesson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4234</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Actually Happened At The London Black Lives Matter Protests</title>
		<link>/what-actually-happened-at-the-london-black-lives-matter-protests/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=what-actually-happened-at-the-london-black-lives-matter-protests</link>
					<comments>/what-actually-happened-at-the-london-black-lives-matter-protests/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rubi Ager recounts her experience of last week’s protests that brought the capital to a halt.&#160; June 6, 2020 This is a first-hand account of the actual events &#8211; of what actually happened rather than the twisted lies a white supremacist media feeds the public. The centre of the protest was Downing Street; crowds gathered [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/what-actually-happened-at-the-london-black-lives-matter-protests/">What Actually Happened At The London Black Lives Matter Protests</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p style="font-size:18px"><strong>Rubi Ager recounts her experience of last week’s protests that brought the capital to a halt.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><strong>June 6, 2020</strong></p>



<p>This is a first-hand account of the actual events &#8211; of what actually happened rather than the twisted lies a white supremacist media feeds the public. The centre of the protest was Downing Street; crowds gathered around the Prime Minister’s residence, chanting peacefully, holding up signs, letting off flares and pink smoke bombs to protest against police brutality and racism. A march also took place, starting from Parliament Square; people joined as the march went on, continuing to chant and support the movement. The awful weather neither stopped us nor dampened our spirits.</p>



<p>The protest was kept peaceful by the people until the police started pushing us unexpectedly from where we were gathered. Coming down from Trafalgar Square, police horses and vans started to charge at us, causing mass panic amongst the crowds, and people started running away. People fleeing left their bikes on the ground, threw objects such as plastic bottles in self-defence and tried to get away quickly to avoid injury. Amidst the panic, a horse trampled over a bike, causing the policewoman riding it to fall off; it then charged into the crowd and knocked over a protestor. This is an example of how police turned a peaceful protest into a violent one, making people angry enough to retaliate against the brutality they were faced with. It was the protestors themselves who restored peace by chanting “keep it peaceful” and walking back to the original scene of protest, playing songs about love and unity, such as Bob Marley’s ‘One Love’ and Black Eyed Peas’ ‘Where Is The Love.’ People were singing together and dancing as one, rising above attempts to disperse the crowds and mar the reputation of the movement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unfortunately, the media reported things differently, claiming that a bike was thrown at a horse and focusing all their attention on that isolated incident. They seem to have sided with the police and that is a dangerous use of their power; by framing things a certain way, they are indirectly being unsupportive. We caution against believing everything you hear about the protests, because zeroing in on isolated incidents of disorder takes the focus away from the movement and the work that needs to be done to dismantle systematic racism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is another example of the media undermining the cause, blaming protestors rather than examining the behaviour of law enforcement and the flaws of the current government. The use of horses obviously carried a risk of harm and was probably intended to cause chaos in a peaceful protest, setting off fight-or-flight responses when the horse lost control and charged into the crowd. We do not condone vandalism and criminal damage as part of protests and the treatment of the statues of war heroes is controversial, but we are also disheartened that the media only focuses on these incidents as if they are representative of the movement as a whole. It is another excuse to dismiss protesters’ voices, labelling them as ‘thugs’ and exaggerating their responses, with claims that they threw ‘bricks’ (which did not happen in the scenes I witnessed) or behaved unreasonably. So please be cautious about the way the media chooses to portray the protests, read widely, keeping in mind that certain sources could be biased, and double-check things before sharing with others.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is an outrage that we still have to fight for equal rights for black people and we now have to also put our lives at risk by protesting in the midst of a pandemic. Do not let biased sources detract from the cause we are protesting for.</p>



<p><strong>Text by Ruby Ager</strong><br><strong>Featured image by <em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.marouanejoubba.com/ldnprotest03062020?fbclid=IwAR2cHzS7aSDl86-y1ONfDV3BGxRX8tO2atEFojwXkDL3Y3LjTCGs-EDborA" target="_blank">Marouane Joubba</a></em></strong>.</p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/what-actually-happened-at-the-london-black-lives-matter-protests/">What Actually Happened At The London Black Lives Matter Protests</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/what-actually-happened-at-the-london-black-lives-matter-protests/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4227</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Protest</title>
		<link>/a-protest/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-protest</link>
					<comments>/a-protest/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 17:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nicole&#8217;s poem explores the conflict many face when deciding to protest for Black Lives Matter in the midst of the Covid-19 Pandemic. Featured image by Marouane Joubba</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-protest/">A Protest</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>Nicole&#8217;s poem explores the conflict many face when deciding to protest for <strong>Black Lives Matter</strong> in the midst of the <strong>Covid-19</strong> Pandemic.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4215" data-permalink="/a-protest/a-protest-poem/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-protest-poem-.jpg?fit=1280%2C1280&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1280,1280" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="a-protest-poem-" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-protest-poem-.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-protest-poem-.jpg?fit=1024%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="1280" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-protest-poem-.jpg?fit=1024%2C1024" alt="" class="wp-image-4215" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-protest-poem-.jpg?w=1280&amp;ssl=1 1280w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-protest-poem-.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-protest-poem-.jpg?resize=1024%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-protest-poem-.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-protest-poem-.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Featured image by <a href="https://www.marouanejoubba.com/ldnprotest03062020?fbclid=IwAR2cHzS7aSDl86-y1ONfDV3BGxRX8tO2atEFojwXkDL3Y3LjTCGs-EDborA" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Marouane Joubba</em></a></strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-protest/">A Protest</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/a-protest/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4214</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five Climate Conscious Flicks</title>
		<link>/five-climate-conscious-flicks/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=five-climate-conscious-flicks</link>
					<comments>/five-climate-conscious-flicks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bust lockdown boredom and catch up with our top 5 films championing environmental issues. Movies have the power to shape narratives, introduce new perspectives and they can be particularly compelling when bringing awareness to environmental issues. Below find SUBCULTURED writer Nathaniel’s recommendations, some are documentaries and some aren’t – but their stories are all a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/five-climate-conscious-flicks/">Five Climate Conscious Flicks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p style="font-size:18px"><strong>Bust lockdown boredom and catch up with our top 5 films championing environmental issues.</strong></p>



<p>Movies have the power to shape narratives, introduce new perspectives and they can be particularly compelling when bringing awareness to environmental issues.</p>



<p>Below find SUBCULTURED writer Nathaniel’s recommendations, some are documentaries and some aren’t – but their stories are all a must-watch.</p>



<p><strong><em>WALL-E</em> (2008)</strong> | Directed by Andrew Stanton &amp; Written by Andrew Stanton and Jim Reardon</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/aM4ZyAm7LUv2kYj7TXfyAaKRL8wUIZCSFnjGYDTcYrN_CITOqieE-5xsy-x5-Z41kVlyiCpAdfIessXisp2G9mIBfESER13uVhPpWnlcxNHDRRO88X96kINexon7uiBvV7rJMkc" alt="Nonconformity - Corpron_Transcendentalism"/></figure>



<p><em>WALL-E</em>’s cinematography and screenplay are amazing in depicting the story of WALL-E (standing for ‘Waste Allocation Load Lifter Earth-class’) [voiced by Ben Burtt], who’s the last robot on Earth. WALL-E’s tasked to tidy the planet as mankind’s had to abandon Earth after becoming filled with rubbish. WALL-E ultimately embarks on an exciting adventure when he meet EVE [voiced by Elissa Knight]: a sleek probe sent back to Earth on a scanning mission. However, one message is clear: we need to manage waste, look after nature and protect our planet. <em>WALL-E</em> won the 2008 Golden Globe Award for Best Animated Feature Film and 2009 Hugo Award for Best Long Form Dramatic Presentation.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Earth</em> (2007)</strong> | Directed by Alastair Fothergill and Mark Linfield &amp; Written Alastair Fothergill, Mark Linfield and Leslie Megahey</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/wdwfBTGNFdkZDcfAAhi8r1l8H8R0Rp54_tYc6v3VvHMzaW8vjt14oewQs06W9c6YTXiUzTpsafgvSA4UR7ggFATgVppSr-8Gl8p6MTvfum3WDx22hhOTZFLcr4JIm77nhC8xuhI" alt="Earth (2007 film) - Alchetron, The Free Social Encyclopedia"/></figure>



<p><em>Earth</em> documents a viewers’ journey from the North Pole to the South Pole over the course of twelve months; and focuses on the polar bear, the African bush elephant and the humpback whale. This film further follows a range of other animals in their natural environment during the calendar year. Cinematically, the film has stunning scenes, as time-lapse cameras are used to enable the enthralling action moments on screen. Based on the BBC’s Planet Earth: Patrick Stewart narrates this movie, which is the second highest grossing nature documentary of all time behind <em>March of the Penguins</em> (2005).</p>



<p><strong><em>Avatar</em> (2009)</strong> | Directed and Written by James Cameron</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/0tTZlxTBVwsP9xM55iBcPZTFBuQF08LulFHLij3FDTBOrIzJaLTh2_vOOS7gU_hbnP01ON_3bx0uaG7O-L36DIBtS7uS3FCCi21XwLRBR5QYz8Qdus1ia-Z6mtyP0n9cDYtpyXY" alt="Avatar filming delayed in New Zealand due to coronavirus | Metro News"/></figure>



<p><em>Avatar</em> follows the events that transpire for the Na’vi on the lush and vibrant alien moon of Pandora after humans work to colonise the land and mine the mineral unobtanium directly from the surface. The overuse of natural resources on Earth has forced humans to find supply of energy elsewhere. <em>Avatar</em> studies ecology, the environment and implications of personal choice when our protagonist Jake Sully [played by Sam Worthington], a former marine who joins the Avatar programme (which involves humans remotely operating genetically engineered Na&#8217;vi body to breathe and interact with true Na’vi on Pandora to support the humans’ mining efforts), becomes close to Neytiri [played by Zoe Saldana], daughter of the Omaticaya leader (the Na&#8217;vi clan central to this story). Cinematically, <em>Avatar</em>’s visual effects are incredible; and the film went to become the highest grossing of all-time at $2.79 billion globally, surpassing Cameron’s own record for <em>Titanic</em> (1997), which previously held this status, until <em>Avengers: Endgame</em> (2019) grossed $2.797 billion. James Cameron signed with 20th Century Fox to produce four sequels; with <em>Avatar 2</em> expected to be released on December 17<sup>th</sup>, 2021!&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Trashed</em> (2012)</strong> | Directed and Written by Candida Brady</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/H9kbUtOZe7_uSBzaYkxhHT8MwBqQH3RcPmQ2vdqxe-qhNFMlt6p0QT6RiHp0m63RJX5o4RGNYmNEeBOnZ2evcOKpOvtngDiInwbufEsP-bB0xeLZiBr8z_aLtUmjmeKfKDMQad0" alt="Jeremy Irons: Fighting Trash in Bali and Beyond • The Yak Online"/></figure>



<p><em>Trashed</em>, is an environmental documentary in which Jeremy Irons ‘discovers the extent and effects of the global waste problem, as he travels around the world to beautiful destinations tainted by pollution’. This film has been released in over 40 countries and has even had special showings at the Houses of Parliament and the European Parliament– and it’s a must-watch for film fans and climate activists alike. The goal of zero-waste is discussed alongside issues of rubbish build-up leading to groundwater, greenhouse gas and animal danger. The film premiered at Cannes Film Festival in 2012 and it was further nominated for Camera d&#8217;Or.</p>



<p><strong><em>Chasing Ice</em> (2012) </strong>| Directed by Jeff Orlowski &amp; Written by Mark Monroe</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/bJFETPyru0VK61_ADdlcpOrC3QdlY7lZm21dbVQgI9u8d81l2Y4F60zQDIJ1qNXeLVGZp-RWMBIoN6WGmJkLyDo1ssxCkRVWpQr7-3yLIuuy54_PYQaPqA4WLoY5o2AwXmRPDoo" alt="A snow covered mountain

Description automatically generated"/></figure>



<p><em>Chasing Ice</em> is a documentary that follows conservation photographer James Balog capturing the effects of global warming on glaciers in Greenland, Iceland and Alaska through the use of time-lapse cameras. Cinematically, this film is shot beautifully, which only heightens concerns against the earth’s atmospheric temperature gradually increasing over time. Balog states at its end that – “when my daughters look at me 25 to 30 years from now and say ‘what were you doing when global warming was happening and you guys knew what was coming down the road’, I want to be able to say I was doing everything I knew how to do”. This drive is evidenced throughout the movie by the filmmakers continuing to record despite technical difficulties, camera issues, team pressures and injuries. The documentary premiered at Sundance and won the Satellite Award for Best Documentary Film in 2012, a testament to its pioneering dedication to countering climate change.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Text by Nathaniel Nelson-Williams</strong><br><strong>Featured image via&nbsp;</strong><strong><em>https://newmediarockstars.com/</em></strong><strong>.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/five-climate-conscious-flicks/">Five Climate Conscious Flicks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/five-climate-conscious-flicks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4198</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Travel Without Leaving Your House</title>
		<link>/how-to-travel-without-leaving-your-house/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-travel-without-leaving-your-house</link>
					<comments>/how-to-travel-without-leaving-your-house/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 17:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The books that will help you mentally breach Boris’ lockdown. With the world enveloped in COVID-19 pandemonium, your future travel plans have undoubtedly been snuffed, and although your cancelled holiday is not the worst thing to happen, you can’t help but feel a little blue… But do not fret, here are SUBCULTURED’s literary suggestions to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-travel-without-leaving-your-house/">How To Travel Without Leaving Your House</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p class="has-medium-font-size">The books that will help you mentally breach Boris’ lockdown.</p>



<p>With the world enveloped in COVID-19 pandemonium, your future travel plans have undoubtedly been snuffed, and although your cancelled holiday is not the worst thing to happen, you can’t help but feel a little blue…</p>



<p>But do not fret, here are SUBCULTURED’s literary suggestions to get you through the dreary days and give you oodles of inspiration for your post-corona hols. Capitalise on the abundance of your new found free time and transport yourself to far flung corners of the globe, revelling in the escapism that a good book brings.</p>



<p><em><strong>The Gringo Trail: A Darkly Comic Road-Trip Through South America</strong> </em>by <strong>Mark Mann</strong></p>



<p>The satirical, tongue-in-cheek travel companion will transport you to the gritty cocaine clubs of Colombia, the peaks of Patagonia and everything in-between. Follow Mark and his two university pals as they blunder through the hedonism, and hellishness, of the Gringo Trail. Perfect if you are longing for a rugged backpacking adventure.</p>



<p><strong><em>Norwegian Wood</em></strong> by <strong>Haruki Murakami</strong></p>



<p>This 1987 rite-of-passage novel is a tale that navigates through the heartbreak, loss and agony of protagonist Toru Watanabe, a Tokyo college student. Set in the backdrop of the 1960’s, in Japan’s capital, you are introduced to the beautiful and damaged Naoko, and the elusive Midori in the midst of a society on the brink of modernity. Its ultimately devastating plot, weaves through the bohemian neighbourhoods of Eastern Tokyo to the icy forests north of the Kyoto Prefecture, all in a bid to relinquish the past.</p>



<p><strong><em>Burmese Days</em></strong> by <strong>George Orwell</strong></p>



<p>Orwell’s first novel echoes many of his later great works about class, systemic inequality and injustice. He himself called it one of his “purple passages” in which he indulges in a description and imagery so vivid that you feel like you yourself are on the eastern frontier of the British empire. The fictional characters stem from Orwell’s own experience as an imperial policeman and through them the evils, ineptitudes and contradictions of colonial society are exposed.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Goodbye to Berlin</em></strong> by <strong>Christopher Isherwood</strong></p>



<p>Set in pre-war Berlin, Isherwood, drawing from his own past, evokes the long forgotten glamour of the early 1930’s, a decade characterised as much by decadence, excess and great cabaret as by the fight against the rise of Hitler. A snapshot of Weimar Germany, one long eclipsed, is offered and introduces us to no one else but the upper-class, English eccentric Sally Bowles, dive in to this book for a glimpse of a world dictated by debauchery.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Pachinko</em></strong> by <strong>Min Jin Lee</strong></p>



<p>The novel’s name hails from the gambling parlours that represented hope for Koreans. Korean-American novelist, Min Jin Lee, portrays the trials and tribulations which have affronted Korea in the past century by following the family of Sunja, through the generations, who migrate to neighbouring Japan. Strong-willed characters and their stories of love, loyalty and sacrifice flit between heaving Korean markets and kimchi sellers to the prestigious halls of Japanese universities. It is the first book written in English which explores the intricacies of Japanese-Korean culture and is a profound exposé on the unspoken lives of ordinary citizens.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Americanah</em></strong> by <strong>Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie</strong></p>



<p>Ifemelu and Obinze are young and in love when they depart a Nigeria under military control. They reunite after 15 years of Ifemulu residing in the United States and Obinze living a precarious life as an illegal immigrant in London. The title of a book is a Niegrian-ism for those who have lived so long out of their country that they forget the nuances of what it means to be Nigerian. Adichi’s insightful writing focuses on the importance of culture, while the juxtaposition of the pristine campus of Princeton with Ifemelu’s native Lagos is colourful, humorous, and gives the novel a humbling depth.</p>



<p><strong><em>Down under: Travels in a sunburned country</em> </strong>by <strong>Bill Bryson</strong></p>



<p>Bryson shows us that Australia is not just another continent – it is also home to many things that can kill you! Factual passages interjected with pithy one liners and anecdotal hilarity are the perfect antidote to homebound gloom. Follow Bryson on his travels down-under and you will embark on an adventure-filled journey full of curiosities.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Text by Eve Wills</strong>.</p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-travel-without-leaving-your-house/">How To Travel Without Leaving Your House</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/how-to-travel-without-leaving-your-house/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4173</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
