<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Interview &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/interview/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A fashion, culture, art and music publication, written by students about students.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 18:49:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/cropped-12773305_10206631248554054_481252708_o.jpg?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Interview &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107671177</site>	<item>
		<title>An Interview With The Man Behind SurreyFess</title>
		<link>/an-interview-with-the-man-behind-surreyfess/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=an-interview-with-the-man-behind-surreyfess</link>
					<comments>/an-interview-with-the-man-behind-surreyfess/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3585</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SurreyFess. The elusive Facebook confession page where the gritty truth and mundane reality of Surrey campus life can be found, library crush declarations, passive aggressive flat mate grievances, memes frequently directed at Chancellor Max Lu, alongside people genuinely searching for life advice from fellow students, are submitted anonymously to the online forum. The posts are [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-interview-with-the-man-behind-surreyfess/">An Interview With The Man Behind SurreyFess</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>SurreyFess. The elusive Facebook confession page where the
gritty truth and mundane reality of Surrey campus life can be found, library
crush declarations, passive aggressive flat mate grievances, memes frequently
directed at Chancellor Max Lu, alongside people genuinely searching for life
advice from fellow students, are submitted anonymously to the online forum. The
posts are often a hit for procrastinators and people avoiding dissertation, but
who is the person behind the site who holds all the power in campus´ favourite
confession outlet? </p>



<p>Speculation points it to being a third year, citrus loving male,
who possibly has too much time on their hands as a former meme contributor
student to Dank Surrey Memes pages and now has progressed to running the SurreyFess
page.<em></em></p>



<p>We spoke to the SurreyFess admin to find out more&#8230;</p>



<p><strong>Can you describe your experience at Surrey?</strong><br><em>I moved to Surrey and was lucky enough to have some pretty good flatmates. In fact, half of my first year flat still doesn’t know I run the page! I had a pretty good first year; I made a few new friends, but stayed quite close to my flatmates and friends that I knew before university. In second year I became a lot more outgoing, and think I’ve only become even more outgoing this year, joining a couple of societies and going to a lot more socials.</em></p>



<p><strong>How did you get involved with SurreyFess?</strong><br><em>It started with the page Dank Surrey Memes actually. I used to send a lot of memes to the DSM admins and became good friends with them. I discussed the possibility of a Surrey themed confession page the way other universities have them &#8211; Oxfess was the big one I was familiar with. We toyed with the idea, but nothing really came of it, until one night in July (I think?) I pulled the trigger and created the page. A quick post on DSM was all it took – SurreyFess was born</em>.</p>



<p><strong>Is it a group or just you?</strong><br><em>Initially I offered moderator roles to the DSM admins. One was more than happy to help for a while. I found that I was doing a large amount of the posting, so I asked whether they minded if I took it solo. It wasn’t at all a problem and we’re still on good terms about it. In fact, I usually send submissions I enjoy to them before they make it onto the Facebook page as a bit of a sneak preview. To answer the question, yeah – now it’s just me.</em></p>



<p><strong>As it has grown in popularity, it seems like a fair amount of effort to manage, what motivates you?</strong><br><em>Since the move to the Uni-Truths site it’s been a lot less effort than it’d seem to manage! I think in part the big motivator is how big (and successful? That’s debatable) the page is – taking 5 minutes a few times a day to work through the submission queue isn’t too time consuming. I love having something to read in lectures, and honestly seeing people around me reading Surreyfess posts and talking about it is always fun.</em></p>



<p><strong>What role do you take in censoring different entries?</strong><br><em>So, the accept/reject ratio is about 6:1. As far as rejections go, it’s usually down to</em>:<br><em>• Posts that go against Facebook standards / would get the page or post blocked</em><br><em>• Attacks on students/lecturers/groups of people</em><br><em>• Advertisements/spam</em><br><br><em>Lecturers have always been a grey area. There’s one that I’ve spoken to and he’s flattered seeing posts about himself whereas others don’t like it, so it’s usually just the positive posts that make it through about them. My rule of thumb has been; “if I think someone will ask me to take it down, don’t post it in the first place” and that’s worked well.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Are the entries with the new submission, Uni Truths form completely anonymous?</strong><br><em>Yes! Crushninja used to give a vague location the post was submitted from. This didn’t give much away as the most common location tags were “Guildford, Surrey, United Kingdom” and just “United Kingdom”. Sometimes this meant I could pick up if someone had sent multiple posts in a row (imagine five submissions in the space of ten minutes all from one town) – but it largely didn’t help me identify people. Uni Truths doesn’t even provide a location, so I’m 100% in the dark now. Unless people message their confessions to the Facebook page, in which case it’s their own fault.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Are you concerned by the number of individuals confessing mental health problems? </strong><br><em>A bit concerned, but not too surprised that people use Surreyfess for it. While it was the last thing I anticipated the page being used for when I created it, I can see why the anonymity helps people. Coming to Surreyfess for advice in general was a common thing, and I don’t see now why that can’t extend to mental health advice. Our submission portals have had contact numbers for the Samaritans and Papyrus UK for a long time.  I have a ton of respect for the people who give advice on those posts – they do a far better job than I could.</em></p>



<p><strong>Do you think that this platform is helping or hindering the community of Surrey?</strong><br><em>Probably net positive, but I’m honestly not too sure. I don’t think it does too much harm…? Except when I see people on the page in lectures – like, focus! Although it’s kind of flattering, seeing someone consider the page you run more interesting than the lecture they’re in.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Which types of submissions are you tired of posting?</strong><br><em>Honestly, it’s mostly the politics and the big debates that Surreyfess spawns. That and “where are the Rubix photos”. Everything else &#8211; the memes, the campus life, the declarations of love, are all great fun. I recently slowed down on the “not a substitute for a personality” posts. Lots of people didn’t want to see any more of those.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Do you ever submit any posts yourself, to share your views?</strong><br><em>Yes, not too often though. Maybe once a week on average? Oh, and perks of the job – you can submit a post and skip it to the front of the post queue!</em></p>



<p><strong>What will be the future of Surrey Fess?</strong><br><em>Near future – a lot more of the same. New trends come up all the time, it’s always great seeing what people come up with. Longer term… who knows? </em><br> <br> <em>Thank you!!</em><br> <em>Tell Leroy I love him</em>.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Eve Willis<br>Picture research by Anna Irina; featured image from <em>rawpixel.com</em>.</strong><br><br><strong>Special thanks to SurreyFess admin for your participation.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-interview-with-the-man-behind-surreyfess/">An Interview With The Man Behind SurreyFess</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/an-interview-with-the-man-behind-surreyfess/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3585</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Interview with DJ SoFly</title>
		<link>/an-interview-with-dj-sofly/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=an-interview-with-dj-sofly</link>
					<comments>/an-interview-with-dj-sofly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 18:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>MJ SoFly is a creative, experimental and masterful 20-year-old rapper from West London whose sound is reminiscent of nostalgic hip-hop music. The up-and-coming artist has been surrounded by music his entire life. His first interactions with music were through his Dad who is a former DJ, so in this way musical talent and creativity is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-interview-with-dj-sofly/">An Interview with DJ SoFly</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/an-interview-with-dj-sofly\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-1 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3569" data-permalink="/an-interview-with-dj-sofly/untitled-14/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Untitled.png?fit=805%2C537&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="805,537" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Untitled" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Untitled.png?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Untitled.png?fit=805%2C537&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="805" height="537" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Untitled.png?resize=805%2C537" alt="" data-id="3569" data-link="/?attachment_id=3569" class="wp-image-3569" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Untitled.png?w=805&amp;ssl=1 805w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Untitled.png?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Untitled.png?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w" sizes="(max-width: 805px) 100vw, 805px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption> <br> <br> <br> <br> <br> <br> <br><br><em> ‘…making music was never something that was completely out of my reach because it was already implanted deep within me’, says West Londoner MJ SoFly</em></figcaption></figure></li></ul>



<p><strong>MJ SoFly</strong> is a creative, experimental and masterful 20-year-old rapper from West London whose sound is reminiscent of nostalgic hip-hop music. The up-and-coming artist has been surrounded by music his entire life. His first interactions with music were through his Dad who is a former DJ, so in this way musical talent and creativity is instilled within him. For this SUBCULTURED issue, Mirfat Khamis caught up with the ‘Fly’ guy to discuss all things music, inspiration and how he balances his studies whilst making and releasing music. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>What do you
enjoy the most about making music?</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><em>What I enjoy most about making music is being in the studio with me and my people making music. What makes the experience even more enjoyable would be the feeling of going to the studio not knowing what I’m going to make and leaving the studio with one or more songs.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>How would you
describe your sound and what genre does your music fall into?</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><em>I wouldn’t say I have a particular type of sound just yet but what I will say is that my sound definitely stems from hip-hop. I personally feel like I don’t fit into any one genre because my versatility allows me to sway across a number of different genres. </em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>What was the
inspiration behind your artist name?</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><em>The MJ part of my artist name is something that people have always called me growing up. The SoFly part of my name is part of the record label that I co-founded with my friends. It is a music, management and visual arts collective movement. </em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Who are you
inspired by?</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><em>I am inspired by artists such as The Notorious B.I.G, Snoop Dogg and Donell Jones as I have grown up listening to their music. To some extent this is where my inspiration of music comes from but not entirely. This is because part of what inspires me is music itself like instruments used and the beats and percussions.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Have you ever
dealt with performance anxiety?</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><em>Not really. I always can’t wait to get on stage. I always experience a good nervous feeling. I just want to get on the stage and when the show is done, I just want to be back on again performing doing what I love – sharing my music and telling my story through it.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>When can we
expect new music? / What’s next for you?</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><em>Me and SoFly are expecting to release music within the next couple of months, hopefully during the Summer. There is a SoFly tape due to come out, so watch out for that one. Admittedly we haven’t released a lot of music recently because we have been working hard in the studio producing and making tracks as we are working on perfecting our craft in terms of our delivery, flow, lyrics and the beats. Personally, I don’t want to rush the music process, so I am looking forward to sharing musical content that is much more advanced than the music we have released previously.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>What do you
feel is the best song you’ve released and why?</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><em>I don’t think I’ve released a song of my highest potential just yet. I think my best songs are still unreleased. But if I could name one song, I’ve released I’d say life at 2am with my friend Primo. I think that’s my best song so far because it is a relevant reflection of the experiences I was facing at the time. This was the first song I’ve done where the beat was different to what I would usually rap to. Also, it is the first song where I expressed heartfelt lyrics. So yeah that song is most certainly close to the heart.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>If you could choose
to collaborate with one artist from the U.K and U.S who would it be and why?</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><em>Okay. From the U.K I
would choose to work with IAMDDB because she brings her own wave and is in her
own lane when it comes to the music which makes her work very original and
authentic. Her sound is something that can’t be replicated. And I feel as
though she is one of a kind in the U.K especially because there aren’t many
original old school and new school artists that can do it like her. So, I think
if we would ever get in the studio together, we would make real good music.</em></p>



<p><em>And from the U.S it would have to be Nipsey Hussle who is one of my all-time favorite rappers, especially of this generation because not a lot of artists can rap about real life the way that he does. Nipsey is always telling a message and a story in his music. You can tell that he is a real musician based on his flow, delivery, voice and the instruments he chooses to use. And yeah, he’s woke! I just consider him one of the greats.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>When did you realise you had such a passion
for music?</strong></p>



<p><em>A year and a half ago I really realised my passion for music when me and my friend went into the studio to make music and a year and a half later, we’re still here! My passion also comes from the fact that I grew up around music. My Dad was a DJ in his days so music was constantly around me. He would always be teaching me about music, quizzing be about who produced songs and I’d just have to try and guess. So, making music was never something that was completely out of my reach because it was already implanted deep within me.</em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>What makes
your music unique?</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><em>I would say my music is unique because it is a very different sound to the U.K music scene. And even though I am trying to make a break through into the U.K music scene, I am bringing a very old-school American sort of vibe. The music in the U.K is in need of something new and that’s something that I am offering because no other artist in the U.K is jumping on beats like mine or has a flow like mine, I’m in my own lane. Not only this but I feel as though every verse, every hook, every chorus that I write has a meaningful message behind it. If I’m not telling a story then you might learn something about me in my music. Which is why my music is so different, because most rappers in the music scene aren’t sending messages through their music anymore. </em></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>What is your favorite
song that isn’t yours?</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p><em>My favorite song right now is “Brown Hair” by Jay Critch because like me he is also in his own lane, doing his own thing, with his own sound and own style. Even the energy he brings into his songs is completely different to a lot of songs out there right now.</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Mirfat Khamis</strong></p>



<p><strong>Picture research by Anna Irina; featured image from Pinterest.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-interview-with-dj-sofly/">An Interview with DJ SoFly</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/an-interview-with-dj-sofly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3568</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Interview with Adriana Blanc</title>
		<link>/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=an-interview-with-adriana-blanc</link>
					<comments>/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 18:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>So it’s nearing the end of February, and I’m sure most of us have fallen off the wagon when it came to our well intentioned New Year’s resolution to get back in the gym and start getting fit. Well, not all hope is lost! We sat down and spoke with Adriana Blanc, a student and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/">An Interview with Adriana Blanc</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>So it’s nearing the end of February, and I’m sure
most of us have fallen off the wagon when it came to our well intentioned New
Year’s resolution to get back in the gym and start getting fit. Well, not all
hope is lost! We sat down and spoke with Adriana Blanc, a student and personal
trainer who is making it her mission to empower young women to be the best,
healthiest and happiest versions of themselves. With easy to follow workouts
and delicious looking meal prep ideas, Adriana uses Instagram and YouTube to
connect with hundreds of young women struggling with their fitness journey.
With specific advice for university students trying to juggle a healthy
lifestyle with deadlines and the odd night out, Adriana offers practical advice
whilst being your own personal hype girl. </p>



<p>Adriana’s personality shines through in the
following interview, it’s clear she feels passionately about health and
well-being. So give it a read, get inspired and keeping pursuing those health
and fitness goals. We can’t wait to see what she does next!</p>



<p><strong>Hi! First
of all, could you just introduce and tell us a little bit about yourself and
what you do?</strong></p>



<p>Hi! I’m Adriana Blanc, I’m a 21 year old final
year student at the University of Bath studying Chemistry and I’m also a
personal trainer. </p>



<p>I have a genuine love and interest in helping young, newly independent females like myself implement long term and sustainable healthy habits, so I created an Instagram account called <a href="https://www.instagram.com/adrianablancfit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="@adrianablancfit (opens in a new tab)">@adrianablancfit</a> aiming to achieve just that. The «&nbsp;Healthy at Uni&nbsp;»&nbsp; Facebook community I created has two groups with over 140+ girls in both so that I can connect to them more personally. As a uni student, with both of these platforms I aim to help female students healthily transition into and experience university life by providing them with informative resources on exercise, nutrition, and mindset. </p>



<p>I also have various off and online personal
training clients, and teach circuit training fitness classes at university to
girls&nbsp;!</p>



<p><strong>Where did
you start with your fitness journey? Have you always liked working out or was
it a lifestyle change for you?</strong></p>



<p>It was never a lifestyle change for me as I’ve always been in love with sports – my family is very athletic so I grew up playing volleyball, tennis, and football competitively and am currently on the university volleyball team. I got into structured gymming/working out during my first year of university – just working out in my dorm room because I felt way too intimidated by the university gym (Uni of Bath is literally known for their huge athletes!) In second year, I decided to overcome my fear and just hit up the gym and slowly but surely my confidence in there built up. I started to love mixing heavy weightlifting with circuits, High intensity training, and cardio as an overall fitness routine, so have continued since and will continue for life!</p>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-1 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3530" data-permalink="/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/img_6755/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?fit=4032%2C3024&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="4032,3024" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1540833972&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;40&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.04&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_6755" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?fit=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="4032" height="3024" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?fit=1024%2C768" alt="" data-id="3530" data-link="/?attachment_id=3530" class="wp-image-3530" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?w=4032&amp;ssl=1 4032w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_6755.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></li></ul>



<p><strong>What made
you want to start your fitness Instagram account?</strong></p>



<p>I was getting asked a lot for advice and help
from my friends, and I noticed that often their questions were self-sabotage
driven, such as “I hate how I look in this” or “I want to get rid of this”.
While I of course understand the motivation behind those worries, with my
account, I want to instill in all girls my age the mindset that exercise and
healthy eating should come from a desire for self improvement, self care, and
self love, NOT from a place of shame, self-hatred, and wanting to fundamentally
change yourself. It is so important to develop this mindset. It’s essential to
establishing long-term habits that make you enjoy the process, that make you
patient (rather than have you searching for a «&nbsp;quick fix&nbsp;») that
make you feel proud of your efforts (rather than feeling frustrated for the
speed of your progress) and that make you KIND to yourself. </p>



<p>With my stories and posts that just show my
realistic day to day life of my nights out, stressing over uni coursework,
having fun meals with friends, but still being able to fit in exercise and
cooking OVERALL, I want to show that it really is a LIFESTYLE, not a strict set
of rules that we have to 100% live for.&nbsp; </p>



<p>The reason I wanted to create a “healthy at uni”
theme to my account is because university is a
particularly vulnerable point in the lives of young females; it is the first
time we are fully independent and rely on our own willpower/motivation for self
care (cooking, exercising, socialising). It is widely known that this often
results in a lack of self care; in US colleges a popular term called the
“Freshman 15” refers to this in that freshers may gain or lose 15 lbs in their
first year of university at the expense of their health. An overall <strong>trend</strong> has been observed: often
this quick decline in health in first year directly affects many other aspects
of our lives, such as academic performance, self confidence, and body image
(especially given our tendency to spend so much time on social media channels
that portray a “ideal” body). Also, <strong>gym/exercise
intimidation</strong> is especially prevalent in student university gyms (and even
more so at the #1 UK 2018 sports university) where gym members tend to be known
acquaintances and already knowledgeable and experienced athletes. This often
deters young female students from either joining, consistently attending, or
making the most out of the gym. With my Instagram account, I wanted to create
resources (workout programs, budget/quick meal recipes, and self
help/development messages) that are dedicated to and account for university
life and culture. </p>



<p>With
guidance, it is completely possible to <strong>both</strong>
enjoy and have fun at university (the social/drinking/eating out/late nights
aspect of it) <strong>while</strong> developing and
implementing healthy habits. When practiced from the VERY beginning of
university, I genuinely believe the students will be able to overall make the
most out of and feel our best throughout university: mentally, physically, and
academically.</p>



<p><strong>It’s
great to see that you don’t just focus on exercise, but on well-being and
nutrition too! Why is that stuff so important to you?</strong></p>



<p>Exercise is just one form of self-care, and
knowing how to use it in a way that is enjoyable, that benefits your ambitions
and that you can actually stick to is what will make it enhance your life. </p>



<p><strong>What
advice to you have for someone too scared to start their own fitness journey?</strong></p>



<p>I talk about this topic all the time because I
feel so passionate about giving people the courage to push past their fear of
change, others people’s judgments, so that they can just START doing the things
they know they want to do. </p>



<p>Like anything in life, the beginning is
uncomfortable. Usually, there are 3 reasons why someone would feel intimidated
or scared: You’re unsure if you’re doing things correctly, you’re intimidated
by those who are more experienced/you compare yourself to them, and you think
you will have to dedicate 100% of your effort all the time to “being healthy”. </p>



<p>I have a YouTube video that discusses gym
confidence which you can check out!</p>



<p>This is a post I wrote dedicated to this topic:</p>



<p>To
all the ladies that tell me you really struggle with lacking confidence when
doing any of this fitnessy stuff&#8230;</p>



<p>Here’s
the thing my gals: confidence comes from a series of repeated actions. That’s
all it really is <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f917.png" alt="🤗" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Repeated actions. </p>



<p>Think
about it: you probably lacked confidence at your first local job because at
first, everyone else knew how it all worked, where everything was, and how it
all got done, while you did not. But now? You know your job like the back of
your hand, walk around like you own the place <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, and you’re bros with
your boss</p>



<p>So,
when you’re <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4aa-1f3fc.png" alt="💪🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />goin at it<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4aa-1f3fc.png" alt="💪🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, think of that. And if you start to get
uncomfortable, and you start to get frustrated, wishing you just had the
confidence to properly get it done, remind yourself that:</p>



<p>Discomfort
is normal. </p>



<p>Discomfort
is good.</p>



<p>Discomfort
is your friend. </p>



<p>Discomfort
is opportunity for growth. </p>



<p>Because
the coolest thing is that if you keep exposing yourself to it, you will soon
overcome it. </p>



<p>Don’t
convince yourself that discomfort, or lack of confidence, is a legitimate
barrier for going for what you KNOW you want to go for. It is PART of the
process. Everyone has felt it. </p>



<p>And overcoming it, little by little, is what creates that confidence you will very soon feel. So KEEP IT UP my gal<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2764.png" alt="❤" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-1 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3532" data-permalink="/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/screen-shot-2019-02-18-at-10-37-05-2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?fit=1152%2C920&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1152,920" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2019-02-18 at 10.37.05" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?fit=300%2C240&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?fit=1024%2C818&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1152" height="920" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?fit=1024%2C818" alt="" data-id="3532" data-link="/?attachment_id=3532" class="wp-image-3532" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?w=1152&amp;ssl=1 1152w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?resize=300%2C240&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.05-1.png?resize=1024%2C818&amp;ssl=1 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1152px) 100vw, 1152px" /></figure></li></ul>



<p><strong>How do
you balance all of it with university? </strong></p>



<p>I view it as a priority! self care will always be
a priority for me; I will perform much better as a student, friend, athlete,
you name it – if I am taking care of myself. </p>



<p>I’ve written a couple posts on the workout side
of this: </p>



<p><strong>MINDSET TIPS </strong></p>



<p>I want to highlight these 3 mindset shifts that SERIOUSLY helped me because <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />mindset <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />is everything<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />!!!!</p>



<p>1.PRACTICE SELF AWARENESS</p>



<p>be
REAL with yourself and realise that, girlies, we DO have time. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/23f1.png" alt="⏱" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />how often do we
open insta/twitter/snapchat and scroll through for 15 minutes? As I write this
while chillin, it’s probably my 5th/6th of the day, and as you read this, it
may be yours as well. No need to feel guilty, because we like doing it &#8211; but
pointing it out is a perfect way to be self aware that we DO have the time.
Realise it and convince yourself of it &#8211; so that you can use it.</p>



<p>2. VIEW IT AS A PRIORITY</p>



<p>Here’s
the thing amigas, there will literally ALWAYS be coursework you can get ahead
on, lecture notes to write, socials to attend, nights out calling our names, a
shift at work to get to. And it’s honestly overwhelming that uni life is KNOWN
for that fact that no one can really tell us what to do anymore; WE have to set
our priorities. So: consider the workout JUST AS IMPORTANT as the lab report &#8211;
so that you go when you said you would, EVEN IF you didn’t get as ahead in the
assignment as you said you would. Why? Keep reading heheh (look at me buildin
up the suspense)</p>



<p>3. Realise that it will IMPROVE YOUR TIME MANAGEMENT and productivity</p>



<p>When
you schedule it in, you subconsciously motivate yourself to plan a structure
around it, and stick to that plan. AND without getting too scientific, there
are a SHIETton of studies that directly correlate exercise to boosts of
productivity; whether they’re immediate (we all know that post workout high!)
or long term (memory improvement, energy generation, stress relief OH SO MAny) </p>



<p>So
when you are struggling to fit in your workouts/cooking as a student, start
with your mindset. Convince yourself of these three things:</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> You DO have the time</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> It IS a priority</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> It WILL improve your time management, productivity, and make you a better student</p>



<p><strong>PRACTICAL TIPS </strong></p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> In short, REDUCE the amount of decision making you have to spend on aaaaany of it!! </p>



<p>1. SCHEDULE IT IN</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Whether its a class, or a gym date with a pal, or a YouTube workout. I encourage you to write<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f44f-1f3fc.png" alt="👏🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />it<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f44f-1f3fc.png" alt="👏🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />down<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f44f-1f3fc.png" alt="👏🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Gives you a sense of accountability that will help you as a student IMMenseLy trust meh (and the fact that i tried to go 4 months of my first year chemistry degree without an agenda LOL #itdidntwork #atall)</p>



<p>2. BE REALISTIC WITH YOUR SCHEDULING so that you can literally only set yourself up for success</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Is it a particularly reeeally busy week? So it looks like you can only do 2 workouts (even though your plan requires 4). That’s fine! Schedule in those 2 workouts, and do them. Think about the mental significance of this: you can be proud that you ACHIEVED the 2 workouts you scheduled in, rather than frustrated for writing off 2 that were unrealistically put in. </p>



<p>3. ALWAYS HAVE A PREPARED GYM BAG so that if it’s a workout day, all you have to do is pick it up</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> For a long while I literally used a grocery bag lol and just always had it by my door. quickly replaced the sweaty with the clean, set it back down by the door, ready for its next use. (tbh often I don’t even switch out some stuff ewies heheh but gotta save the wash monies where we can)<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f937-1f3fb-200d-2640-fe0f.png" alt="🤷🏻‍♀️" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<p>4. WORK OUT EFFICIENTLY by following a planned guide/structure so you don’t faff around</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Nothing worse than walking in and feeling like “sooo what now” or walking out and being like “what did I just do in the past hour”!!Walk in, check through each planned move, walk out feeling lit and sassy (and sweaty) af</p>



<p>5. <em>(personal preference) </em>GET IT DONE IN THE MORNING</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2b50.png" alt="⭐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> teehee. There’s just something about starting your day with a huge check to your to do list and a boost of energy. It takes getting used to FOR SURE but try it <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2764.png" alt="❤" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<p><strong>MEAL PREP TIPS</strong></p>



<p>You
save so much time and money meal prepping! Instead of spending 30 min in the kitchen
every night, lots of time queuing for/deciding on food on campus, you spend 1
hour every 3 or 4 nights making food you know you’ll like and for much cheaper.
</p>



<ul><li>Buy food on Sunday. Then meal prep on Sunday and Wednesday evening. </li><li>Make one pot (4ish portions worth) and one oven based (4ish portions worth) recipe at once – so that way in 30 min you have yourself 8 meals. </li><li>Instead of putting it in individual Tupperware (that’s 8ish tupperware…way too much) put each recipe in one huge Tupperware (so you’ll have 2 tupperware that easily stack on each other in the fridge). </li></ul>



<ul data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":1,"permalink":"https:\/\/www.subculturedmag.com\/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc\/"}' class="wp-block-gallery columns-1 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img data-attachment-id="3533" data-permalink="/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/screen-shot-2019-02-18-at-10-37-19/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?fit=1526%2C1148&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1526,1148" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2019-02-18 at 10.37.19" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?fit=300%2C226&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?fit=1024%2C770&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="1526" height="1148" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?fit=1024%2C770" alt="" data-id="3533" data-link="/?attachment_id=3533" class="wp-image-3533" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?w=1526&amp;ssl=1 1526w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?resize=300%2C226&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-2019-02-18-at-10.37.19.png?resize=1024%2C770&amp;ssl=1 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure></li></ul>



<p><strong>Do you
think this sort of lifestyle is compatible with being a student that maybe
drinks and has dominos more than they really should? </strong></p>



<p>Of course! That is the entire message of my
platform and what I stand for. I want us gals to realise and remember that
progress (of any form) comes from CONSISTENCY, not RIGIDITY. I want us to
realise that drinks out, occasional dominoes, and some late nights are all a
part of this fun stage in our life, and to stop mentally bullying ourselves
into thinking we “failed” at “being healthy” when this happens. Focus on what
you can “control” on the WHOLE, such as the self-made food you can nourish
yourself with (and save lots of money on), and the workouts you can get energy
from. The other fun bits are called LIFE. </p>



<p>As uni students there is a social
aspect so entrenched in the uni experience (drinking with friends, having food
out, late nights etc) that may make “aesthetic” results slower than if we were
at another point in our lives &#8211; I fully realise this and embrace it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I always encourage
students to shift your mentality to view consistent exercise as an investment
in your LONG term health, discipline, and happiness, rather than an immediate
way to get aesthetic results (as it’s so often marketed as). </p>



<p>When I’m lacking
motivation, I turn to my beloved science for some: SO MANY studies consistently
demonstrate how daily exercise boosts your brain capacity, helps to prevent
depression, and prevents long-term chronic diseases (Type 2 Diabetes, heart
disease, dementia etc).&nbsp;</p>



<p>So now I view every half
hour workout as this: an opportunity for major endorphin release immediately
after, an opportunity to have some daily time to focus on myself, and an
opportunity to better my long-term health.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&nbsp;&nbsp;prioritise
getting my exercise in as much as I&nbsp;&nbsp;prioritise writing up that
essay. In the long term, the mental clarity and brain boost I feel from every
workout, and the confidence in myself that I’ve developed from a consistent
exercise routine, has contributed so much to my discipline as a hard-working
student. If I can trust myself to squeeze in a 30 minute workout even when I’m
not really in the mood, I can trust myself to just write up those lecture notes
when I know I should. so STICK TO IT: the time will pass anyway, so may as well
fulfil those daily self-promises to workout that your long term self will
seriously thank and feel proud of you for.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>How did
you balance it with working full time? Do you have any top tips for staying
motivated when the 9-5 has you ready to collapse into bed the minute you’re
home?</strong></p>



<p>My biggest (and probably most annoying!) tip is
to get it done in the morning. It takes getting used to but here is a post I
wrote on it: </p>



<p>Things
I do the night before: </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I sleep in my workout outfit (it’s clean and comfy don’t you worry heh) </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I place my alarm clock (phone) across the room &#8211; classsssic trick</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I place my headphones, a water bottle, my shoes and my jacket next to it</p>



<p>So
the morning of goes something like this: </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f449-1f3fc.png" alt="👉🏼" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> The stupid flippin “diddledumdumdumdumdum…. dumdumdumdum” iPhone alarm goes off (literally singing that in my head right now)</p>



<p>And
I’m tired. I don’t want to get up. The bed is so warm. Oh so very warm. But I
literally have to get up &#8211; to turn the world’s worst tune off. </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f483-1f3fb.png" alt="💃🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> So I do. </p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4a6.png" alt="💦" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> And drink the water, it perks me up a lil</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f3a7.png" alt="🎧" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> And put on the headphones, play “Move Your Feet” by Junior Senior &#8211; that tune perks me up a lil more </p>



<p>And
I’m up: in my outfit, headphones on, water bottle in my hand and jacket/shoes
right there…lesssss just go my gals!</p>



<p><strong>For the
girls who aren’t already ‘fit and slim’ how do you cater for them in terms of
lower impact exercises, diet change etc.? </strong></p>



<p>In my fitness classes, I always encourage the
girls to do what they can while MAKING SURE to challenge themselves. All of us
know our levels, and we all know when we are challenging ourselves (even if we
don’t admit it!) </p>



<p>Learn how to build up every move: the squat, the
pushup, pull up, etc!</p>



<p>Never ever be embarrassed of your current
abilities. Everybody starts somewhere, so don’t convince yourself you’re
naturally restricted to certain abilities! </p>



<p>For diet change, I always emphasise the
importance of adding habits rather than removing very engrained ones as a form
of gradual habit formation. For example, ADD ON drinking 2L of water a day, add
on veggies to your plate, ADD ON cooking your own meals instead of buying out.
Once you see it’s pretty simple to stick to those habits, you trust yourself to
be able to remove some habits you don’t think are that great for you!</p>



<p>It is never ever
too late to start adding on exercise and self-cooking into your life, no matter
your life circumstances, current fitness level, body type, etc. Exercise and
diet change is not “one size fits all”, and every little effort counts. </p>



<p><strong>What are
your own personal goals for your growing fitness empire? What change do you
want to make? </strong></p>



<p>I would love to make a big community out of it
like Kayla Itsines has done – where I can offer a subscription service (like an
app) with workouts, meal prep ideas for one, written articles on mindset help,
and have the ability to personally meet anyone that uses it with big meetups.
I’d especially want to emphasise the “connection” and “community” factor. The thing
is; you can google workouts and recipes at any point in time anywhere, but I
want to humanise the process by appreciating their actions, easing their
frustrations, congratulating them for their efforts. </p>



<p>That’s why I like to put a lot of thought into my captions! Each post is a chance to connect with someone, and encourage them. While we are subconsciously taught to “want” to work out and eat well to I want to instil in every person that comes across my platforms and encourage them, and make them feel fully capable!</p>



<p>You can find Adriana here:</p>



<p>Instagram: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="@adrianablancfit (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.instagram.com/adrianablancfit/" target="_blank"><em>@adrianablancfit</em></a></p>



<p>YouTube: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Adriana Blanc  (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCtgOYBxEUX6fCcxsa_U3Whw" target="_blank"><em>Adriana Blanc</em></a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Holly Butteriss</strong></p>



<p><strong>In-text photos provided by Adriana Blanc</strong></p>



<p><strong>Picture research by Juliey Pham; featured image by  <br>@fezbot2000 on Unplash.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/">An Interview with Adriana Blanc</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/an-interview-with-adriana-blanc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3526</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surrey Creative: An Interview With Cordeliya Prahalathan</title>
		<link>/surrey-creative-an-interview-with-cordeliya-prahalathan/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surrey-creative-an-interview-with-cordeliya-prahalathan</link>
					<comments>/surrey-creative-an-interview-with-cordeliya-prahalathan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 20:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For music lovers, music is a reflection of feelings. I’m no different – when I’m stressed, I listen to music. When I’m sad, I listen to music. When I’m happy, I listen to music. Listening to music is what keeps people going when they feel like they can’t go on anymore. It transports you to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/surrey-creative-an-interview-with-cordeliya-prahalathan/">Surrey Creative: An Interview With Cordeliya Prahalathan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p>For music lovers, music is a reflection of feelings. I’m no
different – when I’m stressed, I listen to music. When I’m sad, I listen to
music. When I’m happy, I listen to music. Listening to music is what keeps
people going when they feel like they can’t go on anymore. It transports you to
another place, one where you don’t have the same worries and anxieties that you
thought you had five minutes ago. Music has so much power, across all
generations, all races, all genders. I love the power it has. It brings people
of all walks of life together. It only makes sense that music is a symphony of
many emotions, as it is an expression of an artist’s feelings. Once hidden
away, to be brought to life in song, just for a moment. Emotions shared evoke
emotions in others and so the butterfly effect unfolds in front of your very
eyes. Watching someone feel moved by a piece of music is something that cannot
be compared to anything else. Bringing some to tears and you can’t explain why.
This and more, is all what has inspired many to sing and express their love for
music and Cordeliya Prahalathan is no exception.<br>
<strong><br>
So, Cordeliya, why don’t you introduce yourself to SUBCULTURED?<br>
</strong>“So, I am a second year psychology student… An ordinary girl, living an
ordinary life. Music has been part of my journey from a very young age and has
got me through a lot of difficult times in my life.”</p>



<p><strong>How long have you have
singing?<br>
</strong>“I learnt Carnatic music when I was little, with the veena alongside that.
I’m at grade 8 with Carnatic, basically diploma level, and with the veena I am
at grade 7. Being able to share my passion with other people is such a blessing
– it’s super nice.”<strong><br>
<br>
What’s your favourite memory that singing has given you?<br>
</strong>“Being a shy person, performing alone is very nerve-wracking for me so my
performance last year at the University of Surrey’s iGala was a challenge. But
it was also a fear to overcome, having everyone look at me whilst I sang a
solo. On the day of the performance I was absolutely terrified, but my friends
encouraged me. As soon as I got on that stage with the spotlights on me, I was
transported to another place. That was my moment. Hearing people cheering you
on gives you the boost you need and reminds you why you love music so much. It
makes you feel alive. I realised the power of music in that moment. I was so
happy and proud that I faced my fears, because hearing the audience applaud at
the end was such an unbelievable feeling that I will remember for the rest of
my life.”<strong><br>
<br>
How do you balance your passion with student life, especially as you’re a
second year student?<br>
</strong>“Due to my studies, I had to take a break for a while because it was a bit
much at the time. But I haven’t given up on my passion, last year I saw the
opportunity to perform for the university’s Tamil society and I thought “why
not!””<strong><br>
<br>
Is this something you’d like to continue throughout your life?<br>
</strong>“I don’t think music will ever not be a part of my life. Now that I’m in
second year, my friends suggested that I should start a cover account on
Instagram to showcase my singing. Hopefully to lead on to a YouTube account
later down the line. Originally I didn’t want to because I was overthinking the
negatives, but once I realised they were stopping me from pursuing what I
actually wanted to do, I went for it. Uploading my first cover was so scary,
but the support I got was really encouraging and it really inspired me to keep
going, so I’m excited to see where it takes me!”</p>



<p><em>Interested to hear more?<br> Please follow her on Instagram at </em><strong><em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" @cordeliyamusic (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.instagram.com/cordeliyamusic/" target="_blank">@cordeliyamusic</a></em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>Text by Annabella Costantino</strong></p>



<p><strong>Picture research by Anna Irina; featured image from Pinterest.</strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/surrey-creative-an-interview-with-cordeliya-prahalathan/">Surrey Creative: An Interview With Cordeliya Prahalathan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/surrey-creative-an-interview-with-cordeliya-prahalathan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3465</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Victoria&#8217;s Secret: The Road To Extinction?</title>
		<link>/victorias-secret-the-road-to-extinction/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=victorias-secret-the-road-to-extinction</link>
					<comments>/victorias-secret-the-road-to-extinction/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 18:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Victoria’s Secret’s annual fashion show attracts billions of viewers across the globe every year. Undoubtedly, this makes the brand one of the world’s leading influencers in women’s fashion, especially lingerie. This being so, you would assume that Victoria’s Secret would be leading the way in the body diversity revolution. However, this is not the case. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/victorias-secret-the-road-to-extinction/">Victoria&#8217;s Secret: The Road To Extinction?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody"><em>Victoria’s Secret</em>’s annual fashion show attracts billions of viewers across the globe every year. Undoubtedly, this makes the brand one of the world’s leading influencers in women’s fashion, especially lingerie.</p>
<p>This being so, you would assume that <em>Victoria’s Secret </em>would be leading the way in the body diversity revolution. However, this is not the case. Despite consumers showing an increasing demand for brands to represent diversity in race, age and size across their catwalks, Victoria’s Secret models continue to represent the idealized female body, and not the real thing.</p>
<p><em>Vogue</em> Magazine’s Nicole Phelps sat down with Ed Razek and Monica Mitro, the chief architects of the <em>Victoria’s Secret </em>2018 fashion show. They discussed the brands evolution and their stance on the brands global message. The interview gave a shocking insight into the willfully blind and irresponsible attitude of two of the company’s most esteemed figures. The article covered topics such as plus-size inclusion in the industry and the backstage atmosphere at shows in relation to the #MeToo campaign. Here are some of our thoughts on the interview.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_3322" style="width: 1290px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3322" data-attachment-id="3322" data-permalink="/victorias-secret-the-road-to-extinction/img_2584/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2584.jpg?fit=1280%2C853&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1280,853" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Josh Wong Photography&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1480552574&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;Josh Wong Photography&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_2584" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2584.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2584.jpg?fit=1024%2C682&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-3322 size-full" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2584.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2584.jpg?w=1280&amp;ssl=1 1280w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2584.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2584.jpg?resize=1024%2C682&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2584.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-3322" class="wp-caption-text">via standard.co.uk</p></div></p>
<p>The article begins with an overwhelmingly negative outlook on the <em>Victoria’s Secret</em> brand, with Phelps stating <em>“as a social media–savvy generation”</em> we expect to see ourselves <em>“reflected in advertising and marketing; and, not least of all, a shift in the lingerie business itself. Maybe you’ve heard of Rihanna’s little project, </em><a href="https://www.vogue.com/article/savage-x-fenty-runway-show-rihanna"><em>Savage x Fenty</em></a><em>?”</em> This sets the tone for the rest of the article. When Rihanna launched her <em>Savage x Fenty</em> brand, she proved that any woman of any size, race and age can feel body confident in lingerie. The world watched as a truly diverse range of women walked the catwalk, reshaping the idea of what it is to ‘look good.’ However, in response to Rihanna’s show, Razek had this to say: <em>“Everybody keeps talking about Rihanna’s show. If we had done Rihanna’s show, we would be accused of pandering without question… And all of these things that they’ve </em><em>‘invented,’ we have done and continue to do.”</em> The blatant difference between the two shows being that <em>Victoria’s Secret</em> models are by no means plus size or diverse. Razek goes on to say: <strong><em>“</em></strong><em>We attempted to do a television special for plus-sizes [in 2000]. No one had any interest in it, still don’t.”</em> On the contrary, the success of Rihanna’s <em>Savage x Fenty</em> show proves that the world is interested. We’re very interested.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As the article continues, the way both Razek and Mitro masterfully skirt around issues and avoid answering questions becomes tiresome and reveals a lot about how the company view their customers (in other words, they are happy to deceive them). In response to claims that Adrianna Lima (one of <em>Victoria’s Secret’s</em> longest serving ‘angels’) does not drink fluids up to a week before the show to achieve her athletic physique, Mitro gave the following response.</p>
<p><em>“This is her 18th year. She is 37 years old. She is so driven. And talk about age diversity. There aren’t a lot of brands that continue to use models past a certain age. But she’s an athlete; she boxes. That’s her routine, so if she’s with some nutritionist who says, “Try this, try that,” we don’t know.”</em></p>
<p>This calculated response implies <em>Victoria’s Secret </em>are not understanding the bigger picture. Their show has a direct effect on how both men and women view the female body and how ‘normal’ women, who aren’t <em>VS</em> models view their own bodies. There is nothing empowering about a scantily clad, skeletally thin woman blowing kisses as she walks down a runway. Rather, that image is something ‘normal’ women will never achieve.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_3323" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3323" data-attachment-id="3323" data-permalink="/victorias-secret-the-road-to-extinction/img_2587/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2587.jpg?fit=1000%2C563&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1000,563" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="IMG_2587" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2587.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2587.jpg?fit=1000%2C563&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-3323 size-full" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2587.jpg?resize=1000%2C563" alt="" width="1000" height="563" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2587.jpg?w=1000&amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_2587.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-3323" class="wp-caption-text">© Josh Wong Photography</p></div></p>
<p>In addition, in response to <em>Victoria’s Secret</em> 2018 show, Vanessa Freidman for <em>The New York Times</em> had this to say: <em>“to think that presenting women as presents to be unwrapped does not shape social expectations is to fool yourself.”</em> Freidman suggests it is expected that this type of sexualized voyeurism is detrimental to the female image, and the orchestrators of the <em>Victoria’s secret</em> brand know it, yet they refuse to take responsibility. Instead, as Razek declares in his interview with <em>Vogue</em> <em>“</em><em>the show is a fantasy. It’s a 42-minute entertainment special. That’s what it is. It is the only one of its kind in the world.”</em> It is no wonder then, when a global brand is intent on creating a “fantasy” world for its consumers that completely unrealistic expectations of the female body are created.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Vogue’s</em> article proves to us that <em>Victoria’s Secret</em> is a brand completely out of touch with what modern consumers want. When a brand is <em>“really proud”</em> of allowing their models to <em>“wear their natural hair”</em> on the runway, it shows the extent of the modifications that <em>Victoria’s Secret</em> impose upon their own models. It is unsurprising then, given the brand’s unrealistic expectations on the female image, that <em>Victoria’s Secret</em> continue to perpetuate <em>“an idea of sexy rooted in the pinup era, when women and their bodies were defined by the eye and imagination of a male beholder” </em>but, crucially as Freidman claims <em>“that era is on its way to extinction.” </em>It would appear however, that <em>Victoria’s Secret’s</em> indifferent attitude to what their consumers want is coming at a cost. With their market share and sales figures falling over recent years, how long will their age of ignorance continue?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<p>Freidman, V (2018) <em>&#8216;Victoria’s Secret Is Trying to Change With the Times. Or Is It?&#8217;</em> The New York Times (New York Edition), 9 November. Accessed at: <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/09/fashion/victorias-secret-liberation-in-corsets-and-spike-heels.html">https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/09/fashion/victorias-secret-liberation-in-corsets-and-spike-heels.html</a></p>
<p>Phelps, N (2018) <em>‘“We’re Nobody’s Third Love, We’re Their First Love”—The Architects of the Victoria’s Secret Fashion Show Are Still Banking on Bombshells,’ </em>Vogue Magazine (Runway Edition), 8 November. Accessed at: <a href="https://www.vogue.com/article/victorias-secret-ed-razek-monica-mitro-interview">https://www.vogue.com/article/victorias-secret-ed-razek-monica-mitro-interview</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Natalie Carter</strong></p>
<p><strong>Picture research by Anna Irina, featured image from Pinterest.</strong><strong> </strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/victorias-secret-the-road-to-extinction/">Victoria&#8217;s Secret: The Road To Extinction?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/victorias-secret-the-road-to-extinction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3318</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Interview With Rebekah Roy</title>
		<link>/an-interview-rebekah-roy/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=an-interview-rebekah-roy</link>
					<comments>/an-interview-rebekah-roy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 17:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rebekah Roy has been working as a fashion stylist for over 15 years, and is one of London’s top creative consultants and stylists, working with cutting edge designers and styling for London fashion week, Rebekah is a huge inspiration to a lot of us who aspire to work in the fashion industry. &#160; Rebekah believes [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-interview-rebekah-roy/">An Interview With Rebekah Roy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">Rebekah Roy has been working as a fashion stylist for over 15 years, and is one of London’s top creative consultants and stylists, working with cutting edge designers and styling for London fashion week, Rebekah is a huge inspiration to a lot of us who aspire to work in the fashion industry.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rebekah believes in supporting fresh new talent and growing a more inclusive fashion industry and we’ve been lucky enough to have the chance to ask her a few questions about how she got to where she is today, what inspires her and what sees for the future of fashion.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="3039" data-permalink="/an-interview-rebekah-roy/27025124137_f14f0b8689_k/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/27025124137_f14f0b8689_k.jpg?fit=1365%2C2048&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1365,2048" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="27025124137_f14f0b8689_k" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/27025124137_f14f0b8689_k.jpg?fit=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/27025124137_f14f0b8689_k.jpg?fit=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3039" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/27025124137_f14f0b8689_k.jpg?resize=1200%2C1800" alt="" width="1200" height="1800" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/27025124137_f14f0b8689_k.jpg?w=1365&amp;ssl=1 1365w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/27025124137_f14f0b8689_k.jpg?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/27025124137_f14f0b8689_k.jpg?resize=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 683w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p><strong><em>Hi Rebekah! First things first, what originally sparked your interest in fashion and design, who influenced you at the early stages of your journey into fashion?</em></strong></p>
<p>I was very inspired by my mother and grandmother. I grew up watching them make all their clothes and my mother also knit all our sweaters and crochet bedspreads and tablecloths. My mum made my dresses and even crochet matching outfits for me and my panda bear. It was part necessity and a true labour of love. I loved clothes and all the things that you could say and express with them. I also understood how other people would interpret and react to what one was wearing. I loved art, painting, clothes and storytelling, styling was everything that I loved coming together under one umbrella.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong><em>And how did you end up where you are today? What challenges did you face along the way?</em></strong></p>
<p>I was always interested in fashion, but it wasn’t something that I studied at university. I did Women’s Studies in Montreal, I was interested in art and communication. Later, I did an internship at UK Vogue and that was the beginning of my career in London – from there everything was set in motion. I think the biggest challenge is that you are responsible for yourself. No one else is going to make your life happen. You need to find your team, people you like to work with, people who have a similar aesthetic but different enough that they challenge you. You have to keep working, building your portfolio and exploring new ideas. Keep testing and do lots of editorial fashion shoot</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>What’s the best advice you’ve ever received? </em></strong></p>
<p>I had a teacher who said if you’re going to make a mistake make a big one. Take risks, lose everything, get back up again and start again.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>What has been your biggest accomplishment since entering the fashion industry?</em></strong></p>
<p>I don’t know if I’ve had a ‘biggest accomplishment’… I think I’ve had a series of small successes that add up. Maybe it’s better that way and keeps me happy and motivated. I’ve had a wonderful time so far! Early on in my career I had the opportunity to do European tours with Billy Idol and I’ve worked with Kate Nash for the past seven years. I’ve give workshop, done fashion shoots and styled shows all over the world from Saudi Arabia to New York Fashion Week. Every experience counts!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>Where do you see the future of fashion going?</em></strong></p>
<p>Everyone is talking about sustainability, it’s not just a buzz word – it’s how we’re going to have a future. I styled the Consider Design Show at Graduate Fashion Week. It was the first show of its kind at the event.  This year so many of the UK’s emerging designers were focused both on design and sustainability.  It’s becoming a regular, normal part of our thinking, and we’re just at the beginning &#8211; there’s lots of changes to be made. Sustainability has to become part of our everyday life so much so that we’re not evening thinking about it and it’s just normal. In August I’m styling a vegan fashion show. Most people know what organic food is, but they don’t know what vegan fashion looks like and that’s going to change.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="3041" data-permalink="/an-interview-rebekah-roy/40994569925_20e522ac80_k/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/40994569925_20e522ac80_k.jpg?fit=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2048,1365" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="40994569925_20e522ac80_k" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/40994569925_20e522ac80_k.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/40994569925_20e522ac80_k.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3041" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/40994569925_20e522ac80_k.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/40994569925_20e522ac80_k.jpg?w=2048&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/40994569925_20e522ac80_k.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/40994569925_20e522ac80_k.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/40994569925_20e522ac80_k.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p><strong><em>What is your best advice for our readers for staying stylish on a budget?</em></strong></p>
<p>Think about why you’re buying something and buy clothes that you really love.  Clothing is an investment and that will last over time. You don’t need to buy lots of thing but you need to shop wisely. Think about the fabrics you’re buying, shop at second hand place and experiment within your wardrobe.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>Tell us, what is your favourite piece in your wardrobe? </em></strong></p>
<p>I wish I had one favourite piece but I don’t. I’ve got quite a few hats from Stephen Jones and I love them all.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>And what are you most excited to wear this summer?</em></strong></p>
<p>Colour! I’ve worn black for so many years that all of a sudden I’m tired of it and I need colour. I love everything pink and red right now.</p>
<p>I think we all need to explore colour a little bit more and summer is an easy time to do that. This season we’re seeing everything from colour blocking and bold stripes with lots of bright yellows, greens and pinks. Grandma chic is everywhere with lots of print on print. There’s so much to explore and have fun with – really it’s all about personal style.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>When you’re not styling or blogging, what can we find you doing?</em></strong></p>
<p>I like going to the cinema and exhibitions. I love walking around London playing tourist and people watch with my dog. When it’s sunny I like to be out in a park or outdoor café with the dog but I do love a Netflix binge.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>And finally, what advice do you have for any of our readers who are interested in entering the fashion industry?</em></strong></p>
<p>Do lots and lots of research and see what it is that really interests you. There are so many jobs within the fashion industry, take a short course, do an internship and learn as much as you can. And then go for it!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>To find out more about Rebekah and read her thoughts on fashion and the industry, find her here:</em></p>
<p><em><a href="https://www.rebekahroy.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.rebekahroy.co.uk/</a></em></p>
<p><em>Instagram: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/fashionstylistlondon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@fashionstylistlondon</a></em></p>
<p><em>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/styliststuff" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@styliststuff</a></em></p>
<p><em>Pinterest: <a href="https://www.pinterest.co.uk/rebekah_roy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">rebekah_roy &#8211; Rebekah Roy Fashion Creative</a></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Holly Butteriss</strong></p>
<p><strong>Photos provided by Rebekah Roy&#8217;s team.</strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Special thanks to Rebekah Roy for her participation.</strong></em></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/an-interview-rebekah-roy/">An Interview With Rebekah Roy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/an-interview-rebekah-roy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3035</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surrey Style Profile: Part 2, Flo</title>
		<link>/surrey-style-profile-part-2-flo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surrey-style-profile-part-2-flo</link>
					<comments>/surrey-style-profile-part-2-flo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 19:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2940</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Flo Wadey, who also studies English Literature also kindly agreed to give us an insight into her unique and vibrant style. Flo is from Brighton and says she takes full advantage of the wealth of different shops and styles that are there. &#160; I start by asking who her style inspirations are. She looks confident [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/surrey-style-profile-part-2-flo/">Surrey Style Profile: Part 2, Flo</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">Flo Wadey, who also studies English Literature also kindly agreed to give us an insight into her unique and vibrant style. Flo is from Brighton and says she takes full advantage of the wealth of different shops and styles that are there.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I start by asking who her style inspirations are. She looks confident as she answers “Monica, Rachel, and Phoebe in the early seasons of ‘Friends’ are style icons, more recently though, I’ve been really inspired by Jazzelle Zanaughtti!”</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em>So what is your favourite season to dress for? </em></p>
<p>“Probably autumn” she looks down briefly, “I like the versatility the weather brings as it’s not too hot and not too cold.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>What are your go to outfits for uni?</em></p>
<p>“At the moment, jeans and a jumper, usually jazzed up with some interesting accessories.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Where are your favorite places to shop?</em><br />
She takes a moment to think-</p>
<p>“Shopping in Brighton is great as there are so many independent stores. I’d say my favourites are ‘To Be Worn Again,’ ‘Beyond Retro’, and ‘Dirty Harry.’”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>What is your go to outfit on a night out?</em></p>
<p>“Usually I’ll go for a skirt, fishnets, and a long sleeve top so that I don’t freeze.” She pauses, “I tend to switch between my red denim, yellow tartan, and black corduroy skirts, and usually accessorise with my Grommet belt.”</p>
<p><em>What clothing pieces are on your wishlist?</em></p>
<p>“A pair of Buffalo sneakers and the UNIF Clarissa and Crayola sweaters.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>How would you describe your style? </em></p>
<p>“Colourful and probably way over-accessorised.” She points to the chunky belt around her hips and laughs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Do you have any favorite items in your wardrobe? </em></p>
<p>“My Fila Disruptor II shoes in black are the best purchase I have ever made. Other than that, my fuzzy multi-coloured crop-top, as well as my black denim kick flares from Urban Outfitters, are great. I also have an oversized t-shirt with Leonardo Dicaprio’s face printed really big on both the front and back – it’s so bad it’s good.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Finally, do you have a best and worst outfit you’ve ever worn?</em></p>
<p>“The worst outfit is probably what I wore to year 11 prom – a mint green, lace bodycon from Dorothy Perkins; a nude clutch; and a nude pair of pumps which I could barely walk in. It wasn’t ugly as such but it was so not a style I was comfortable in. My best outfit is probably what I wore to Brighton Pride in 2017 – a red, denim mini skirt; a sheer blue spaghetti strap top with a bralette under it; a red ‘Adidas’ track jacket; a pair of red-lensed, circular sunglasses; and a rainbow choker which I made myself. All the colours clashed brilliantly and it was super fun.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Natalie Carter</strong></p>
<p><strong>Photos provided by Flo herself.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/surrey-style-profile-part-2-flo/">Surrey Style Profile: Part 2, Flo</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/surrey-style-profile-part-2-flo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2940</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Life After Graduation: An Interview</title>
		<link>/life-after-graduation-an-interview/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=life-after-graduation-an-interview</link>
					<comments>/life-after-graduation-an-interview/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 17:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Posts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The university year is fast drawing to a close and for many final year students, this can be a daunting time. From the nerves about impending exams and coursework, to the downright fear of stepping into the world of unemployment sans student loans; graduate life can appear impossible to navigate. However, SUBCULTURED spoke to an [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/life-after-graduation-an-interview/">Life After Graduation: An Interview</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The university year is fast drawing to a close and for many final year students, this can be a daunting time. From the nerves about impending exams and coursework, to the downright fear of stepping into the world of unemployment sans student loans; graduate life can appear impossible to navigate. However, SUBCULTURED spoke to an Oxford graduate working in fashion production and casting in London having worked as the Production Director at Wonderland Magazine, Gay Times and Man About Town Magazine. We asked about her first year going it alone and how you can make it after graduation too.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Discussing her initial interest in fashion, she said </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“At the end of my first year at Oxford, I decided to apply to an editorial role at the student paper- I wanted to be the Arts Editor. They didn’t give it to me, but they offered me the fashion editor role and told me that if I did it for a term, I might have a better chance of getting the Arts Editor role the term after. I was outraged at first; I didn’t know anything about fashion and because of all of the conventional stereotypes I assumed  it was all a bit superficial. But with a bit of thought, I realised that I had actually always loved conceptual shoots in magazines like Hunger, i-D and Dazed, and that fashion and art weren’t actually worlds apart. So I started working on the shoots for the student paper and after a few weeks, realised that despite the fact that I didn’t know anything about the industry, I had a good sense of aesthetics and had a bit of a knack for art direction. Afterwards, I founded my own fashion, arts and identity politics magazine called PAN. My team and I wanted to create a magazine that really pushed for diversity and intersectionality, covering a wide range of social issues.”</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aside from the extra-curricular activities, for some graduates university may have just made them realise they don&#8217;t click with the subject they chose. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So how important are specific degree subjects for getting a job in the fashion industry? She studied History of Art, and replied </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think that the really high levels of pressure at Oxford, particularly whilst juggling a silly amount of extra-curricular projects helped me cope with the intense  pressures of being a Production Director so soon after uni. It definitely helped me hit the ground running.” </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, perhaps it’s less about your subject, and more to do with the work ethic you have?</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“History of Art as a subject is really broad and so elements of it have of course helped me since. We did a lot of reading on post-colonialism and gender and the constructs of sexuality- all things that have helped me see existing social inequality and perhaps think about how our work in fashion can help deconstruct embedded prejudices and ease existing divides. I’m not sure that History of Art specifically helped me get into fashion; it definitely came down to the extra-curricular I was involved in. I’m really glad that in my second year I realised that a degree from Oxford wouldn’t be enough to get me a job in fashion and so threw all of my energy into getting as much intern experience as possible.”</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And her best advice for students graduating this year, looking to get into the industry? </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Unlike a lot of industries, it’s a lot less common to apply to graduate schemes in fashion and it’s unlikely that you’ll get very far applying to jobs without any experience in the industry already. If you don’t know anyone in the industry who can help you get an internship then it’s definitely not the end of the world- which is contrary to what everyone told me when I first started. My advice would be to email people directly- if you can find one person’s email from the team then you basically know everyone’s email from the team, all you have to do is switch the names around. Go on Models.com and look through the names and the portfolios of the people in the industry who are achieving what you want to achieve. Then: google them, find them on LinkedIn and if that doesn’t find you their email address then use Instagram as a last resort. Pop them a short introductory message and ask for their email address and you can continue on there. Don’t be afraid to ask people for internships or work experience. Actually most of my interviews and small jobs have come through messaging on Instagram- people are a lot less likely to ignore you that way because I guess you feel more like a real person.”</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And some advice on making your social media profile a hireable one</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">: “Make sure your Instagram looks good and that you put your work on there- people look at that and they’ll have formed an opinion of you within a minute or two. It’s unlikely that you’ll get anything paid at the start, but it isn’t impossible to manage this either- despite what people say. You’d be surprised at the amount of  of successful people in the industry who didn’t have financial support from the parents and who have fought really hard for what they now have; and if it meant working 9 hours a day interning and then 5 hours in the evening behind a bar six days a week, then so be it.”</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So what about when you actually land a job in the industry</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">? “</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think that all magazines are slightly different when you intern there and interns often don’t have an entirely positive experience, though it’s by no means always  as bad as people say. You should always give a hundred and ten percent to everything because even if it seems like no one is paying attention to you, people do notice a good intern. If you do well at your job and people like you, you can get yourself a paid position pretty quickly- even as quickly as two or three months; because the industry has such a high turnover, they’re always looking for new people- you just have to prove yourself. A lot of internships are unpaid in fashion and that’s also something you should be prepared for if fashion is what you want to do. It can be difficult but I would always remind myself that it was going to pay-off in the long term.”</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to get a good job in the fashion industry, London is the best place to start interning and getting experience. We asked her how she finds living in such a notoriously expensive city, and why she thinks it’s totally worth it: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“London is such a fantastic city- you can really find the people you vibe with, explore a dozen  different nightlife scenes and every week come across a new bubble in the city that you didn’t know about. I grew up in a small village on the northern border of England and Wales, and so I think that the opportunities available to me in London still fill me with so much excitement. If you’re someone like me who is super-fast-paced, wants a wide range of life-experiences,  and to meet lots of diverse characters, perspectives and cultures, then London is a big playground. It has such a great energy.”</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Of course, living in London can be a nightmare financially. London is one of the most expensive cities in the world and what would be seen as a decent wage back up North, in London is often barely enough. I have struggled financially, like everyone else- but I think that at the end of the day, your drive and passion for what you are doing keeps you afloat. If you want to make something work, it’s going to work. If it means doing stupid hours, tutoring online, buying and selling clothes on eBay for a profit, or even taking six months out to work behind a bar and save money for rent. I’m not willing to let my lack of financial-means disrupt my career in the long run, so i’ve really gone to all extents to make it work- it’s been tough, but i’ve managed it.” </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">But</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">if financial support is an issue for you when you graduate, there’s always the possibility of finding alternative routes to your dream job too.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speaking of expensive living costs and the struggle to get where we want to be, she discussed some of the lower points in her career so far: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Fashion is not an easy industry. Nothing is going to fall into your lap- if you don’t go out of your way to email people (repeatedly), call places up, chase contacts etc. then it’ll feel like it’s an impenetrable world. But the more people you meet and the more you go out of your way to show people that you’re keen and willing to learn, the more things will work out for you. The two important things to remember  about the fashion industry are this: firstly, you’ve got to want it more than anything. Secondly, you can’t give up.”</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ultimately, what seems to ring true in everything she says is the importance of determination and doing everything you can to achieve your goals, because when it starts to pay off, it’ll be more than worth it. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Often, the highlights for me have been some of the sets that have just fallen into place effortlessly. It’s so nice when you have an entire team that vibe really well together and everyone has fun on set. It’s often reflected in the quality of the images too.”</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When asked about where she’d like her career to go from here, she said </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Funnily enough, I entered the fashion industry with the intention of moving into film as soon as I had a decent amount of production experience under my belt. Recently I decided that now is the time to transfer to the  film industry and start working as a freelance Producer. A lot of the skills I gained as Production Director at Wonderland Magazine are pretty transferable to film. The experience I gained with fashion of hammering down people’s doors to get where I want is invaluable but people are a lot more responsive in film. I guess what that shows really is that fashion is the worst industry when it comes to email replies/successful job applications and that if you don’t get a positive response straight away, it’s not at all a reflection of you. You just have to keep going!”</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And finally, our interviewee gave her 3 top tips on how to survive life after graduation, and getting into the industry you want:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are probably people who have a better CV than you and have more relevant experience. Don’t let that deter you- let it motivate you! Learn how to make yourself stand out more than them. </span></i></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Always be friendly, nice and down-to-earth with everyone you work with. People will remember you for that and it’s so important not to let a job title change the way you treat people whose position is below yours. In fashion, you can lose your position at any point, tables turn all the time. Don’t be a dick- it won’t work out for you. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Never turn down an opportunity to gain experience, no matter how small. The absolute key to success is to be an opportunist. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Words by Katt Skippon</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/life-after-graduation-an-interview/">Life After Graduation: An Interview</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/life-after-graduation-an-interview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2928</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Black Students of British Institutions</title>
		<link>/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=black-students-british-institutions-introduction</link>
					<comments>/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 19:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Art & Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo-shoots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Posts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When Yale student Akintunde Ahmad asked Vivian Dang to photograph him and his friends, he intended to showcase the bond of their community. The photos were uploaded to Twitter with the caption: ‘Introducing the # BlackMenOfYaleUniversity’ and soon became a viral sensation. The message crossed the Atlantic and struck a cord with black students in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/">Black Students of British Institutions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">When Yale student Akintunde Ahmad asked Vivian Dang to photograph him and his friends, he intended to showcase the bond of their community. The photos were uploaded to Twitter with the caption: ‘Introducing the # BlackMenOfYaleUniversity’ and soon became a viral sensation.</p>
<p>The message crossed the Atlantic and struck a cord with black students in the University of Cambridge, who posed in similar fashion to show black students in the UK that there is a place for them in Cambridge and they should fight to claim it.</p>
<p>We did not hesitate for a minute to join the ranks and examine the experience of the black community in a range of British universities. From Imperial to Queen Mary to Surrey, we invited students from diverse backgrounds to share their opinions on their university experience, dispel the stereotypes that haunt their high-ranking institutions and discuss how we can move on to ensure there are more black students in higher education, how we can defeat casual racism, what we can do for the future of black students beyond higher education and much more.</p>
<p>So meet the team and stay tuned for more in our <strong><a href="https://issuu.com/subculturedmag" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">upcoming issue</a></strong>!</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2497" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/2-18/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/2-1.jpg?fit=2584%2C3876&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2584,3876" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/2-1.jpg?fit=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/2-1.jpg?fit=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2497" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/2-1.jpg?resize=1200%2C1800" alt="" width="1200" height="1800" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/2-1.jpg?w=2584&amp;ssl=1 2584w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/2-1.jpg?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/2-1.jpg?resize=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 683w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/2-1.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2498" style="width: 2810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2498" data-attachment-id="2498" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/3-16/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/3-2.jpg?fit=2800%2C4200&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2800,4200" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/3-2.jpg?fit=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/3-2.jpg?fit=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2498" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/3-2.jpg?resize=1200%2C1800" alt="" width="1200" height="1800" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/3-2.jpg?w=2800&amp;ssl=1 2800w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/3-2.jpg?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/3-2.jpg?resize=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 683w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/3-2.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2498" class="wp-caption-text">Alexa Miyoko, Queen Mary University of London, Maths and Economics</p></div></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2499" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/4-9/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/4.jpg?fit=4068%2C2712&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="4068,2712" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="4" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/4.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/4.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2499" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/4.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/4.jpg?w=4068&amp;ssl=1 4068w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/4.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/4.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/4.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/4.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/4.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2500" style="width: 2671px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2500" data-attachment-id="2500" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/5-17/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/5.jpg?fit=2661%2C3991&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2661,3991" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="5" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/5.jpg?fit=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/5.jpg?fit=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2500" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/5.jpg?resize=1200%2C1800" alt="" width="1200" height="1800" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/5.jpg?w=2661&amp;ssl=1 2661w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/5.jpg?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/5.jpg?resize=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 683w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/5.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2500" class="wp-caption-text">Alex Mitcham, Imperial College, Mathematics</p></div></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2501" style="width: 2783px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2501" data-attachment-id="2501" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/6-7/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/6.jpg?fit=2773%2C4018&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2773,4018" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="6" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/6.jpg?fit=207%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/6.jpg?fit=707%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2501" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/6.jpg?resize=1200%2C1739" alt="" width="1200" height="1739" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/6.jpg?w=2773&amp;ssl=1 2773w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/6.jpg?resize=207%2C300&amp;ssl=1 207w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/6.jpg?resize=707%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 707w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/6.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2501" class="wp-caption-text">Hareef Asunramu, Imperial College, Medicine</p></div></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2502" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/7-8/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/7.jpg?fit=4185%2C2790&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="4185,2790" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="7" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/7.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/7.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2502" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/7.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/7.jpg?w=4185&amp;ssl=1 4185w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/7.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/7.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/7.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/7.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/7.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2503" style="width: 4160px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2503" data-attachment-id="2503" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/8-8/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/8.jpg?fit=4150%2C2767&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="4150,2767" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="8" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/8.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/8.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2503" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/8.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/8.jpg?w=4150&amp;ssl=1 4150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/8.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/8.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/8.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/8.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/8.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2503" class="wp-caption-text">Arvin Taylor, Imperial College, Biochemistry and German</p></div></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2504" style="width: 4188px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2504" data-attachment-id="2504" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/9-10/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/9.jpg?fit=4178%2C2785&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="4178,2785" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="9" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/9.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/9.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2504" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/9.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/9.jpg?w=4178&amp;ssl=1 4178w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/9.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/9.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/9.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/9.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/9.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2504" class="wp-caption-text">Nabil Toure, Imperial College, MSc Economics</p></div></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2505" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/10-5/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/10.jpg?fit=4200%2C2800&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="4200,2800" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="10" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/10.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/10.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2505" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/10.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/10.jpg?w=4200&amp;ssl=1 4200w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/10.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/10.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/10.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/10.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/10.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2506" style="width: 2711px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2506" data-attachment-id="2506" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/11-5/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/11.jpg?fit=2701%2C4052&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2701,4052" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="11" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/11.jpg?fit=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/11.jpg?fit=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2506" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/11.jpg?resize=1200%2C1800" alt="" width="1200" height="1800" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/11.jpg?w=2701&amp;ssl=1 2701w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/11.jpg?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/11.jpg?resize=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 683w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/11.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2506" class="wp-caption-text">Rhoda Manu, Queen Mary University of London, History and French</p></div></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2519" style="width: 2651px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2519" data-attachment-id="2519" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/12-3/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12-.png?fit=2641%2C3962&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2641,3962" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="12" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12-.png?fit=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12-.png?fit=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2519" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12-.png?resize=1200%2C1800" alt="" width="1200" height="1800" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12-.png?w=2641&amp;ssl=1 2641w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12-.png?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12-.png?resize=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 683w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12-.png?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2519" class="wp-caption-text">Joyce Bongardt, Business Management undergraduate, Durham University. Currently at Imperial College studying for an MSc in Strategy Marketing</p></div></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2507" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/13-2/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/13.jpg?fit=4055%2C2703&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="4055,2703" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="13" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/13.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/13.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2507" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/13.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/13.jpg?w=4055&amp;ssl=1 4055w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/13.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/13.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/13.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/13.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/13.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2512" style="width: 2652px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2512" data-attachment-id="2512" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/14-4/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/14-1.jpg?fit=2642%2C3963&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2642,3963" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="14" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/14-1.jpg?fit=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/14-1.jpg?fit=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2512" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/14-1.jpg?resize=1200%2C1800" alt="" width="1200" height="1800" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/14-1.jpg?w=2642&amp;ssl=1 2642w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/14-1.jpg?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/14-1.jpg?resize=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 683w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/14-1.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2512" class="wp-caption-text">Kate Nwokorie, University of Lancaster, Law with Politics</p></div></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2509" style="width: 2752px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2509" data-attachment-id="2509" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/15-3/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/15.jpg?fit=2742%2C4113&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2742,4113" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="15" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/15.jpg?fit=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/15.jpg?fit=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2509" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/15.jpg?resize=1200%2C1800" alt="" width="1200" height="1800" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/15.jpg?w=2742&amp;ssl=1 2742w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/15.jpg?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/15.jpg?resize=683%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 683w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/15.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><p id="caption-attachment-2509" class="wp-caption-text">Toussaint Gervais, University of Surrey, Physics and Mathematics</p></div></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2510" data-permalink="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/16-3/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/16.jpg?fit=4028%2C2686&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="4028,2686" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="16" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/16.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/16.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2510" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/16.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/16.jpg?w=4028&amp;ssl=1 4028w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/16.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/16.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/16.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/16.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/16.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Project Co-ordination: Rebecca Cofie </strong><br />
<strong>Photography: Setareh Sanjarani </strong><br />
<strong>Words: Vasiliki Papadopoulou </strong><br />
<strong>Post-production: Kendrick Foo.</strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/">Black Students of British Institutions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/black-students-british-institutions-introduction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2494</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Interview with Fashion Editor of gal-dem, Hannah Gooding</title>
		<link>/interview-fashion-editor-gal-dem-hannah-gooding/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=interview-fashion-editor-gal-dem-hannah-gooding</link>
					<comments>/interview-fashion-editor-gal-dem-hannah-gooding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 17:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hannah Gooding, fashion editor of game-changing publication gal-dem and budding garment technologist, is destined for success. She pursues her passion for fashion writing and styling as editor of the popular zine, but is making some wise choices by pursuing a career as a garment technologist, a job with a clear-cut career path that allows her [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/interview-fashion-editor-gal-dem-hannah-gooding/">An Interview with Fashion Editor of gal-dem, Hannah Gooding</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">Hannah Gooding, fashion editor of game-changing publication gal-dem and budding garment technologist, is destined for success. She pursues her passion for fashion writing and styling as editor of the popular zine, but is making some wise choices by pursuing a career as a garment technologist, a job with a clear-cut career path that allows her to make a successful living. Interestingly, her diverse ethnic background as half Chinese and half British, a bi-racial young adult, makes her a perfect contribution to the gal-dem team, as she can relate to the experiences her colleagues have encountered, but also express her creative passions as fashion editor of the publication.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2220" data-permalink="/interview-fashion-editor-gal-dem-hannah-gooding/article-thumbnail-pic-1/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/article-thumbnail-pic-1.jpg?fit=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2048,1365" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="article thumbnail &#8211; pic 1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/article-thumbnail-pic-1.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/article-thumbnail-pic-1.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2220" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/article-thumbnail-pic-1.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="article thumbnail - pic 1" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/article-thumbnail-pic-1.jpg?w=2048&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/article-thumbnail-pic-1.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/article-thumbnail-pic-1.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/article-thumbnail-pic-1.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Pictures courtesy of  <strong><a class="OWAAutoLink" href="http://www.instagram.com/hannahsangooding">@hannahsangooding</a></strong></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hannah joined the gal-dem team upon graduating university when she stumbled upon a Facebook call from editor-in-chief Olivia Little (<a href="http://www.instagram.com/livslittle">@livslittle</a>) who set up the publication whilst studying at Bristol University. She quotes; “I vaguely knew Liv from friends from home but she shared her status with me and I just messaged her with my experience, such as interning as an assistant stylist and a bunch of things I did at uni like running the photography committee. So with that experience she came back to me and said ‘Would you like to be the fashion editor?’ and that’s kind of how it began”. Since then, gal-dem has become an instant success. Described as a ‘vibrant online magazine written by women of colour for all to explore’, gal-dem highlights issues of race but also music, fashion, art from the perspective of one of the most underrepresented groups in the media &#8211; female ethnic minorities. The publication has been heavily praised, with Dazed and Confused recognising the indie magazine in the Dazed 100. She marvels on the brand’s success; “Just everyday we wake up and something amazing has happened. It’s surreal, but it’s just testament to how hard people work and how we have people that come from so many different areas that everybody has their own piece of expertise to lend. We’re not industry experts but together we’ve managed to tap into something that people obviously needed”.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2221" data-permalink="/interview-fashion-editor-gal-dem-hannah-gooding/pic-2/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-2.jpg?fit=640%2C640&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="640,640" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="pic 2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-2.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-2.jpg?fit=640%2C640&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2221" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-2.jpg?resize=640%2C640" alt="pic 2" width="640" height="640" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-2.jpg?w=640&amp;ssl=1 640w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-2.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-2.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-2.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Pictures courtesy of  <strong><a class="OWAAutoLink" href="http://www.instagram.com/hannahsangooding">@hannahsangooding</a></strong></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Although the publication is primarily run by females of African and Caribbean descent, Hannah has still been able to relate to her colleagues’ experiences due to her mixed Asian-British heritage. She explains how the term ‘women of colour’ encompasses a ‘shared experience’ amongst ethnic minorities. This ‘experience’ was made even more apparent during her time at Durham University.  “I went to a really white university, having come from a really multicultural background, London. A lot of discussions on race were overlooked, which I didn’t realise at the time, until I was coming up to graduation and got involved in gal-dem and I was like, oh, all these microaggressions that I’ve experienced are actually things that have been bothering me but I never knew how to articulate”. On discussing the question ‘Where are you from?’, Hannah explains; “They’re usually asking ‘why do you not look fully white?’ Because I think that people look at me and they don&#8217;t necessarily think I’m half Asian but they definitely know that I’m not full white. I get asked that question almost on a daily basis sometimes”.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2222" data-permalink="/interview-fashion-editor-gal-dem-hannah-gooding/pic-3/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-3.jpg?fit=640%2C640&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="640,640" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="pic 3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-3.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-3.jpg?fit=640%2C640&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2222" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-3.jpg?resize=640%2C640" alt="pic 3" width="640" height="640" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-3.jpg?w=640&amp;ssl=1 640w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-3.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-3.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-3.jpg?resize=125%2C125&amp;ssl=1 125w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Pictures courtesy of  <strong><a class="OWAAutoLink" href="http://www.instagram.com/hannahsangooding">@hannahsangooding</a></strong></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Despite her experiences with race at university, Hannah had an enriching time at Durham. Pursuing an academic degree in Philosophy was the most appropriate choice at the time as she wanted to live away from home and gain the authentic experience. However, Hannah always knew she was interested in fashion from a young age. “I’ve always wanted to work in fashion, it sounds cliché but I was that kid who used to go buy Vogue every month”. As a result, she successfully managed to squeeze her way into the industry at the tender age of 14. “I made my Mum become friends with Jimmy Choo so I could go work there because the Chinese community is really small in London. She went to a networking event for business people, met his wife there and asked ‘Can my 14 year old daughter come in for two weeks?’, and that’s really where it started”. Upon graduating university, she pursued fashion writing and styling, but quickly realised they were not sustainable in the long-term due to their freelance nature. Lost and confused, Hannah stumbled upon a careers fair and discovered the field of Garment Technology &#8211; an in-demand sector involving fabric selection and quality control, with a clear, direct career path. Realising that this particular area of fashion was also profitable, Hannah embarked on a yearlong course at the Fashion Retail Academy &#8211; a route which allowed her to gain an in-depth education in this area without needing to go back to university. However, she still continues her passions for fashion writing and styling in gal-dem. When asked if the publication could ever become her full-time job, Hannah describes how the main purpose of the publication was to inspire young women of colour and reach out to people’s experiences, not as a profit-making venture. She states, “it would be amazing to have [gal-dem] as our career but that’s not really why we’ve started it in the first place”.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="2223" data-permalink="/interview-fashion-editor-gal-dem-hannah-gooding/pic-4-credit-this-by-yvonne-gyamfi/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-4-credit-this-by-Yvonne-Gyamfi.jpg?fit=5472%2C3648&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="5472,3648" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;4&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;Yvonne Gyamfi&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 7D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1484489992&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;32&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;3200&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.0166666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="pic 4 &#8211; credit this by Yvonne Gyamfi" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-4-credit-this-by-Yvonne-Gyamfi.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-4-credit-this-by-Yvonne-Gyamfi.jpg?fit=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2223" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-4-credit-this-by-Yvonne-Gyamfi.jpg?resize=1200%2C800" alt="pic 4 - credit this by Yvonne Gyamfi" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-4-credit-this-by-Yvonne-Gyamfi.jpg?w=5472&amp;ssl=1 5472w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-4-credit-this-by-Yvonne-Gyamfi.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-4-credit-this-by-Yvonne-Gyamfi.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-4-credit-this-by-Yvonne-Gyamfi.jpg?resize=360%2C240&amp;ssl=1 360w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-4-credit-this-by-Yvonne-Gyamfi.jpg?w=2400&amp;ssl=1 2400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/pic-4-credit-this-by-Yvonne-Gyamfi.jpg?w=3600&amp;ssl=1 3600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Photo by Yvonne Gyamfi</em></p>
<div></div>
<p>Our discussion comes to a close and Hannah gives budding students tips for breaking into the fashion industry. She explains how important it is to utilise the contacts you already have. “I’ve been really lucky, I have really supportive parents who are not ashamed to ask literally anyone they know for an internship. My Dad heard that his colleague’s daughter was a stylist and asked for her email. I think it was the fact that I emailed her and sounded keen, she didn’t actually know that my Dad knew her Mum, and I got the internship anyway”. She also emphasises the importance of self-promotion, not only limited to blogging; “There’s so many ways you can do it quite easily now, just have an Instagram that reflects what you do, or even a portfolio”. And above all is patience, “something I need to play by myself as well”, Hannah describes. “I always like to know what the next step is but sometimes that’s not really possible”.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our conversation highlights that a combination of preparation meets opportunity has led to Hannah’s success so far and gal-dem has given her a great platform to continue this trajectory. We look forward to seeing what the future entails for both Hannah and gal-dem.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Text by Rebecca Cofie</strong></p>
<p><strong>Special thanks to Hannah Gooding.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><strong><a href="http://www.hannahsangooding.com/">hannahsangooding.com</a></strong></em></p>
<p><strong><em><a href="http://www.gal-dem.com/">gal-dem.com</a></em></strong></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/interview-fashion-editor-gal-dem-hannah-gooding/">An Interview with Fashion Editor of gal-dem, Hannah Gooding</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/interview-fashion-editor-gal-dem-hannah-gooding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2219</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
