<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Farewell Issue &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/the-farewell-issue/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>A fashion, culture, art and music publication, written by students about students.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 18:43:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/cropped-12773305_10206631248554054_481252708_o.jpg?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>The Farewell Issue &#8211; SUBCULTURED Magazine</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107671177</site>	<item>
		<title>SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part IV</title>
		<link>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv</link>
					<comments>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 17:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Farewell Issue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Posts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rebecca, Founder, Creative Director and our Queen The day has finally come, SUBCULTURED is coming to an end. Whether it’s a temporary hiatus or something permanent (only time will tell), I felt like it was time to move on. With everything that has happened this year, I could not foresee us trying to recruit a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part IV</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Rebecca, Founder, Creative Director and our Queen</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4354" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-1/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4354" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-1.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>The day has finally come, SUBCULTURED is coming to an end. Whether it’s a temporary hiatus or something permanent (only time will tell), I felt like it was time to move on. With everything that has happened this year, I could not foresee us trying to recruit a new team of staff amidst COVID-19, to replace those who have graduated. But it has been an incredible journey.</p>



<p>It all started in 2015 with a strong, gut feeling that wouldn’t go away, causing me to send an email to the student body about this idea that would quite frankly, change my life! Hundreds of responses to my email and subsequently calls, meetings and discussions led to our website launch and first issue in Semester 2 of 2016. Little did I know when I sent that email how much SUBCULTURED would impact my life and all those involved. It was a key factor in obtaining my placement year, the subject of university assignments, a source of like-minded people and so much more! To this day, I have still referenced it in post-grad interviews and it has been a vessel to get me where I am today. And it has done the same for many others as well. I have also learnt sooo much about entrepreneurship, work-life balance, people management, and pretty much every single creative skill going <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f602.png" alt="😂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I’m not going to lie though, there were both ups and downs (as is everything in life) to running the magazine, but it has made me who I am today and I wouldn’t change it for the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I cannot reference just one specific memory, but between the years of 2015 and 2018, where I was most involved, was a key time in the magazine, which included our website launch and party in 2016, the University of Surrey hoodies shoot (one of my favourite photo-shoots to date), doing our first print issue in 2018 and the Black Students of British Institutions feature.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to give a huge shout out to the rest of the team, as without them none of this would have been possible. Thank you to Alice, who has supported myself and the magazine from the very start, partner in crime and a true OG. Thank you to Juliey, for being the force behind our digital presence, thank you to Natalie for coordinating our lit photo-shoots, thank you to Alim for standing in as President of the society after I graduated, thank you to Roshni for shooting some sick street style, thank you to Eve for commissioning articles and putting together a lit final issue and thank you to Daisy for coordinating our last round of content. And thank you to the rest of the current team &#8211; Niki, Amy and Clarise. Some other staff that have since left the magazine but were heavily involved in the launch are Katherine, Zehra, Setareh, Dagmar and Elpida &#8211; thank you! And most of all, thank you to our readers and contributors.</p>



<p>I started off as Editor-in-Chief and Creative Director, being involved in all areas of the magazine, but more recently specialised in the Creative Direction side, leading me to work as a Graphic Designer after graduating. Much self-discovery then led me to Front-End Development within the fashion, media and lifestyle space and I will be starting a new role as a Junior Front-End Developer this month. I am so excited to move on to the next phase of my life but I will miss running this wonderful enterprise.</p>



<p><strong>To conclude, I have created and designed a brand new website for The Farewell Issue, which summarises our best content from the last few years. Check it out at: </strong><a href="http://www.farewell.subculturedmag.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">http://www.farewell.subculturedmag.com/</span></strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>



<p>Follow Rebecca: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/beccacofie/?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">@beccacofie</span></a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/rebeccacofiedesign/?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">@rebeccacofiedesign</span></a></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part IV</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4406</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part III</title>
		<link>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii</link>
					<comments>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 17:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Farewell Issue]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Alice, Managing Director and OG SUBCULTURED Member It wouldn’t be an exaggeration to say that my uni life really started when I got into SUBCULTURED. I loved doing things alongside my degree and I loved meeting like-minded people. Just knowing that there was a creative outlet for me helped me through stressful times and offered [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part III</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Alice, Managing Director and OG SUBCULTURED Member</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4359" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-9/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-9" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4359" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-9.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>It wouldn’t be an exaggeration to say that my uni life really started when I got into SUBCULTURED. I loved doing things alongside my degree and I loved meeting like-minded people. Just knowing that there was a creative outlet for me helped me through stressful times and offered me a chance to keep being creative.</p>



<p>When I got Rebecca’s email about the magazine she wanted to start and went to the first session she organised, I was amazed by the energy in the room and all the incredible people I talked to. But it wasn’t until later that I actually got to know Rebecca – it was while she was preparing to make a speech in front of a packed AGM to convince them to grant us society status. Our connection was instant. After spending a few hours with her, I was energised and ready to help with anything.</p>



<p>That was exactly what I did – and it turned out a lot of help was needed, because the task before us was overwhelming and there was no manual for all the unexpected issues that came up. Assembling the team, designing the logo and the website, commissioning content, working for our website to go live… There were so many meetings in the Surrey library with all of us involved, trying hard to work things out as we went along! So so SO many messages and calls between Rebecca and me. Eventually I became Managing Director, which meant I continued to be heavily involved with running the magazine, managing the team, supervising content, recruiting amazing new people, and making sure the projects we had planned came to fruition. I have shared many incredible moments with our talented team and our contributors and have had such an amazing relationship with Rebecca, who has been to me not only a partner in creativity, but also a friend. We have been there for each other and for the team during the ups and downs of the magazine, of university life, of life after graduation, of life during corona.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, even though the time is right for Rebecca and me to move on with our professional lives, I am going to miss the buzz of getting ready for another round of content, of setting up exciting projects. I certainly will miss the team and the creators that have supported us for these past five years. I have been lucky to be part of a truly diverse team, committed to promoting our mission; we wanted to create content that showcased the student community in all its diversity, to champion sustainability, to talk about youth culture and explore fashion through the lens of self-love. So that is one of the main things I am taking away from SUBCULTURED, which was a working environment that allowed me to thrive: I want to be surrounded by unique, different people all the time, especially at work! SUBCULTURED has set the bar high for any professional environment I find myself working in.</p>



<p>Lastly, a huge thank you to our audience and the Surrey community. I have loved being a member of it and I can only hope that we made university life for you even a bit fun – hopefully as fun as it was for us behind the scenes!</p>



<p><strong>Stay tuned for Part IV (Final Part)!</strong><em><br><strong>From SUBCULTURED Team</strong></em></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part III</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-iii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4401</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part II</title>
		<link>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii</link>
					<comments>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 17:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Farewell Issue]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Roshni, Street Style Director and Professional Fashionista Hi, I’m Roshni and I was the Street Style Director for SUBCULTURED. I joined last year, around this time. From the beginning of uni, I had a deep desire to be part of a community interested in fashion and youth culture, which is why I joined the magazine. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part II</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Roshni, Street Style Director and Professional Fashionista</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4355" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4355" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-2.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>Hi, I’m Roshni and I was the Street Style Director for SUBCULTURED. I joined last year, around this time.</p>



<p>From the beginning of uni, I had a deep desire to be part of a community interested in fashion and youth culture, which is why I joined the magazine. Prior to the pandemic, I was photographing street style around campus, jotting down outfit details and doing post-production on photos before sending them off to be published. I had a little dabble in some social media stuff as well, which I loved!</p>



<p>I was sadly not a part of the SUBCULTURED team for long and so my favourite memory sounds quite mundane I suppose. Despite my social anxiety, I loved communicating and being surrounded (whether that was physically or digitally) by a cohort of people working together for a common interest and passion. What I definitely gained out of the whole experience was being able to be part of a community that I had been seeking for so long!</p>



<p>I just graduated from Surrey and I will now be doing my MA in Strategic Fashion Marketing at London College of Fashion at UAL in October! As I am currently involved in a fashion mentoring programme, I am reading a lot of fashion books and watching a ton of fashion documentaries!</p>



<p>What we are going through is certainly unprecedented, but the youth of today are part of a revolutionary time. Lockdown became a time in which all of us were forced to confront issues of race and power. I would like to use my final words in this space to say a little something, because SUBCULTURED was created by the youth of today for the youth of today:&nbsp; we must all do the best we can to educate ourselves, to fight for a fair and just future, not just for ourselves but for all.</p>



<p>Finally, I cannot thank Rebecca enough for creating and maintaining this amazing community within UoS. SUBCULTURED gave the students of Surrey a forum in which to express their creative self. It brought a whole array of people together, allowing us to be a part of something meaningful, memorable and personal.</p>



<p><strong>Daisy, Editorial Director and Outstanding Staff Writer</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4357" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-6/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-6" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4357" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-6.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>I have only been involved with SUBCULTURED for the past year, but its value to me has been immeasurable. As a keen writer, SUBCULTURED gave me the creative outlet I had been seeking, serving as a platform for my thoughts and feelings. More importantly, it gave me a community of creatives I didn’t know I was looking for, people who worked tirelessly and selflessly to keep the magazine running despite their own individual commitments. The amazing team generously trusted me with content and editorial responsibilities which have given me insight into a world that I hope to be part of one day as a professional. SUBCULTURED is more than a magazine, it’s a passion project; it’s Rebecca’s baby and I want to personally thank her for lovingly creating it and sharing it with us. Saying goodbye to this experience is really hard, which is why I am hoping this is not goodbye forever, just for now.</p>



<p>For the time being, I will keep writing and creating, finding my way through this strange time governed by face masks and hand sanitizer. Keep safe everyone!</p>



<p><strong>Stay tuned for Part III!</strong><em><br><strong>From SUBCULTURED Team</strong></em></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii/">SUBCULTURED Editors&#8217; Letters: Part II</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-ii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4399</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SUBCULTURED Editors’ Letters: Part I</title>
		<link>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-i/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=subcultured-editors-letters-part-i</link>
					<comments>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-i/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SUBCULTURED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 17:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Farewell Issue]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Juliéy, Digital Director, Social Media Maverick, and Incredible Content Creator Hey there, I’m Juliéy, Social Media &#38; Digital Director at SUBCULTURED. I manage all digital marketing activities in the magazine, on the website and on social media. It’s been a wild ride with SUBCULTURED! I started out doing marketing for the magazine when it was [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-i/">SUBCULTURED Editors’ Letters: Part I</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="cb-itemprop" itemprop="reviewBody">
<p><strong>Juliéy, Digital Director, Social Media Maverick, and Incredible Content Creator</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4356" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-3/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4356" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-3.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>Hey there, I’m Juliéy, Social Media &amp; Digital Director at SUBCULTURED. I manage all digital marketing activities in the magazine, on the website and on social media.</p>



<p>It’s been a wild ride with SUBCULTURED! I started out doing marketing for the magazine when it was founded in Surrey 5 years ago, and just worked my way up to be a Director (sort of proud to say that Rebecca, Alice and I are the only 3 members who were there from the very beginning and are still here today).</p>



<p>One of my best memories at SUBCULTURED is definitely when we released our first print publication, ‘THE STUDENT ISSUE’. I remember vividly that moment when we were waiting in the Union House for the magazine delivery and got way too excited and screamed at the top of our lungs when the print copies finally arrived. For us, as creators, to be able to physically witness our hard work after all those months, and to see that it was so highly anticipated and that it was received so well by Surrey students was the best feeling ever.</p>



<p>I’m now working full-time as a digital marketer and have been working from home since lockdown. Lockdown was daunting at first, but I’ve really enjoyed being in my own vibe and hanging out with my housemates. I think the key to staying sane during this pandemic is to really focus on yourself, by self-pampering, eating healthy and exercising. Also stay positive- nothing can help you get through tough times more than a positive attitude. And, in case you miss us, always feel free to check us out on the SUBCULTURED website, where you can also find links to our online issues!</p>



<p>For more by Juliéy: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/julieythe1st/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">@julieythe1st</span></a> on Facebook and Instagram</p>



<p><strong>Natalie, Photography Director and Blogger Extraordinaire</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4351" data-permalink="/subcultured-mini-8/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-8" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4351" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/subcultured-mini-8.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>I joined SUBCULTURED as a Creative Assistant back in 2017 when I was in my second year of Uni. I helped plan, style and direct photoshoots, which led to me becoming Photography Director and undertaking the creative direction of photoshoots.</p>



<p>I love how our shoots brought different people together and I had so much fun meeting everyone. I also wrote some articles for the SUBCULTURED website and got to explore some really interesting topics, such as unrealistic beauty standards. It was great to have people edit my work and help me improve. SUBCULTURED was a brilliant creative outlet for myself and many others and it gave me so many skills both personally and professionally; it gave me experience of managing a team and helped me gain confidence through interacting with new people and speaking at AGMs. Ultimately,<em> </em>SUBCULTURED allowed me to feel part of something which helped me during times when I felt isolated at uni. Being part of<em> </em>SUBCULTURED was one of the highlights of being at Surrey for me, and I will cherish the memories for the rest of my life. Thank you, Rebecca, and thank you to the rest of the SUBCULTURED team.</p>



<p>For more by Natalie:&nbsp; <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.ncarterofficial.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.ncarterofficial.com/</a></span> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/nat_carts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">@nat_carts</span></a>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Eve, Former Editorial Director and Content Queen</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><img data-attachment-id="4372" data-permalink="/?attachment_id=4372" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?fit=1240%2C1649&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1240,1649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="subcultured-mini-10" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?fit=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?fit=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="226" height="300" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10-226x300.png?resize=226%2C300" alt="" class="wp-image-4372" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?resize=226%2C300&amp;ssl=1 226w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?resize=770%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 770w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?resize=1155%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1155w, https://i2.wp.com/www.subculturedmag.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/subcultured-mini-10.png?w=1240&amp;ssl=1 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>I joined SUBCULTURED in my first year, writing articles whenever I could. I loved being part of such a cool and talented team and in my final year I had the opportunity to become Editorial Director for the magazine. In this role, I had the responsibility of commissioning content and learned about maximising the magazine’s reach through tailored, relevant content. The Valentine’s Week feature and our latest issue are some of my favourite pieces. I have so much respect and love for Rebecca and Alice who have made SUBCULTURED what it is and it will be sorely missed!</p>



<p><strong>STAY TUNED FOR PART II!<br><em>From SUBCULTURED Team</em></strong></p>
</span><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/subcultured-editors-letters-part-i/">SUBCULTURED Editors’ Letters: Part I</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">SUBCULTURED Magazine</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/subcultured-editors-letters-part-i/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4382</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
